<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Roots Blog</title>
    <description>Engaging activities and voter through cutting edge digital and grassroots strategies. That deliver the hardest fought elections</description>
    <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 07:39:43 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 07:39:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tools for Social Media Tracking and Engagement (Updated)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Figuring out what is trending on Twitter can be difficult. Do you use the advance search to look for keywords? Do you look at a list of thought leader every day? Check to see what’s on your timeline?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of tools out there that can help you discover what is popular right now to help you reach out to your targeted audience. Below are three that are some of the best around&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;buzzsumohttpbuzzsumocom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://buzzsumo.com/&quot;&gt;Buzzsumo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/buzzsumo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Buzzsumo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buzzzsumo searches multiple social sites for the most popular keywords or domains and can show results by time period, from last 24 hours up to a year. The best thing about Buzzsumo is that it tracks keywords and domains across multiple social media site including Google + this will allow you to add your two cents to the conversation no matter where it is, and know which platform will perform the best for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buzzsumo tools for Twitter that lets you search for influencers with a number of filter that let you find individuals that can offer strong engagement, and have quality backlinks. Buzzsumo also lets you search twitter so you can Find people talking about your brand, your competitors and topics relevant to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;topsy-discontinued&quot;&gt;Topsy (Discontinued)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/topsy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Topsy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topsy is a social search engine that displays results similar to Google. One of the biggest advantages to Topsy is that it offers a more immediate time filter the Buzzsumo ranging from the past hour to 30 days. You can also filter by links, videos, tweets, and by relevancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest advantages of Topsy is that it goes further with Topsy Analytics. There you can look at the volume of tweets sent each day and compare them to up to 2 other keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;socialmentionhttpsocialmentioncom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://socialmention.com/&quot;&gt;Socialmention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/socialmention.png&quot; alt=&quot;Socialmention&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Socialmention unlike Buzzsumo and Topsy focuses on real-time search results this means that is doesn’t automatically sort by popularity or volume. The big advantage of Social mention is you can see the latest tweets, blog posts and other social posts about any topic you choose, from any time, or from a specific time like the past hour for the past month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the left side you can see some basic stats about your chosen keyword, such as the sentiment and reach. There is other useful information that you can use to dive deeper into what content is popular available too, like the top tweeters tweeting about your topic and the most popular related hashtags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;epictionshttpepictionscom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://epictions.com/&quot;&gt;Epictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/epictions.png&quot; alt=&quot;Epictions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epictions is a tool that focuses on influencer and hashtags on all social media Platforms, and offers many of the same content tools as Buzzsumo. One of the strongest tools Epictions offers is the ability to search for multi-channel influencers, and know what kind of content they share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest advantage of Epictions is that it focuses on hashtag and content research so you are able to figure out what kind of content is being shared in your niche and the hashtags you should use to join the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;first-posted-10-22-2015&quot;&gt;First Posted 10-22-2015&lt;/h6&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/Social-Media-Tracker/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/Social-Media-Tracker/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building a Campaign List: Digital Fundraising (1 of 3)</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital Fundraising is one of the cheapest and most effective ways to raise money for your &lt;a href=&quot;../starting-activist-group/&quot;&gt;online advocacy group&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;../Campaign-Plan&quot;&gt;political campaign&lt;/a&gt;. The main focus of Part 1 is about content that will generate email addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;basics-of-digital-fundraising&quot;&gt;Basics of Digital Fundraising&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The main tool&lt;/strong&gt; that your fundraising effort is &lt;strong&gt;email&lt;/strong&gt;. The key to getting strong results starts with building your email list. While there are both online and offline ways to build an email list for fundraising, we will be focusing on using Social Media to help build your email list for fundraising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;social-media&quot;&gt;Social Media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List Building/Lead Generating using social media is a &lt;strong&gt;very time consuming effort&lt;/strong&gt; because the core part of this is creating content that will drive traffic to your blog, while also reaching out to social media influencers. While the initial return on your time might seem minimal the main thing to remember is that &lt;strong&gt;any gains that you make will continue to advance your fundraising effort after you stop&lt;/strong&gt; your list building efforts. In contrast, once you stop a paid campaign, there are no residual gains that can be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;blog&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogs are the best way for an organization or advocacy campaign to reach your audience and find supporters online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Digital-Fundraising/graph-reason-blog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Graph of Blog increase in lead generation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;Content&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an Online Activist Group and Political and Issue Campaign there a 3 types of content that will help your effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Press Release: Should be short and act as announcements for the Organization, such as fundraising number or upcoming event. While a lot of people will copy the text into twitter it is better to link to it with a twitter card, and retweet it multiply time through the day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Technical: Are either research, or policy on your issue. While reporting on other research or policy initiatives is ok. It is better for you to do original work, which is often a key component to this type of content getting shared. You can also do How To’s to help people who want to make a difference and help out in their day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Narrative: This is a personal story that talks about the effects of not acting on your issue, and should try to create an emotional connection with an uplifting ending.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consumer psychologist Dr Brent Coker from the University of Melbourne has identified four key elements present in viral videos, and revealed four common factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Shareability’ on social media. The video content must make the sharer look good to their peers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Viewers must be able to connect to the content. Activating memories via music and nostalgia are key to getting the audience to connect to the video.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Large emotional range. Clips that quickly take the viewer from an emotional low (sadness or unfairness) to an emotional high (joy, love or justice) are more likely to go viral.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;‘Frisson’ or primitive feeling of excitement or thrill. There is often a physical response to a viral video, hairs standing on the back of the neck and goosebumps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Source &lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/news/2016-03-recipe-video-viralresearch-key-ingredients.html&quot;&gt;phys.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While telling the story about the cause you are trying to help is one of the best approaches because it can incorporate all 4 points of viral content. You can create How To’s Listicles that will help you raise brand awareness by getting shared. A listicle value focused around shareability and due to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-intersect/wp/2016/06/16/six-in-10-of-you-will-share-this-link-without-reading-it-according-to-a-new-and-depressing-study/&quot;&gt;6 in 10 people sharing links&lt;/a&gt; without reading them the most important thing that focus on is the Headline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;headline-templates&quot;&gt;20 Headline Templates&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100 Useful &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; Tips For &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; Expert &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; Tips&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;# ____&lt;/code&gt; Do’s and Don’ts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; Common &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; Mistakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where To Find &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; Like a Pro/Boss&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; Seconds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What To Do With &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;# ____&lt;/code&gt; Tips&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; VS &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; Bad &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; Habits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; Facts and Myths&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; Ways to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What Everyone Ought to Know About &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Cheat Sheet For &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Real Truth About &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top World Cheapest/Best/Worst &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How To &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; Easy Steps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; Quick &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; Tips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best performing posts include images because, visual elements are your bait and anchors for keeping supporters on your page. So incorporate as many images, videos, and other fancy visuals into your content as you can. This will help you get mass appeal and keep your audience emotionally attached to your cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Digital-Fundraising/Visual-content-important.png&quot; alt=&quot;infographic for images in content&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While creating visual content (.ie photos, infographics, and videos) can be more difficult for some, but the benefit spreads to your social media outreach, and help expand awareness for your cause and organization. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.bufferapp.com/the-power-of-twitters-new-expanded-images-and-how-to-make-the-most-of-it&quot;&gt;A study on Buffer&lt;/a&gt; found that tweets with images received 18% more clicks and tweets with images are retweeted 150% more than ones without&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Digital-Social/clicks.png&quot; alt=&quot;Increase in Click graph&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; style=&quot;min-width: 300px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Digital-Social/retweets.png&quot; alt=&quot;Increase in retweets graph&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; style=&quot;min-width: 300px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;call-to-action-cta&quot;&gt;Call-to-Action (CTA)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important part of your blog is to have multiple call-to-action (CTA). The best place to have a CTA is to have it as anchor text:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Digital-Fundraising/anchor-text-cta.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image pointing out anchor text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/blog-anchor-text-call-to-action-study#sm.00001f0sxqlq1ldaywg7jgiyor1ot&quot;&gt;Hubspot&lt;/a&gt; had found that in past they tracked, the anchor text CTA was responsible for the largest percentage, with &lt;strong&gt;between 47% and 93% of the post’s leads come from the anchor text CTA&lt;/strong&gt;. When you are writing your anchor text CTA you should use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; because &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; are used by accessibility software as navigation points. The other major point of the study was the use of ‘internal link CTA’ which are placed in the content like normal links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Digital-Fundraising/discrete-internal-link-cta-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Discrete Internal Link CTA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Digital-Fundraising/direct-internal-link-cta-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Direct Internal Link CTA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Between 83% and 93% of each post’s leads came from anchor text CTAs and internal link CTAs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;putting-it-all-together&quot;&gt;Putting it All Together&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you start building your email list and fundraising list you just need to focus on repeating your organization’s outreach and creating quality content. Things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Visual content will perform the best&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The process can be slow to start, but will pay off in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure you have high quality contents&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure you have multiple call-to-action&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;part-2-finding-influencer&quot;&gt;Part 2: Finding Influencer&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Part 2 we’ll go over how to find and reach out to influencers to help expand the reach of your content and tap into new supporters who haven’t heard of you.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/building-a-campaign-list-digital-fundraising-part-1/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/building-a-campaign-list-digital-fundraising-part-1/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Problem With Yard Signs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every cycle, you see them pop-up in neighborhoods and on mediums in the road. Yard signs are ambiguous with local campaigns, but you will find it’s hard to find a campaign consultant or a staffer who is for them. Yet every time seasoned, experienced political candidates and volunteers seem to focus on nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time that could have been spent knocking doors or making phone calls is instead spent on finding more places to put up yard signs. The money spent on them could have been used for digital ads, but is instead wasted on metal sticks and plastic signs. Campaigns have limited time and should be used to make direct and targeted voter contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my first Gubernatorial campaign, we spent more time in the first couple of weeks debating signs. This lead to use not pushing voter contact, and even after we had the sign we had the headache of trying to have them accessible to voter all across Colorado. They ended up being more of a hassle that lead us to spending money and time on something that didn’t help us win the election. In contrast, in a ballot election I worked the year earlier, we didn’t have any yard sign, and while our opposition to Amendment 66 had blanked every public space we still won with over 60% of the vote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The myth with yard signs is that supporters and political candidates who win in spite of them, think that yard signs are a measure of popularity and that people notice them. This myth perpetuates because first time candidates and their supports see the long time incumbents signs and think they need to do it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality is that those well-known incumbents would win without them, and cause a lot less work for their staff, and volunteers. The thing to remember about yard signs is that most people don’t notice them because most neighborhoods there are yard signs for business, and most people don’t notice them. While I would generally stay away from yard sign there is one case that you should consider getting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only time I have made a push for a campaign to get yard sign was in a State Senate race. The reason I made the push was because while we had a handful of volunteers after a couple of weeks they started to waste time making yard signs. This was a unique case because if we didn’t purchase signs our volunteers might have continued spending time making them rather than contacting voters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite pieces of advice came from a Local Election Judge in Texas, whose campaign I ran, and has never lost an election in spite being targeted by well funded groups. “Yard signs don’t vote people do”&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/problem-with-yard-signs/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/problem-with-yard-signs/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Tips for better User Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-for-slower-connection-speed&quot;&gt;1. Design for Slower Connection Speed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Design for slow web connections such as 3G&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: In the United States at least eighty-nine percent (89%) of users have high speed access, but currently fourty-two percent (42%) of internet usage in the USA is used on phones and tablets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/usa-internt-usage-graph.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Graph of internet Usage in USA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-not-display-unsolicited-windows-or-graphics&quot;&gt;2. Do Not Display Unsolicited Windows or Graphics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Do not have unsolicited windows or graphics ‘pop-up’ to users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: Users have commented that unsolicited windows or graphics that ‘pop up’ are annoying, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2016/08/helping-users-easily-access-content-on.html&quot;&gt;Google has started to penalize sites&lt;/a&gt; that use these ‘pop-ups’å&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;limit-homepage-length&quot;&gt;3. Limit Homepage Length&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Limit the homepage to one screenful of information, if at all possible. If you have a longer homepage keep important information above the fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: Any element on the homepage that must immediately attract the attention of users should be placed ’above the fold.’ Information that cannot be seen in the first screenful may be missed altogether—this can negatively impact the effectiveness of the Web site. If users conclude that what they see on the visible portion of the page is not of interest, they may not bother scrolling to see the rest of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some users take a long time to scroll down ’below the fold,’ indicating a reluctance to move from the first screenful to subsequent information. Older users and novices are more likely to miss information that is placed below the fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/ted-cruz-desktop-site.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ted Cruz's Desktop Website&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/ted-cruz-mobile-site.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ted Cruz's Mobile Website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;avoid-scroll-stoppers&quot;&gt;5. Avoid Scroll Stoppers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensure that the location of headings and other page elements does not create the illusion that users have reached the top or bottom of a page when they have not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;:In one study, three headings were positioned in the center of a page below a section of introductory text—the headings were located about one inch below the navigation tabs. When users scrolled up the page from the bottom and encountered these headings, they tended to stop, thinking the headings indicated the top of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, users have been found to not scroll to the true bottom of a page to find a link because they encountered a block of text in a very small font size. This small type led users to believe that they were at the true bottom of the page. Other elements that may stop users’ scrolling include horizontal lines, inappropriate placement of ’widgets,’ and cessation of background color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/example-scroll-stoppers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Examples of scroll stoppers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;set-appropriate-page-lengths&quot;&gt;6. Set Appropriate Page Lengths&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Make page-length decisions that support the primary use of the Web page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: In general, use shorter pages for homepages and navigation pages, and pages that need to be quickly browsed and/or read online. Use longer pages to (1) facilitate uninterrupted reading, especially on content pages;
(2) match the structure of a paper counterpart; (3) simplify page maintenance (fewer Web page files to maintain); and, (4) make pages more convenient to download and print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/appropriate-page-lengths.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Examples of appropriate page length&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;place-primary-navigation-menus-in-the-left-panel&quot;&gt;7. Place Primary Navigation Menus in the Left Panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Place the primary navigation menus in the left panel, and the secondary and tertiary menus together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: [One study]((http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/154193120404801309) found that navigation times were faster when the primary menu was located in the left panel. Also, navigation performance was best when the secondary and tertiary menus were placed together. Placing a navigation menu in the right panel was supported as a viable design option by both performance and preference measures. Users preferred having the primary menu in the left panel, and grouping secondary and tertiary menus together, or grouping all three menu levels together. The best performance and preference was achieved when all three menus were placed in the left panel (placing them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;eliminate-horizontal-scrolling&quot;&gt;8. Eliminate Horizontal scrolling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Use an appropriate page layout to eliminate the need for users to scroll horizontally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/webmasters/mobile-sites/mobile-seo/common-mistakes&quot;&gt;Google has stated&lt;/a&gt; that horizontal scrolling hurts mobile SEO. Also horizontal scrolling is a slow and tedious way to view an entire screen. Common page layouts including fluid and left-justified may require some users to scroll horizontally if their monitor resolution or size is smaller than that used by designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/horizontal-scrolling.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Examples of Horizontal Scrolling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-headings-in-the-appropriate-html-order&quot;&gt;9. Use Headings in the Appropriate HTML Order&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Use headings in the appropriate HTML order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: Using the appropriate HTML heading order helps users get a sense of the hierarchy of information on the page. The appropriate use of H1-H3 heading tags also allows users of assistive technologies to understand the hierarchy of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/Heading-order.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Example of proper heading order&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;avoid-misleading-cues-to-click&quot;&gt;10. Avoid Misleading Cues to Click&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensure that items that are not clickable do not have characteristics that suggest that they are clickable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: Symbols usually must be combined with at least one other cue that suggests clickability. In one study, users were observed to click on a major heading with some link characteristics, but the heading was not actually a link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, to some users bullets and arrows may suggest clickability, even when they contain no other clickability cues (underlining, blue coloration, etc.). This slows users as they debate whether the items are links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/misleading-cues-to-click.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Example of misleading cues to click&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/10-tips-for-a-better-user-experince/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/10-tips-for-a-better-user-experince/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting a Political Action Committee</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A Political Action Committee (PAC) is often the best way to make a difference in politics. In this post we will go over the key differences between the two most common PACs, and an overview of the steps you will need to take to start and terminate a Nonconnected PAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;separate-segregated-funds&quot;&gt;Separate Segregated Funds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Corporations and labor organizations can’t contribute to federal candidates. They can establish and administer a special kind of political committee: the separate segregated fund (SSF).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An SSF can raise funds to make contributions to candidates — including expenditures that are coordinated with candidates — within the applicable contribution limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who can set up an SSF?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Corporations (including those without capital stock)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Labor organizations&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Incorporated membership organizations (including trade associations)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;National banks&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Incorporated cooperatives&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sponsoring corporation or labor organization is called the SSF’s “connected organization.” The connected organization can use its own money to solicit contributions to the SSF and to pay the costs of establishing and operating the SSF, for example staff salaries and office space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSFs may solicit contributions only from a limited group of people, including the connected organization’s executive or administrative personnel, its stockholders (if the connected organization is a corporation), or its members (if the connected organization is a labor organization or a membership organization).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nonconnected-comittees&quot;&gt;Nonconnected Comittees&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to set up a Political Action Committee (PAC) — and your PAC is not a political party committee, a candidate’s authorized committee or a separate segregated fund (SSF) established by a corporation or labor organization — you can set up a “nonconnected” committee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of congress and other political leaders often establish nonconnected committees, usually called Leadership PACs. Leadership PACs usually support candidates for various federal or nonfederal offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Super PACs and Hybrid PACs are another type of nonconnected committee. These committees must register and report all of their receipts and disbursements. If you are setting up a Super PAC or a Hybrid PAC, find more information on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/ans/answers_pac.shtml#super_hybrid&quot;&gt;FEC.gov quick answers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;essentials-for-nonconnected-committees&quot;&gt;Essentials for nonconnected committees&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;registration&quot;&gt;Registration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;getting-a-tax-id-and-bank-account&quot;&gt;Getting a tax ID and bank account&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Political committees must establish a bank account. This is required for many reasons, including helping keep committee funds separate from personal funds. You’ll use this account to deposit receipts and make disbursements. The account must be at one of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;National bank&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;State bank&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;FDIC- or NCUA-insured institution&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ll list the name and address of the bank on the authorized committee’s Statement of Organization (Form 1).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Banks require you to have a taxpayer identification number to open an account. Get your “Employer Identification Number” online or by completing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/fss4.pdf?portlet=3&quot;&gt;IRS Form SS-4&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions about obtaining a taxpayer identification number, call the Internal Revenue Service, 1-800-829-3676.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;getting-a-treasurer&quot;&gt;Getting a treasurer&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Every political committee must designate a treasurer before it can accept contributions or make expenditures. Designate your treasurer on your Statement of Organization (Form 1).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Treasurers must ensure committee reports and statements are complete, accurate and timely. This is a significant responsibility— if there’s an enforcement action against a committee, the treasurer is usually named as a respondent. Treasurers can be found officially (or, in some circumstances, personally) liable for the actions they take.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Treasurer responsibilities:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Sign and file all committee reports and statements.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Deposit receipts in the committee’s designated bank within 10 days of receipt.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Authorize expenditures or appoint someone else (orally or in writing) to authorize expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Monitor contributions, ensuring they comply with legal limits and prohibitions.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Keep records of receipts and disbursements for three years from the filing date of the report to which they relate.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A candidate can choose to act as his or her own committee treasurer.
Assistant treasurer&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A committee can’t raise or spend money unless it has a treasurer. For that reason, the FEC urges every committee to designate an assistant treasurer on its Statement of Organization. If the treasurer resigns or is unavailable, the assistant treasurer can perform any of the duties listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The assistant treasurer should be aware of all filing requirements and have access to the committee’s electronic filing password, if the committee files electronically.
Changing treasurers&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Committees must report a change in treasurer within 10 days of the change. Most do this by filing an amended Statement of Organization. This amended form designates (and is signed by) the new treasurer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Treasurers can also resign by informing the FEC directly by letter or — in the case of electronic filers — by Form 99.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;registering-a-nonconnected-committee&quot;&gt;Registering a nonconnected committee&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You must register your nonconnected committee within 10 days of raising or spending more than $1,000 in contributions or expenditures during a calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Register by filing a Statement of Organization (Form 1) with the FEC. The Statement of Organization collects some basic information, including the full name of your nonconnected committee, your address and your treasurer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If the information you disclosed on your Statement of Organization ever changes, you must report that change within 10 days. Do this by filing an amended Statement of Organization. If your nonconnected committee isn’t an electronic filer, you may update your Statement of Organization by letter.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Statement of Organization is available in the following options:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://webforms.fec.gov/webforms/form1/index.htm&quot;&gt;Web form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pdf/forms/fecfrm1.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pdf/forms/fecfrm1sf.pdf&quot;&gt;Screen-fillable PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pdf/forms/fecfrm1auth.pdf&quot;&gt;Screen-fillable PDF with audio instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read Form 1 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pdf/forms/fecfrm1i.pdf&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-file&quot;&gt;How to File&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some committees are required to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/elecfil/ef_overview.shtml&quot;&gt;file electronically&lt;/a&gt;. All other committees can choose whether to file electronically or by paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/elecfil/ef_overview.shtml&quot;&gt;Electronic filing&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/elecfil/software.shtml&quot;&gt;Filing Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper Filing&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;When filing by paper, your committee can use first-class mail, hand delivery or overnight mail options.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Always retain proof of mailing and delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First-class mail or hand delivery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;If you use first-class mail or hand delivery, your reports must be received by close of business on the filing deadline. If the filing deadline falls on a weekend or federal holiday, your report must be received by the close of business on the last business day before the filing deadline.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overnight mail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“Overnight mail” means registered mail, certified mail, Priority or Priority Express mail (with delivery confirmation) or overnight delivery service (with online tracking)— if you use one of these methods, your reports must be postmarked by 11:59 p.m. Eastern Time on the filing deadline, unless the report is a pre-primary or a pre-general report.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-primary and pre-general reports&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Pre-primary and pre-general reports must be received by close of business on the filing deadline if sent by first-class mail or hand delivery. They must be postmarked by 11:59 p.m. Eastern Time three days before the filing deadline if sent by one of the “overnight mail” options.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Postal deliveries to the FEC:&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Federal Election Commission&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;999 E Street, NW&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Washington, DC 20463&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;regular-filing&quot;&gt;Regular Filing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;know-your-filing-requirements&quot;&gt;Know your filing requirements&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After registration, your nonconnected committee must file regular reports with the FEC until you request to terminate and that request is approved by the FEC.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nonconnected committee filing requirements differ in election and non-election years. Election years are even-numbered years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As you review required documents, you may notice that some forms are offered as both a web form and a PDF. With the exception of mandatory electronic filers, nonconnected committees can choose whether to file electronically or by paper.  If a committee voluntarily files electronically, it must continue to do so for the remainder of the calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;election-years&quot;&gt;Election years&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In election years, your nonconnected committee can choose to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/info/filing.shtml&quot;&gt;file either quarterly or monthly&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to switch your committee’s filing frequency, you can do this only once per calendar year, and your treasurer must notify the FEC. Send the notification along with a report filed under your current filing schedule, on paper or electronically, whichever is your regular method of filing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Independent expenditures&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In some circumstances, your nonconnected committee may need to file specific and separate reports of independent expenditures. These are called 24- and 48-Hour Reports.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about Independent Expenditure reporting follow this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pages/brochures/indexp.shtml&quot;&gt;link to the FEC.gov section&lt;/a&gt; on Coordinated Communications and Independent Expenditures&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;non-election-years&quot;&gt;Non-election years&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your nonconnected committee &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/info/filing.shtml&quot;&gt;files quarterly&lt;/a&gt; in election years, you’ll automatically switch to semi-annual reporting in non-election years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your committee &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/info/filing.shtml&quot;&gt;files monthly&lt;/a&gt; in election years, you’ll keep filing monthly in non-election years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you want to switch filing frequency from monthly to quarterly or vice versa, you can do this only once per calendar year, and your treasurer must notify the FEC. Send the notification along with a report filed under your current filing schedule, on paper or electronically, whichever is your regular method of filing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Other filing requirements may also apply if your committee is active in a special election.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;terminating-a-committee&quot;&gt;Terminating a committee&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you decide to close down your committee operations, you must file a termination report.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You can file a termination report when your committee meets all of these criteria:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;You no longer receive (or intend to receive) contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;You no longer make (or intend to make) expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use your regular campaign finance disclosure form to file the termination report (Form 3, 3X or 3P). Check the “Termination Report” box on line 4 of that form’s cover page.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For example, you can combine your termination report with an already scheduled filing by checking the “Termination Report” box on your May monthly report. However, your termination report must include the following information:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;All receipts and disbursements not previously reported. This includes your accounting of any debt retirement.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;How you will use any remaining committee funds and assets.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your committee is involved in an FEC enforcement action, audit or litigation, you cannot terminate your committee. You must file regularly until that matter is resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once the FEC notifies you that it has accepted your termination report, you can stop filing regular campaign finance disclosure reports with the FEC.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t stop filing just because you checked the “Termination Report” box on your regular campaign finance disclosure form. You must file regularly scheduled reports until the Commission notifies you in writing that it has granted your request to terminate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;troubleshooting&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;missed-deadline&quot;&gt;Missed deadline&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The FEC doesn’t have the authority to give deadline extensions. If you miss a filing deadline, you may be referred to their Administrative Fine Program. File your report as soon as you realize you’ve missed a deadline. Contact the FEC with questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;responding-to-a-request-for-additional-information-rfaihttpwwwfecgovradfederalelectioncommission-rad-respondingtorfaisshtml&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/rad/FederalElectionCommission-RAD-RespondingtoRFAIs.shtml&quot;&gt;Responding to a Request for Additional Information (RFAI)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;administrative-fine-program-httpwwwfecgovafafshtml&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/af/af.shtml&quot;&gt;Administrative Fine Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;contact-the-fechttpwwwfecgovpagescontactshtml&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pages/contact.shtml&quot;&gt;Contact the FEC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/intro-to-poltical-action-committes/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/intro-to-poltical-action-committes/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Get Involved with Your Local Political Party</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the November election long past and midterms still over 18 months away a lot of people I know have asked me how to get involved with local politics. While there are may ways to seem involved the new way in social media rarely will lead to making the kind of difference you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-to-meeting&quot;&gt;Go To Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do if you want to get involved is join a local group that is affiliated with the party. The best place to find out when they have meeting is to go to a county party site or an affiliated group site. If you do have a problem finding the event calendar or if it is blank look for an email address and ask them about getting involved. The reason why I would avoid the state party is because they are less responsive compared to the local parties and groups, and it’s often the local parties role to organize during none election years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;volunteer-at-head-quarters&quot;&gt;Volunteer at Head Quarters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your state you can volunteer at the Head Quarters. This is a great opportunity because even though you start out with stuffing envelopes and answering phones it will give you an opportunity to meet a lot of the people who make the local and state parties run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-for-a-campaign&quot;&gt;Work For A Campaign&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reach out to a campaign they are always looking for volunteers, and would be happy for you to join them. The thing to keep in mind you will be spending your first couple of weeks doing voter contact before you get to do more, but everyone has had to do this, and most people who work on campaigns still go out knock doors and make phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-others-involved&quot;&gt;Get Others Involved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have spent some time campaigning try to get others involved. Start with your friends and family, and then move on to more difficult places like online and from public club meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;start-a-state-or-local-group&quot;&gt;Start a State or Local Group&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have been involved with the local party look at start a group that will help them reach out to the community, and have it sanctioned by the state party. One thing to keep in mind is that &lt;a href=&quot;../fundraising-plan-1&quot;&gt;fundraising&lt;/a&gt; is a critical part of any group, along with volunteer mobilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;run-for-precinct-chair&quot;&gt;Run For Precinct Chair&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Precinct Chairs are the lowest level of elected official, and are elected in party primaries. Precinct Chairs have varying power depending on county and state party rules, but it is by far the best place to start if you want to be in party leadership. This is because in most counties I have worked in the Chairs are the ones who elect the local party official, and can be the ones who determine what kind of primary you have (.ie caucus, convention, or primary).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;run-for-office&quot;&gt;Run For Office&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing you can do to get involved is run for office. If you have gotten involved and are known in the local party it is relatively easy because you will have the party support to get through the primary and general election.  If you aren’t known in the local political party, you can still win with a &lt;a href=&quot;../Campaign-Plan&quot;&gt;strong campaign plan&lt;/a&gt;, and start with a smaller office. Running for Office is like baseball you have to start in the minors to be able to make it in the majors. So when you look at election to run in realizing that by starting local you will be able to win larger races in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/how-to-get-inovlved-with-local-politics/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/how-to-get-inovlved-with-local-politics/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fundraising Plan (2 of 2)</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;../fundraising-plan-1/&quot; rel=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;Fundraising Plan part 1&lt;/a&gt; we looked at how to lay the ground work for you political campaign fundraising. In part 2 we will look at the 6 components every political and advocacy fundraising plan needs to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-6-components-of-a-successful-political-fundraising-plan&quot;&gt;The 6 Components of a Successful Political Fundraising Plan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience these are the 6 thing your political and advocacy Fundraising plan should focus on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;campaign-fundraising-goal&quot;&gt;1. Campaign Fundraising Goal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have stated in part 1 your campaign fundraising goals are driven by your campaign strategy. You will need to know what it will take to win your election before you can raise enough to carry out that strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your political fundraising plan should set clearly defined overall fundraising goals that lays out how much your campaign will need to raise not just for the campaign overall, but at each major milestone - Candidate ID, Voter ID, Persuasion, and GOTV. Because each one of these steps will require some if not all new materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if your campaign is planning to print GOTV materials you have to make sure that the campaign fundraising plan has that laid out so you don’t end up underfunding a key campaign activity. Similarly, if you have stuff you will need to make sure that you have a consistent cash flow in order to make payroll. By having a clear campaign fundraising plan you will make sure that you don’t end up underfunding any campaign activity last minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assumptions&quot;&gt;2. Assumptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you will do once you lay out how much you will need is to make some assumptions when formulating the plan. Every campaign makes assumptions, list them out in your fundraising plan so everyone is on the same page. Some examples of possible assumptions include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Assuming that the campaign will receive endorsements from several trade groups or associations whose support comes with major donations&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Assuming that your candidate will be the “establishment candidate” and receive funding your political base&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Assuming that certain major fundraisers will line up to support your candidate&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;List your assumptions up front, and know that if one of the assumptions doesn’t bear out, you may need to rewrite part of the plan to map out a strategy for dealing with the new reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning DO NOT make payroll decisions on assumptions&lt;/strong&gt; this has happened to me early on in my career and it caused me to give leave a job I couldn’t get back. It’s better to be over worked then hire some you can’t keep on till the election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fundraising-infrastructure&quot;&gt;3. Fundraising Infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What infrastructure do you currently have in place for fundraising, and what infrastructure do you anticipate needing over the length of the campaign?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundraising infrastructure includes things like fundraising staff, a donor database, your fundraising, marketing materials, your &lt;a href=&quot;../website-platform/&quot;&gt;website’s fundraising capabilities&lt;/a&gt;, etc. – everything you use to fundraise. Map out what you will need in order to effectively raise money for your campaign. Be sure to include deadlines and responsibilities for implementation, as well as the cost for each item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fundraising-tactics&quot;&gt;4. Fundraising Tactics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the section where you lay out, in as much detail, all of the different ways you are going to raise money for your campaign. Each tactic should get its own subsection with action steps, deadlines and responsible persons. Common tactics include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Direct Mail
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Events&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Online Fundraising&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../fundraising-plan-1/index.html#First-Step-for-Political-Fundraising---Finance-committee&quot;&gt;Finance Committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Major Donors&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Telemarketing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;PAC Fundraising&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Personal Solicitation by the Candidate&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Affinity Groups and Fundraising Networks&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use this section to detail exactly how you will implement each of these tactics over the weeks and months of your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;donor-communications-plan-and-calendar&quot;&gt;5. Donor Communications Plan and Calendar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use this section of your political fundraising plan to create a strategy for staying in touch with your donors and prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, in order to be successful, you want your campaign donors to feel as much as possible like part of your team. That requires communicating with them on a regular basis – and not every communication should be an ask. (For political campaigns, I recommend that you send your donors at least 1-2 non-ask communications in between every ask).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great donor communication will lead to more and bigger gifts from your donors. There are lots of ways to stay in touch with your donors and prospects. They include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email and snail mail newsletters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Postcards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Telemarketing calls for low dollar donors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personal calls for mid-level and high dollar donors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non-ask events (cultivation or thank-you events)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volunteer opportunities and committees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Public relations / PR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, the easiest and most cost effective way to stay in touch with your donors on a regular basis is through e-mail newsletters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;action-step-timeline&quot;&gt;6. Action Step Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, as I mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;../fundraising-plan-1/&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;, I like to include a list of action steps in each of the sections of the plan that lists what needs to be done by which deadline in order for the plan to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your campaign action steps and fundraising milestones should be listed in chronological order. This will allow for anyone who reads it to get a good picture of where your campaign is at, where your campaign should, and what has to be done in both the short term and long term. Many campaigns I worked on have used weekly timelines for their fundraising staff meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, your fundraising plan is a living document and will change with the campaign, but it is important to write down your plan so you have a clear way to know if you are staying on the right path or need to reexamine your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/fundraising-plan-2/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/fundraising-plan-2/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fundraising Plan (1 of 2)</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this series, we will walk through how to write a successful fundraising plan for your next campaign. In Part 1, we’ll take a look at why you need a plan, where you start with fundraising, and cover the two most important parts. In &lt;a href=&quot;../fundraising-plan-2&quot; rel=&quot;next&quot;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; we will be going through the 6 components that are needed for a strong and achievable fundraising plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-your-campaign-needs-a-fundraising-plan&quot;&gt;Why Your Campaign Needs a Fundraising Plan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fundraising plan is vital to success of any modern campaign, even the most local, but too often candidates assume once they get their campaign off the ground the money will start rolling, and take care of itself. They could not be farther from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campaigns run on money and even in the best Public Financing system you will need to get contributions to fund the campaign’s activities, this is by far the hardest part of any campaign. A successful fundraising effort will require the campaign in general, and the candidate in particular to spend quality time planning and execution a fundraising plan. &lt;strong&gt;The Candidate should spend a minimum 50% of their time fundraising&lt;/strong&gt; no matter level you’re running for - local, state, or federal - from my fundraising experience will be the deciding factor because if you don’t have the funds you can’t run a competitive campaign. That is why I always suggest &lt;strong&gt;writing out your fundraising plan before you launch your campaign&lt;/strong&gt;, and remember that your plan is a living document and can change during the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-comes-first---fundraising-plan-or-campaign-strategy&quot;&gt;What Comes First - Fundraising Plan or Campaign Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While having a well developed fundraising plan is a key to a successful campaign I often am asked by candidates and campaign managers what comes first the campaign strategy or the fundraising plan. Another way of putting it is does a campaign figure out how much it can raise them build a plan around it, or do they figure a &lt;a href=&quot;../Campaign-Plan/&quot;&gt;winning campaign strategy&lt;/a&gt; and then figure out how to fund it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience it is the latter, &lt;strong&gt;your campaign should figure out what it will take to win&lt;/strong&gt; because if you need to raise $500,000 to win and you aren’t able to create a reasonable fundraising plan to match then I would suggest sitting out this cycle or looking at a different race. Also in past races I have been involved with large donors like to know how their money will be spent, and a campaign strategy is the only way to show that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-step-for-political-fundraising---finance-committee&quot;&gt;First Step for Political Fundraising - Finance committee&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name “Finance Committee” can be deceiving because the committee isn’t really responsible for executing the fundraising. That task is for the candidate, campaign manager, campaign staff, and in larger races Finance Director. The role of the Finance Committee is to provide contacts who can be solicited for donations, and provides a starting point for the campaign’s political fundraising network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key elements that each member of the Finance Committee are that they have a wide range of contacts they can solicit to support the candidate, which should go without saying the members should be some of your strongest supporters, and have already donated to the campaign. To keep the members accountable you should get commitments or pledges about how much they will raise. The committee can be cured from a large spectrum of people from local businessmen, professionals, socialites, and political contact among other. &lt;strong&gt;The only requirement is that they have supported the candidate financially and have a gold Rolodex with multiple people who can also donate&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;political-fundraising-network&quot;&gt;Political Fundraising Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to fundraising local candidates are unlikely to national money and PAC contributions, and for the handful of candidate that do they are few and far between. For a candidate to then be successful the candidate, staff, and finance committee must be ruthless when it comes to using their contacts. This means when the campaign goes through their contacts they have to be will go beyond close friends and family and reach out to everyone in their social circles from school alumni to PTA and acquaintances from church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your list the candidate has to make the call. This is because every donor like personal contact, which means that the candidate will get more “Yes” then a campaign staffer. That being said spouses and family members are a close second because &lt;strong&gt;the key is using personal contact to make “potential contributors” into “regular contributors”&lt;/strong&gt;, and the best way is to make them feel like they have access and a connection to the candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-keys-to-a-successful-political-fundraising-plan&quot;&gt;The keys to a Successful Political Fundraising Plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two most important things that political campaigns fail to put into their fundraising plans are &lt;strong&gt;deadlines and responsibilities&lt;/strong&gt;. Every fundraising plan needs to have a list of deadlines for the event followed by action that need to be taken on certain days, which then are assigned a person who will be responsible for carrying out the action so the political campaign can meet its deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example you might create a schedule that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Campaign Kick Off Fundraising Event - 7/2&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Form host committee - 5/15 - John&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Secure venue - 5/20 - Jane&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Send out invitations - 6/1 - John&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make follow up calls - 6/10 - Jane, John and Committee&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Finalize event details - 6/20 - Jane&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Final follow-up calls - 6/28 - Jane and John&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that you can fill in staffing areas with campaign staff or volunteers the key is to &lt;strong&gt;make sure that you have a concrete action plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will guide the person or persons that are in charge of the task.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/fundraising-plan-1/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/fundraising-plan-1/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
