<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Roots</title>
    <description>Engaging activistes and voter through cutting endge digitial and grassroots stratiegies. That deliver the hard fought elections</description>
    <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://digitalroots.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 06:19:58 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 06:19:58 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Writing your Campaign Plan and Determining the Strategy</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-the-campaign-plan&quot;&gt;WRITING THE CAMPAIGN PLAN&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most difficult challenges for first time campaign manager was writing the campaign plan and trying to envision the big picture for what has to happen in a campaign. A campaign plan is critical because it helps you to formulate a strategy, decide where you will need, key people, create a timeline and, perhaps, most importantly, create a budget so you don’t spend your money too soon. One other benefit is that you are more likely to gain a contribution from a large giver if you sit down with them and give them a campaign plan that is well thought out. As an underdog, my campaign plan helped me raise about $6,000 from large givers and political action committees by showing them that I was a legitimate candidate.
One thing -that may help you in creating a campaign plan is to look at it as a series of questions. To help toward this end, I have written some questions and comments on the following pages. Even if you have already written a campaign plan, read through the questions and see if you are adequately prepared to tackle your upcoming campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;district-background&quot;&gt;DISTRICT BACKGROUND&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the voter registration numbers for your district?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How many Democrats, Republicans and independents vote in a Presidential election?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is the past voting history of your district?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t be able to get a voting history for legislative races very accurately since redistricting most probably means that your current district probably was part of two or more previous districts. However, you should know how high profile races (Presidential, U.S. Senator, Governor) and low profile races (State Treasurer, State Auditor) have done in your district&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the age demographics in your district?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing how many people are registered to vote in certain age categories will help you a great deal with strategy and issues. How many registered voters are 18-24 (environment, tuition), 25-44 (education, family issues, crime, tax increases) 45-55 (Property taxes. College tuition, retirement issues, welfare abuse), 60 + (Property taxes, property taxes property taxes and traditional values).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the social demographics of the respective precincts in your district?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should try and classify each precinct as a certain type of person. This can be a difficult thing to do with some precincts’, but is relatively easy with most. This, too, is very important for issue and strategy development. Think among some of these categories: rural/agricultural (property taxes, farm Issues), blue collar/working families (crime, property taxes, welfare abuse, little more pro-life, job creation), country club/business (income taxes, property taxes, economic development, little more pro-choice, education) middle class/ young families (education, crime, some environment and taxes), small town (health of small towns and its institutions, education, school consolidation)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opponent-background&quot;&gt;OPPONENT BACKGROUND&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is the background of your opponent (education, jobs, place of birth, places lived) ?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If incumbent, what are the committees served on?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If incumbent, what are the key votes cast?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The local group, how do they feel about the votes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the stands of your opponent on key issues?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is different than key votes since we don’t have clear votes on most of the key issues&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If incumbent, how high is the absentee rate for voting?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If incumbent, do they have a home in the District, or a home outside of it?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-background&quot;&gt;YOUR BACKGROUND&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are your political and personal strengths in light of the district and the upcoming election race?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a very good idea to list these and to know them so you can emphasize them throughout your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are your political and personal weaknesses in light of the district and the upcoming election race?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is sometimes an uncomfortable thing to do, but it is important to be honest with yourself and your close advisors. I guarantee that people will probably find out your weakness anyway from your opponent. If you deal with it early, you can prepare for any attacks, or if necessary, cast a favorable light on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is your background (include political campaigns, education, jobs, awards won, other recognition, memberships, etc)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;name-identification&quot;&gt;NAME IDENTIFICATION&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is your plan to raise name identification?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What mediums will you use to establish your name identification?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some mediums may be social media, paid digital, billboards, newspaper ads, radio ads, literature, etc*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;earned-media&quot;&gt;EARNED MEDIA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### (PRESS RELEASES, ETC.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the addresses, phone numbers, email and news contacts at your local newspaper, radio stations and television stations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What will you use each social media platform for&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How is a proper press release written?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The state party should be able to send you information on how to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the deadlines for your newspapers radio stations and television stations?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When is a press release adequate and when is a press conference necessary?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doorknocking&quot;&gt;DOORKNOCKING&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many households are there in your district?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I generally figure this by taking the number of registered voters (15,000) and
multiply it by .67 to get the number of actual doors that will have to be knocked to hit the home of each registered voter. Example: 15,000 x .67 = 10,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many doors can you knock in an hour?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This varies widely. Depending on what yon say to people, whether you survey them, etc. will impact how many doors you can hit in an hour. In addition, the time of day also has a major impact because if people aren’t hone, you can hit a great many more homes. This isn’t necessarily effective, but it will increase the number of homes you hit. You can generally figure around 15 to 25 homes per hour. If you hit less than 15, then you may be spending too much time with each household, if you are hitting more than 30 or 40, then you may not be knocking when enough people are home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How many hours a week can you realistically spend knocking on doors?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How many weeks is it going to take to knock on all the doors in your district?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure this by dividing the number of households in your district by the product of the number of doors knocked in an hour multiplied by the number of hours you can knock in a week. Example: 10,000 households divided by (20 homes/hr. x 12 hrs/week) - 42 weeks to knock every registered household in the district. Now, if you don’t have 42 weeks, then you will have to increase the number of homes per hour, the number of hours per week or both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are you going to do with each household that you knock so that they will remember you after you leave?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doorknocking is the most important aspect of campaigning, but it helps most if they remember what your name is after you’ve left. Frequently people don’t. Literature is fine to leave at each household, but it is generally thrown away within 24 hours of your visit. One very effective way to extend your name identification is to follow up your visit with a email/postcard thanking them for the visit. This requires keeping close track of the names you actually visit and constantly updating your voter walking list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you intend to use a registered voter-walking list -and-knock on only those homes with registered voters or forego a list and hit every home registering those people who are not currently registered?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the voter answers the door, do you plan to simply give your literature with a quick spiel about yourself or your issues, or do you plan to administer a survey when they answer the door?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What order are you going to door knock your district?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you should doorknock your precincts in a systematic, planned way meant to maximize voter impact. These decisions should be made through the use of voter information that can be provided to you. by the State Party or you can simply rank your precincts yourself through a prioritization system. If you would like to see the system that I used, please feel free to call me or write me. Generally, I believe that you should knock your most important precincts between September 15th and October 31st.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;important-dates&quot;&gt;IMPORTANT DATES&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you need to petition on. When are petitions available to get signatures for your candidacy?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When are signature petitions due for your candidacy?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When do you need to file a formation of candidacy form with the Campaign finance disclosure commission?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When are the primary and general elections?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When can yard signs go up for the primary and general?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When do yard signs have to be down after the primary and general?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When is your precinct caucus, county convention, district convention and the Republican State convention?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When are the parades and fairs in or near your district?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;campaign-organization&quot;&gt;CAMPAIGN ORGANIZATION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you plan to recruit volunteers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying starting an Internship program at your local college and high school, and try to reach out to both political an civil group to speak at a meeting
2.	What areas of the campaign do you need specific volunteers to fill?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should consider having people help with these positions: overall coordinator or manager, fundraising, Get-out-The-Vote, events coordinator, yard signs, mailing coordinator, absentee ballot coordinator, media (press release, conference) coordinator, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What type of people do you need at the top of your campaign as chairs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should try to find people who appeal to different constituencies, in my campaign, I have a leader from the only small town in the district, a leading ag person and a well respected elected official known county wide. For my fundraising chairs, I have the best known doctor in -the county and a leading lawyer who represents any big business clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will you have one person organize each precinct?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;campaign-budget&quot;&gt;CAMPAIGN BUDGET&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a budget that used all basic elements of a campaign&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description– Number        Cost:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct Mail Campaign- 6  $44,100&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campaign Palm Cards- 30,000  $3,200&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4x8 &amp;amp; 4x4 Signs-     100  $2,360&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T-Posts————-      300  $1,300&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yard Signs———-      600  $1,800&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campaign Banner—–     1  $100&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOTV Robocalls——     N/A  $2,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phone Banking——-    N/A  $500&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook Ads——–        $2,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital Ads (Google, etc.)      $2,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Website————        $150&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MailChimp———-        $300&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event Expenses—–       $3,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campaign Manager—       $14,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canvassing Software-       $5,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dues/Sponsorships -      $2,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOTAL&lt;/strong&gt; :         &lt;strong&gt;$83,810&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-out-the-vote-program-gotv&quot;&gt;GET OUT THE VOTE PROGRAM (GOTV)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who do intend to turn out on election day to vote for  you.?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my opinion that too many legislative campaigns turn out voters that are already intending to vote.  Let me explain.  We know that certain voters vote in every election.  Come rain or shine, they never miss.  So why   use your phone bank or postcard to remind these people to vote?  Clearly, these regular voters need a contact before the election explaining why they should support you and not a GOTV contact.  Take this for what it’s worth, but I would only concentrate on turning out those Republican voters, or identified supporters among independents, that have a history of missing elections. The State of Iowa keeps records of who votes in what elections so it is easy to determine which voters are regular voters and which need a little reminder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What methods do you intend to use to turnout your target groups?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider using a first-class postcard, mailed on Saturday so that it arrives Monday. Also see that you have turnout phoning organized for Monday night before the election and that the local party has phone banks for election day. Another idea that we have used in Galveston is to rise early on election day and place a large “VOTE TODAY” sign on every 4x4 yard sign before people leave for work. Other mediums such as digital, radio, newspaper or T.V. work fine for part of your GOTV program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technology&quot;&gt;TECHNOLOGY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You will need to set up a Website and will have to deiced between a static or CMS&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you intent to use excel or a more advance system, and is the system going to be all in one or pieced together.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are working with less then 75,000-voter universe you can get away with using excel and programs like MailChimp. If you are trying to manage a bigger universe then you will need a more advance system like i360, rVote, and NationBuilder. While they all do similar things i360 and rVote are more targeted to just doing canvassing and voter modeling because it doesn’t have any digital tools, while Nationbuilder is more about managing a digital presence, due to being able to host a website and digital media tools, and can be expanded to do canvassing but no modeling. I prefer to use one that can do more voter out-reach and modeling because of the ease of finding consultants to do a better job at the other tasks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;media-mix&quot;&gt;MEDIA MIX&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Should you spend your money on digital, radio, T.V., direct mail, door-to-door, newspaper ads, etc.?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that candidates should use a mix of audio and visual mediums to establish name identification and to penetrate with a message. This is because some people have better memory recall from audio than visual and vice-versa. Visual would include: digital, direct mail, literature, newspaper ads, yard signs, billboards and television. Audio would include radio, television, speeches, phone banking and door-to-door.
I personally believe (and this view isn’t shared by everyone) that too many Legislative candidates concentrate on visual education and ignore audio education. Behavioral learning abilities dictate that they both be used if you actually want to penetrate to the voter.
The combination that you use depends on the mediums in your district, while digital will work in both rural and urban districts. Radio, newspaper and direct mail will probably be the best choices in a rural district. In an urban district cable television, local television news commercials, and local newspapers can also be added to the list to be bought for radio or television to penetrate,.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When will you run your ads, mail your literature and start you digital ad buys?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly you will want to be out with your name on yard signs and parades, etc., as early and as often as you can, however, when should you spend your money on paid mediums? Well consider some polling research?  Non party line voters can’t begin making up their minds who they are going to vote for until about ten to fourteen days out from the election. Breaking this out in age groups, many senior citizens make their mind up seven to ten days out while 18-24 year olds decide the day before the election or at the polls. All other are somewhere in between.
Therefore, if you are mailing your “lower the property tax” message to seniors, start about two weeks out, while you may want to save your pro-environment mailings to 18-24 year olds until three to five days out.
No matter what else, you will want to spend the great preponderance of your money when people are making up their minds, and that is close to the election. Think of it as holding your fire until you see the whites of their eyes. If you fire too early you’re wasting your ammunition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you, intend to design your media and your literature?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This takes a special talent to create great literature, or commercials, but let me make a couple of suggestions that might help you. First, collect examples from other successful candidates and try to emulate those.  Second, Don’t overburden your reader with too much information in literature or commercials.  Keep it simple and repeat your main point over and over.  Third, make sure you have your name in the literature or commercial repeatedly.  Fourth, use visuals and pictures liberally.  Fifth, don’t be afraid to be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you plan to target your message through your media?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that it requires six contacts with a voter to penetrate with a message. That’s why you hear the suggestion to use three or four issues and keep pounding away at them. With that in mind, there are some very easy ways to target your voter with your message. Using voter information from state voter registration files, you can target in three ways: party, precinct, age.  Clearly, you can tell a lot by whether a person is a Republican, Democrat or Independent.  I also know that the people in rural precincts are concerned about different things than those in my blue collar precincts. Other targeting information that night be helpful is demographic information available from radio stations about their target markets. The same information is available with television.
Example: What if I wanted to target a message to Republicans, in precinct DV12 over the age of 60 with a message about property taxes. Well, I would do three things. First I would pull the names off of my computer of everybody in my district that fits those three criteria. I would use this list for a mailing to these people. Second, I would buy time on the local radio station whose demographics most target that group of people.  Finally, I might put an ad on the digital (cost at most $5 CPM) that best targets this group like CNN or the financial news station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In writing your campaign plan, your strategy will depend heavily on the type of race you have If you are the only Republican in a heavily Republican open district, then your race is going to be significantly different than most challengers. Please keep in mind that 95% of incumbents get re-elected. Therefore, if you are a challenger that intends to be a part of the 5%, you must 1) be aggressive, 2) door knock every door (at least once), 3) start early, 4) raise a lot of money, 5) use “voting” issues to take voters away from your opponent, and 6) take some risks. Too many challengers are afraid to take risks. Challengers are frequently so afraid of offending anyone that they run bland campaigns that don’t make a case for kicking the incumbent out of office.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/Campaign-Plan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/Campaign-Plan/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Recruit a Grassroots Army</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Democrats routinely field more effective volunteer armies than Republicans, largely due to the help of their allies in organized labor. But Democrats have also had more success building grassroots organizations because they’re often better at communicating with and organizing their base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in the 2010 midterms, when GOP voter enthusiasm was supposed to have been at a 15-year high, campaign staffers across the country were at a loss as to how to get enough unpaid boots on the ground. As the 2016 cycle ramps up, down-ballot candidates—particularly in the early states—face the added challenge of competing for volunteers with over a half a dozen presidential campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some campaign managers may simply throw up their hands and hire paid workers rather than recruit volunteers. But don’t put out the call for resumes before spending some real time trying to build a homegrown volunteer effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my observation, volunteers tend to fall into five distinct categories, which I’ve developed into five “clinical case studies.” Using these in your recruiting process should help identify the right volunteers for your campaign and help you manage and retain them once they’re on board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-loyal-foot-soldier&quot;&gt;1 The loyal foot soldier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diagnosis: The foot soldier is the Republican version of the Democratic union faithful. These are the tried-and-true volunteers that turn out every election cycle. Their stomping grounds are county GOP meetings, civic organizations (think Rotary, Kiwanis), VFW halls and trade associations. Common varieties include middle-aged local businessmen, grannies who could stuff envelopes with their eyes closed and wiry old veterans with their phone-dialing fingers at the ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits: Good foot soldiers are worth their weight in gold. They’ve been there, done this, so they understand what volunteer duties consist of and won’t get bored or require constant attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risks: They’ve seen campaigns, and campaign hacks, come and go, and are usually not shy about expressing their opinion of your operation. To retain these volunteers, it’s important to present a competent and professional front. Also, as they trend older, they occasionally resist new technology, so they may need some coaxing to get comfortable with innovations like VoIP phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prescription: Cherish your foot soldiers. Let them do their preferred task, and rest in the knowledge that they will do it well. Use them to train other volunteers in their age range, and reward them with campaign merchandise, they probably collect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-groupie&quot;&gt;2 The groupie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diagnosis: These volunteers are all about your candidate. They either have some personal connection to him or her or, on a larger race, they might just be a big fan. The thrill of being around the candidate, and the idea that they are making a difference for him or her, is the driving force behind their involvement in the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits: Groupies will literally walk over hot coals for your candidate. You can’t instill that kind of devotion in anyone else, paid or volunteer. As long as these volunteers believe that what they are doing is the best way they can help the candidate, they will do just about anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risks: Because they are so invested in the candidate, often on a personal level, groupies tend to rank relatively high on the high maintenance scale. They can also be fiercely critical if they feel that the campaign is putting their candidate at risk, such as by releasing a negative TV advertisement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prescription: You know what they want, so give it to them. These are the ideal volunteers for visibility and crowd building at events, walking in parades and handing out literature at fairs. The caveat here is that these volunteers need to be well trained, or well supervised, so they understand what they are there to do and don’t spend the entire event trying to chat up the candidate. Still, once the event is over, make sure they get rewarded with a personal thank you, and get a photo-op sometime along the campaign trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-architect-in-his-own-mind&quot;&gt;3 The architect (in his own mind)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diagnosis: This Karl Rove wannabe is the consummate political junkie that desperately wants to be on the staff. He’s typically convinced himself that if he were in charge, the campaign would be on a straight path to victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits: There aren’t many. They probably know all the insider terminology, and will employ industry terms like “micro targeting” unnecessarily in conversation. If they are local, they may have a body of knowledge on past races and major players that could be useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risks: Architects view themselves as strategists, not grunt workers, so they are generally long on advice and short on actual help. Because they put themselves before the campaign, it is difficult to get them to be team players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prescription: Pair them up with a tolerant fellow volunteer and a GPS device and let them drive and pontificate while their partner knocks on doors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-eager-beaver&quot;&gt;4 The eager beaver&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diagnosis: The eager beaver is the loyal foot soldier without the experience. Generally high school or college kids, these volunteers are enthusiastic and all about helping the cause in any way they can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits: Eager beavers are energetic, personable and open to instruction. They will likely be thrilled just to be a part of the campaign and are willing to do anything asked of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risks: With all teenagers, the tendency to be flaky goes with the territory. As a result, they will occasionally no-show when club meetings, sports practice and trouble borrowing the car get in the way. Eager beavers tend to glamorize the staff, so they can be pesky. But at the end of day it’s worth spending five minutes of your time chatting them up if it results in 500 phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prescription: Although they require a bit more time and effort on your part, these volunteers will be among your best. Try to recruit them early by staking out local college campuses or posting on social networking sites, and then get them to recruit their friends. Eager beavers tend to be friendly and outgoing, so they’re great for direct voter contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-resume-builder&quot;&gt;5 The resume builder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diagnosis: The resume builder is often similar in age and outward appearance to the eager beaver, but is involved with the campaign for an entirely different reason. He or she is in it primarily to pad their resume. Generally college kids or recent graduates, resume builders are typically competent and tend to be comparatively reliable since they are looking to get a recommendation for their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits: The resume builders are easy to understand, because their motivation is clear. Agree with it or not, you know what they’re in it for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risks: Resume builders’ self-interested approach will be off-putting to true-believer types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prescription: Make it clear what’s in it for them, and they will do what you need done. Resume builders are all about the bottom line. If they seem dissatisfied with the work they’re doing, offer them a title promotion to sweeten the deal. They will generally clean toilets as long as they get to put deputy something-or-other on their resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each volunteer is obviously a unique individual, but many of them can be categorized. The sooner you figure out what they’re looking to get out of the experience, the easier it will be to develop the tools to get what you need out of them. After all, if your campaign can’t motivate people who are already supporters, how can you expect to influence voters?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/recruit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/recruit/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Secrets of Political Domain Names</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;More and more candidates are registering domain names for their campaigns and &lt;a href=&quot;http://grassrootsblog.org/basic_website&quot;&gt;web sites&lt;/a&gt;. Even more, cybersquatters are doing the same for “up and coming” political stars so they can resell it back to the candidate when they seek higher office. Reserving a domain name for the World Wide Web should be a simple issue and if you follow these rules, it will be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t Wait to Reserve Your Domain Name!
Even if you’re not ready to build a web site yet or establish your presence on the Web, go ahead and reserve your domain name. It’s inexpensive and it could save you money later. Reserving a domain name will typically cost around $70, but some companies will charge as little as $60 and others will charge as much as $100. It can be worth it to pay a little more if some consulting comes with it. But if you know what you want, you should be able to get it for $70. Keep in mind that you are only purchasing a two-year license for the name, but you have the right to renew it after that period should you choose. Most Internet design companies will reserve the name for you and there are numerous places on the Web to reserve it yourself with a credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose a name that is easy to remember and will stand the test of time.
Don’t make your domain name complicated. If you run into a voter on the street and they ask where they can sign up to help, an easy to remember domain name is critical. I generally recommend to candidates that their political domain name be the same as their given name. In other words, if your name is Rand Paul, then reserve the name &lt;a href=&quot;http://randpaul.com&quot;&gt;www.randpaul.com&lt;/a&gt; or www.randpaul.org for you web domain. The reasons are simple: first, if people can remember your name, they can find you on the web. Second, no matter what office you seek or what year you run, it can travel with you. Finally, if you succeed and get elected, you can also transform it into a constituent site for your office – something that can’t be said for a campaign related domain name (like www.electrandpaul.com). For those three reasons, I see no reason to complicate the matter further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the domain name you want is unavailable, keep it simple.
Sometimes www.randpaul.com is not available - especially if it’s a common name. As Mick Jagger would say, “Sometimes you don’t get what you want, you get what you need.” So, choose a domain name that is also simple and portable through different offices and years. Consider a name like www.randforusa.com or www.randonworks.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have an effective domain name, let everyone know about it.
It’s not enough to have a good domain name, when you make it an integral part of your election effort, be sure to advertise it properly. Consider these mediums as you pursue your name identification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some candidates now are putting their domain names on their yard signs: JohnSmith.com instead of the standard Vote for John Smith. I have mixed feelings about this, but you saw some of this with signs in the Presidential campaigns this year.
Register your domain name with all the big search engines. There are over 900 search engines these days, but only about 30 – 40 that really matter. Many companies have services that will register your web site for a low fee. It’s important to have this done at least once a month for four months.
Display your domain name prominently in your direct mail, literature, notepads, radio ads, print ads and television ads. It will raise your individual name identification while creating an effective tool for organizational politics.
The bottom line is simple: In politics today, you need a domain name. Don’t wait, Ted Cruz wishes he had moved earlier to get &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tedcruz.com&quot;&gt;www.tedcurz.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/domain-name/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/domain-name/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tools to follow social media</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Figuring out what is trending on Twitter can be difficult. Do you use the advance search to look for keywords? Do you look at a list of thought leader every day? Check to see what’s on your timeline?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of tools out there that can help you discover what is popular right now to help you reach out to your targeted audience. Below are three that are some of the best around&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/buzzsumo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Buzzsumo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buzzzsumo searches Twitter for the most popular keywords or domains and can show results by time period, from last 24 hours up to a year. The best thing about Buzzsumo is that it tracks keywords and domains across multiple social media site including Google + this will allow you to add your two cents to the conversation no matter where it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/topsy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Topsy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topsy is a social search engine that displays results similar to Google. One of the biggest advantages to Topsy is that it offers a more immediate time filter the Buzzsumo ranging from the past hour to 30 days. You can also filter by links, videos, tweets, and by relevancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest advantages of Topsy is that it goes further with Topsy Analytics. There you can look at the volume of tweets sent each day and compare them to up to 2 other keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/socialmention.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Socialmention&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Socialmention unlike Buzzsumo and Topsy focuses on real-time search results this means that is doesn’t automatically sort by popularity or volume. The big advantage of Social mention is you can see the latest tweets, blog posts and other social posts about any topic you choose, from any time, or from a specific time like the past hour for the past month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the left side you can see some basic stats about your chosen keyword, such as the sentiment and reach. There is other useful information that you can use to dive deeper into what content is popular available too, like the top tweeters tweeting about your topic and the most popular related hashtags.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/Social-Media-Tracker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/Social-Media-Tracker/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Digital</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Price Per Click Guide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With voter moving to digital platform social media like Facebook and YouTube, campaigns need to make sure that they treat their digital campaign like it’s own campaign with the ability to fundraise, voter ID, voter registration, and GOTV. This will allow it to work to enhance your traditional campaign beyond a strictly digital strategy. The biggest thing is that digital campaign brings in more reliable voter’s date making measurements. This is a huge improvement because currently canvassing has to do some guesswork about whether the support is real or the voter was being polite, and trying to end the conversation. While you can train voters to mitigate this digital look beyond what they say and take into consideration how long they spend on a page, what pages they looked at, and are able to see what they are talking about throw tags. Also, it is much better at targeting voter because of the range of option from demographics to time and even IP addresses. When looking at digital platform, there are some basics that are shared with all of the options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-3-way-you-can-bid-with-digital-platforms&quot;&gt;There are 3 way you can bid with digital platforms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/0505496001433988952-ppc intro-html-44bd1ed20.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bad example of digital GOTV Get out the Vote&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each platform allows for different bids, but you will always run into some combination of these 3, and for most people CPC and CPA are the best because it allows any individual to set up an ad that does well because they mitigate the need for staff to do ad copy and test. That being said the cheapest if you have the stuff already is CPM because you are able to get the cost per click much lower since you bid for 1000 impressions at a time at a low rate. Also, CPM is the best way to do voter outreach for a GOTV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A digital
  GOTV is one of the best ways to target the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.voterparticipation.org/the-rising-american-electorate/&quot;&gt;Rising American Electorate&lt;/a&gt;, but there are few things that you should
  keep in mind&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;avoid-lots-of-text&quot;&gt;Avoid Lots of Text&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/0505496001433988952-ppc%20intro-html-m166e5a40.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bad example of digital GOTV Get out the Vote&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;have-a-picture&quot;&gt;Have A Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/0505496001433988952-ppc%20intro-html-mcd0f885.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;example with the best picture for digital GOTV Get out the Vote&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-it-short&quot;&gt;Keep it short&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/0505496001433988952-ppc%20intro-html-m3474715b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fat fing design for digital GOTV Get out the Vote&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Cost Per Impression work great for GOTV you are going to want to use Cost Per Click or Cost Per Action for digital fundraising. This will allow you to pay for only the view that clicks on the ad. This means that if you have done your targeting and ad copy correct, then the visitor will have a likely chance a donating given they were drawn in by the ad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/PPC-Guide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/PPC-Guide/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Digital</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jeb&#39;s Problem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While Jeb Bush and Hillary Clinton are often seen as the inevitable nominees for their parties, Hillary Clinton is the only one of the two was there is any certainty of becoming the nomination. The reason why Hillary Clinton can count on the nomination is because she is seen as the most likely candidate to defeat the Republican nominee this means that at least 39% of caucus-goers will likely vote for here. In contrast, while 38% of Republican caucus say defeating the democratic nominee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/poll.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;poll of Jeb Bush&#39;s Problem&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breitbart&quot;&gt;Breitbart:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Of course, former Massachusetts Gov. Mitt Romney—the 2012 nominee—failed to turn out the Republican base in the 2012 election with most estimates saying at least 5 million conservatives stayed home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feeling that Mitt Romney lost for being too moderate is a deeply held thought in many of the grassroots activists that make up the Tea Party, Very Conservative, and Born Again Christians coalitions. This has left the Republican primary somewhat of a mystery because with no clear frontrunner against Hillary the next way to determine who is the most likely to win would be based off of fundraising, but this has also changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ny-times&quot;&gt;NY Times:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And candidates like Mr. Cruz, Bobby Jindal or Rand Paul need not cater to mainline donors and fund-raisers, whose allegiance has been a deciding factor with almost every Republican nomination of the last three decades. Instead, they can combine grass-roots fund-raising online with a few large checks from conservative billionaires, amassing enough to be competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Super PACs more candidates will be able to keep going and unlike 2012 where only Rick Santorum and Newt Gingrich and Mitt Romney had Super PAC this time it is a requirement for everyone. While Jeb Bush still hasn’t released his fundraising totals no one will be scared off by them because as everybody has pointed out there is no reason not to run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/Jeb's-Problem/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/Jeb's-Problem/</guid>
        
        
        <category>GOP</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
