<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Roots</title>
    <description>Engaging activities and voter through cutting edge digital and grassroots strategies. That deliver the hardest fought elections</description>
    <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 22:42:30 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 22:42:30 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Social Media Strategy</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-social-media-strategy&quot;&gt;What is a Social Media Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Social Media Strategy is becoming a critical part of every political and non-for profits strategy, and unlike other digital strategies, your social media strategy is built with a framework and general policy. The first part is the Strategy that will act like a framework that will lay out your key performance indicators (KPI) and the general direction that it will take (IE. platform and activities). The other part is policy and will be the guidelines that will help you adapt your strategy to changing environments on each platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;social-media-policy&quot;&gt;Social Media Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Social Media Policy is by far the most important part of your Social Media Plan because it will be what fills in the strategy, and gives you direction when the unexpected happens. There are three basic points to cover in your Social Media Policy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you respond to people on social media
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The most common way to handle this is to not respond to people on social media because they are most likely to be trolls.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you do respond to people on social media it is best to try to get them off of social media. To do this you can direct them to a press release or direct message them, but you should have guidelines that focus on how fast you respond to people on social media and what type of message do you respond to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How do you use social media (IE. Repost of campaign material or social media exclusive media)? There are pros and cons of both of them, and each campaign will have to decide which one will achieve their goal&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How do you staff handle their own social media?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The one point you should always have is that staffers don’t talk about internal information (IE. voter contact number and canvassing location)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The other one that can be important is what they post about politics in general. The rule of thumb here is for staffers to only post what their boss post.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;social-media-strategy&quot;&gt;Social Media Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Media Strategy has 6 different angles in which you can use social media:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reach: Social media helps politicians more effectively reach large numbers of voters in a short amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Engagement: Unlike television, radio, and direct mailers, social media allow politicians to actively engage with their potential voters.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Share Ideas &amp;amp; Goals: Social media allows politicians to share their beliefs, goals, and accomplishments directly with voters, making them feel more directly involved with the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behind-the-Scenes: Social media allows politicians to give their supporters a behind-the-scenes view of their campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Turn Digital Followers into Votes: It is one thing to build a large, digital following. It is another to turn those followers into votes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Analytics: Social media allows political campaigns to more easily track engagement. “We now track every mention of a Senator, House Representative, or Governor,” said Zachary Green, CEO of 140Elect.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sample-social-media-policy--strategy&quot;&gt;Sample Social Media Policy / Strategy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;social-media-policy-1&quot;&gt;Social Media Policy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address the fast-changing landscape of the Internet and the way voters communicate and obtain information online. &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; departments may consider using social media tools to reach a broader audience. The &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; encourages the use of social media to increase our outreach to communities, where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; has an overriding interest and expectation in deciding what is “spoken” on behalf of the organization on media sites. This policy establishes guidelines the use of personal social media accounts, and official accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; social media related accounts will be subject to approval by office of the communications director&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; website (example.com, example.org, etc.) will remain the organizations primary and predominate internet presences&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The best, most appropriate &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; use of social media fall into two categories:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;As a way to disseminate time-sensitive information as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;As a way to promote an event and encourage followers and supporters engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wherever possible, content posted to &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; social media accounts will also be available on the main website of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wherever possible, content posted on social media should link back to the &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; main website for in-depth information, forms, or documents.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The quality question that is asked through social media will respond to within 24 hours through on or offline channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A Quality question is a question that’s about upcoming events like time and place, or are about clarifying a statement or position.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Poor quality question is accusatory and inflammatory, and will often look to attack your views and start an argument.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All new social media tools proposed for &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; use will be approved by the office of the Technology/Digital Director and the appropriate department’s public information authority.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; will whenever necessary will replace any removed content with an explanation of why it was removed and step that have been taken to avoid similar events.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; reserves the right to restrict or remove any content that is deemed in violation of this social media policy from staff accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Case studies There is no privacy on the Web.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Imagine, if you will, an NPR legal correspondent named Sue Zemencourt. She’s a huge fan of Enormous University’s basketball team and loves to chat online about EU. She posts comments on blogs under the screen name “enormous1.” One day, an equally rabid fan of Gigormous State (“gigormous1”) posts obnoxious comments about EU.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Sue snaps. Expletives and insults fly from her fingers onto the web page. They’re so out-of-line that the blog blocks her from submitting any more comments — and discovers that her i.p. address leads back to NPR. The blog’s host posts that “someone at NPR is using language that the FCC definitely would not approve of” and describes what was said. Things go viral.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The basically good person that she is, Sue publicly acknowledges and apologizes for her mistake. But that doesn’t stop The Daily Show from satirizing about the “NPRNormous Explosion.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Damage done.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Be circumspect about your behavior, even when the exchange feels private or anonymous. Even an email to a trusted recipient can be made public, with or without the recipient’s knowledge or consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Staff should avoid posting partisan political material. They shouldn’t just spread information they should be careful and skeptical.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Staff shouldn’t comment on issues that &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; are involved in, and any questions about &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; should be directed to the communication department or website.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Self-protection is part of being accountable online. Make sure that you use two-stage authentication and strong passwords with all social media accounts&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;social-media-strategy-1&quot;&gt;Social Media Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Media Strategy will be used to target 18-35-year-olds thought multiple social platforms. Whenever possible create and maintain an open community, and to disseminate information as quickly as possible. The primary goal is to help organize supporters and reach out to hard to reach groups through fan pages, hashtags, and subreddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platforms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reddit have an ongoing AMA(Ask Me Anything) to direct question on another platform, and have scheduled time for both staff and politician. Allow for the volunteers to form a community, and to create and give input about blitz days and other campaign events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter: use Twitter as a new RSS feed for new site content and press release. Try to get any interaction to the Website or Reddit whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook: use it as a portal for the website, but keep it up to date with pictures unique to the site and recent events and a current event list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tactics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create 2 blog post a week that talk about what the campaign has been up to (IE. events, press mentions, endorsements, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create infographic once a month on issues that are most important to an online audience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use listening tools to monitor keywords and content sediment(negative, neutral, or positive)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;create hashtags for the major event like Blitz Days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Performance Indicators (KPI)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main KPI: Will be sign-ups to an email list to stay up to date on volunteer, and campaign events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondary KIP: - Share and Upvotes(5+ will create a backlink) - Increase of inbound traffic to the main site&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one KPI that you should never use is a number of users this is because followers have no value if they don’t engage with the campaign through sharing commenting or signing-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;influencers&quot;&gt;Influencers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An influencer is a member of a community that can help you spread your brand and gain you meaningful followers that will help your KPIs. There are several tools to help you find them and they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://buzzsumo.com&quot;&gt;Buzzsumo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://keyhole.co/&quot;&gt;Keyhole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Social-Media-Tracker/&quot;&gt;More Tools for Social Media Tracking and Engagement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://meshfire.com&quot;&gt;Meshfire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;(shut down)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALL&lt;/strong&gt; Have a free unlimited option that is somewhat limited but is some of the best options out there.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Media Strategies aren’t like any other strategy you will have for your campaign because of the flex-able nature of social media platforms. That is why you should always have a clear list of rules and ethics that will guide you through every situation while making sure that you have clear, measurable, and meaningful goals for your social media strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;first-posted-11-18-2016&quot;&gt;First Posted 11-18-2016&lt;/h6&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/social-media-policy/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/social-media-policy/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volunteer Relations System</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summery&quot;&gt;Summery&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the election year coming grassroots programs will start to launch and with every program the heart and soul of the grassroots program is volunteer so by creating a volunteer relations system you will be able to build and maintain a volunteer team that will be there for you from your first blitz day to your final GOTV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-you-have-a-volunteer-retention-system&quot;&gt;Why should you have a volunteer retention system&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volunteers are the lifeblood or non-for profits, campaigns, and political parties, and while where and how you recruit them is important keeping motivated and involved not just through the campaign, but in between is important to make sure that you have the support to make the calls and knock the doors to win. Here at Digital Roots we have written about how to &lt;a href=&quot;../recruit/&quot;&gt;identify and manage volunteer&lt;/a&gt;, but we have never talked about how to build a system that will help you retain first-time volunteers and keep them through the winter and off cycle slumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-case-for-a-program&quot;&gt;The Case for a Program&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When maintaining volunteers there are a number of challenges that every organization faces:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reducing ‘churn’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engaging or growing current volunteering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increasing loyalty to the organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These issues are best faced with a loyalty program because there are a number of advantages over the average volunteers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stay active over a long period of time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More likely to suggest people volunteers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spend more time volunteering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-building-the-system&quot;&gt;How to Building the System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While each system will be different in a number of key ways there are some rules of thumbs to make sure that the program is successful. The key parts are broken down into the key element of every loyalty program and the mechanics that make the program function on a day to day basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;loyalty-levers&quot;&gt;Loyalty Levers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;rewards&quot;&gt;Rewards&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rewards are the backbone of the system and can be the most difficult. The rewards can be done in a few ways, but they revolve around accumulating points so that you can receive an award. The points system can be a as simple as receiving the reward after you reach a certain number of points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of this is Duncan Donuts were once you acquire 200 points you are automatically issued a coupon for a free drink. Or as complicated as the ones most hotel use where you can exchange points like cash for food drinks and discount rooms. Unlike Duncan Donuts these systems allow for greater choice for the user and create a more customized experience through the different services. The tradeoff for these systems is that changing the system can cause a friction point with your supporters making it harder to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;recognition&quot;&gt;Recognition&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognition is what keeps people engaged in the program this is because it allows the individual to feel like they are making progress by reaching new levels or gathering badges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognition though isn’t just a statics it also has to come with benefits that are more constant rather than one time. One of the most common examples is when loyalty program members get a preferred customer hotline. For some organization, it could be an extended early bird special for events and fundraisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;relevance&quot;&gt;Relevance&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relevance is what will help you get new members to join the program. This is by far one of the most important parts of the program because using the program can quickly become irrelevant if you can’t gain and active members that will use your loyalty program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest friction points are the forms to sign-up are too long and ask for more information then need to start. The thing to remember is that you can always get more information from a member once they are active. The other fiction point of relevance is the rewards while it can be easy to avoid on simpler systems more complex ones will have to figure out what members what and what is relevant to the as their status and use of the program goes up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;different-kinds-of-loyalty&quot;&gt;Different Kinds of Loyalty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mercenary&lt;/strong&gt; - where they are only loyal because it is the best offer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inertia&lt;/strong&gt; - were they stay in the program because they have already invested money or time(IE. money on a loyalty card)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;True&lt;/strong&gt; - were they believe in the organization and don’t need to be incentivized to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most volunteers will get involved because they fall under true loyalty, but because there are often multiple organizations that advocate for similar issues we need to create inertia loyalty to try to get volunteers to prioritize our efforts over those of allied organizations and give them a reason to stay on board after the first event (reduce churn).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;basic-part-to-a-program&quot;&gt;Basic Part to a Program&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 4 basic parts to every loyalty program, which are the currency, status, enrollment &amp;amp; activation, and partnerships. While most organizations have national, local, and state chapters the ability to do partnerships are limited because of the risk of sharing a volunteer list and the different laws. That is why it is best for an organization with multiple levels of organizations should run the program at the state level and allow local branches to join the statewide program directly rather than working in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Currency (Points) - This is the most significant decision in creating a loyalty program, and is the major supporter of the loyalty lever Reward. The two parts that need to be addressed is the member and organization side:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Decisions that effect Members:&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;How can the currency be earned: It could be for social media activity or for canvassing and phone banking.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;How easy the process is to use them: Does the reward automatically trigger once reaching a certain value or does the person have to spend them.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;What is the value of the rewards?&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Decisions that effect Organization:&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Breakage: ‘points’ earned by volunteers but are never used, typically stated as a percentage of the total.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Administrative Cost: annual costs associated with maintaining, and growing the program.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Reward Cost: financial value of any program award that a consumer receives and uses&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Status - is the especially important element of a loyalty program because it creates value beyond the points system and supports the loyalty lever Recognition:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Statues have to mean something: That means the there should a desirable benefit for these “special volunteers”, and should be a continuing benefit, unlike currency benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Enrollment &amp;amp; Activation - All programs start with enrolling (acquiring) and activating (on-boarding) a new member done well it will support the loyalty lever Relevance. The key points are:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Make the process simple&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Minimize the information that is “required”&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Enable enrollment to happen across many channels.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tell them only what they need to get started&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tracking-key-performance-indicators-kpi&quot;&gt;Tracking Key Performance Indicators (KPI)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest difference between private business and non-for profits is the KPIs. In business, it is based on how much more a member spends. For non-for profits, they could use a program for donations, but it would be better at attracting retaining and mobilizing voters. So the KPIs should be based events, voter contact, and volunteer referred rather than a monetary value or social media engagement (IE. reviews and generated content).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting your KPIs to focus on volunteers will have a larger return because investing in a grassroots program can be a time consuming and labor intensive effort. With a loyalty system is well built you can reduce voluntary churn between election, allowing you to start more aggressively and spend more time growing from last year progress rather than rebuilding last year team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;first-posted-12-03-2016&quot;&gt;First Posted 12-03-2016&lt;/h6&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/volunteer-system/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/volunteer-system/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Free Media and Twitter in the 2016 Presidential Election</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter L. Francia looked into one of the leading theories for the stunning victory of President Donald Trump. In Free Media and Twitter in the 2016 Presidential Election: The Unconventional Campaign of Donald Trump Peter L. Francia looks at a number of different datasets to determine if there is validity to the free media thesis, which states Donald Trump was able to surprises pundits and reporters because they looked at traditional metrics and didn’t take into account Trumps earned media. &lt;strong&gt;Peter L. Francia does state that his paper doesn’t prove or disprove the free media thesis but only adds to the body of work examining it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../pdf/Free-Media-Twitter-2016-Presidential-Election.pdf&quot;&gt;View/Download Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first issue with the free media theory is that Donald Trump’s earned media had been often more negative than positive, but in his study, Dr. Francia points to a YouGov/Economist poll that illustrated why this wasn’t a major hindrance to Donald Trump profiting off of earned media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Source. The Economist/YouGov Poll (2016).&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Trump Voters (%)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Clinton Voters (%)&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;A great deal&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;39&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;A moderate amount&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Not much&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;54&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Not at all&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;342&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;476&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hypothesis&quot;&gt;Hypothesis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Francia sets 5 different Hypothesis to test whether the free media thesis is validated. The hypothesis can be grouped into 2 groups 1 being based on coverage in terms of followers and free media coverage, especially around the crucial months of the campaign, and group 2 which uses polling on how much they saw and who they talked about the 2016 election:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&quot;hypothesis-1&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 1&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Donald Trump generated more free media coverage, especially during the key months of the election cycle, than did his chief opponent, Hillary Clinton.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&quot;hypothesis-2&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 2&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Donald Trump had more followers on Twitter than Hillary Clinton, especially during the key final months of the election cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&quot;hypothesis-3&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 3&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A higher percentage of people reported seeing more social media posts supporting Donald Trump than Hillary Clinton.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&quot;hypothesis-4&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 4&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A higher percentage of people reported seeing more news stories about Donald Trump than about Hillary Clinton.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&quot;hypothesis-5&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 5&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A higher percentage of people reported that they spent more time talking about Donald Trump in their personal conversations than about Hillary Clinton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While he was able to prove all five hypothesis the last three had some issues due to how the data was collected, but both hypotheses, one and two were able to prove which can be seen in table 2 and in the media that have covered the &lt;a href=&quot;https://shorensteincenter.org/news-coverage-2016-general-election/&quot;&gt;amount of coverage the candidate had received&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Donald Trump Versus Hillary Clinton: Media Value and Media Mentions, June 2016 - Oct. 2016&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Source. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediaquant.net&quot;&gt;MediaQuant&lt;/a&gt; (https://www.mediaquant.net).&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;June 2016&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;July 2016&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Aug. 2016&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sep. 2016&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Oct. 2016&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Total&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$435,374,385&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$543,712,760&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$482,966,428&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$482,966,428&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$568,472,657&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$2,490,502,963&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(71,029,693)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(86,155,811)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(70,124,397)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(69,967,542)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(73,802,984)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(371,080,427)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Hillary Clinton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$298,767,825&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$505,324,483&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$340,878,265&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$418,339,706&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$479,094,664&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$2,042,404,943&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(40,576,744)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(72,175,075)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(45,320,187)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(61,782,564)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;60,378,488)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(280,233,058)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;critique&quot;&gt;Critique&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypothesis 3-5 aren’t good indicators to see if the free media thesis could have been the reason for Presidents Trump surprise victory because other research has shown that social media and private conversations about politics are often &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.vice.com/story/journalists-and-trump-voters-live-in-separate-online-bubbles-mit-analysis-shows&quot;&gt;self-sorted&lt;/a&gt; which means the people who were talking about politics were talking to people who were like-minded if they were for Trump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/FreeMediaThesis/TwitterData1-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of graph showing political division and segregation on Twitter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, given the negative coverage of Trump during the campaign and after there is a possibility that the polls might not include people who follow both Trump and Clinton, but support Trump because they are less likely to participate in the poll due to negative coverage which looked at in &lt;a href=&quot;../pdf/swing-voters.pdf&quot;&gt;Myth of the Swing Voter&lt;/a&gt;. With the possible nonresponse rates from marginal supports plus small dataset makes the evidence &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2017-11-27/the-economics-data-revolution-has-growing-pains&quot;&gt;more likely to be a false positive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the study of Peter L. Francia has accomplished what he set out to do, which is contributing to the growing evidence of the legitimacy of the free media thesis being a driving factor behind Donald Trump’s surprise victory. Because, as he points out, when proving hypothesis 1 and 2 the value of the earned media and the timing in which it happened could have had a meaningful impact on the election. &lt;strong&gt;The major take away campaigns can use&lt;/strong&gt; is how social media can be used to gain media coverage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/FreeMediaThesis/Path-of-influence.png&quot; alt=&quot;flow chart from the study showing how information reaches voters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;, but be warned if you are a local candidate this is not likely to work because federal and statewide officeholders take precedence in the media which means there are better ways to gain media attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../pdf/Free-Media-Twitter-2016-Presidential-Election.pdf&quot;&gt;View/Download Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/free-media-thesis/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/free-media-thesis/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basics Of Fundraising</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-you-need-to-fundraise&quot;&gt;Do you need to Fundraise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short Answer: Yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long Answer: Even if you have a full-time volunteer staff you will still need to buy and rent the basics(.ie voter list, offices, and any campaign materials), but full time for Local elections (Towns/Small Cities and State Senate/House) you will need 40-70 hour a week to make enough voter contacts in 3-4 months. So while it is possible to not spend more than $1,000 + voter list for a local race by raising money you will be able to increase your voter contacts so 5 hours of fundraising can reach more voters through mailers or digital ads then 5 hours of phone banking or door knocking. &lt;strong&gt;Keep in Mind the average winning political campaign will spend between $16 - $67 per vote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;basics-of-fundraising&quot;&gt;Basics of Fundraising&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Candidates/Public Figure Does the Fundraising&lt;/strong&gt;: Candidates are your best resource when you are doing fundraising. They are the only ones to give donors the personal touch that often works best.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have to Ask&lt;/strong&gt;: Very little donations come in unsolicited so you have to ask.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask for More&lt;/strong&gt;: No one will ever give more than they are asking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask Often&lt;/strong&gt;: While I was fundraising for the RNC we would go through each list with 2 weeks. This was because we found that people who donated recently are more likely to donate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create Urgency&lt;/strong&gt;: Give a reason to donate like fighting a policy or to win an election.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay In Touch&lt;/strong&gt;: Following Up with donors and making them feel like they are part of the team will make them feel that their donations are going to something meaning full.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every One Does Fundraising&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read More:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../fundraising-plan-1/&quot;&gt;Writing and Developing A Fundraising Plan&lt;/a&gt;: In this article, I go over the fundamentals of writing a fundraising plan, and the 6 Components of a Successful Political Fundraising Plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../digital-fundraising-part-1/&quot;&gt;Build Your Digital Fundraising Effort&lt;/a&gt;: In Digital Fundraising we go over creating a blog to build an email, while also helping you find, reach out to, and measure influencers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-keep-a-cost-low&quot;&gt;How to Keep a Cost Low&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;strong&gt;fundraising is unavoidable&lt;/strong&gt; you can minimize the amount of time you have to spend doing it by keeping your costs low.  The first thing you need to do is to keep the costs of your campaign basics as low as possible. The easiest place to do this is cutting your website cost by using free hosting, and free service. The other major thing you can do is &lt;a href=&quot;../problem-with-yard-signs/&quot;&gt;avoid yard signs&lt;/a&gt;, while you may see them every year they aren’t worth the money because mailers and digital ads are better, due to being able to target, track, and measure them.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/introduction-to-fundraising/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/introduction-to-fundraising/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Campaign Strategy for Political Campaigns</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a Local Campaign comes with its own problems from the lack of resources to the lack of coverage from the media, and while some you have control over others is just part of the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;basics&quot;&gt;Basics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you do anything you need to figure out how many voters you will need, how many voters are there, and how many show up in any given election. This information is publicly available on election boards websites. Below is an example of the Annapolis Mayor Race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start, we take the last three elections 2005, 2009 and 2013 to determine our goals and whether it is possible to run for the local office, by looking at the election summary reports:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;annapolis-2005-mayor-election&quot;&gt;Annapolis 2005 Mayor Election&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Local-Campaign-Strategy/Annapolis-Mayor-Race-2005.png&quot; alt=&quot;Election Summary Report of 2005 Annapolis Mayor Race&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.annapolis.gov/462/Previous-Election-Results&quot;&gt;Annapolis Previous Election Results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;annapolis-2009-mayor-election&quot;&gt;Annapolis 2009 Mayor Election&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Local-Campaign-Strategy/Annapolis-Mayor-Race-2005.png&quot; alt=&quot;Election Summary Report of 2009 Annapolis Mayor Race&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.annapolis.gov/462/Previous-Election-Results&quot;&gt;Annapolis Previous Election Results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;annapolis-2013-mayor-election&quot;&gt;Annapolis 2013 Mayor Election&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Local-Campaign-Strategy/Annapolis-Mayor-Race-2013.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Election Summary Report of 2013 Annapolis Mayor Race&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.annapolis.gov/464/2013-Elections&quot;&gt;Annapolis Previous 2013 Election Results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key take away from these summary reports are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Voter turn out is between 33% and 35%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3rd Parties are an issue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4000 votes is the ideal target&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you know the number of votes you need your next step is to look at voter registration to see how many of the votes can come from registered party members. Depending on the race you can get the voter registration number from your state election board. Alternatively, you can acquire a voter registration list. &lt;strong&gt;If Party registration for one party is 2X higher than the other there is a good chance winning a general election is a long shot, which makes getting volunteers and money much harder.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;strategy&quot;&gt;Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who you target and what you message is can be found out most easily by doing polling and while most polling firms will defend that you should constantly be polling, for down-ballot races you can be more sporadic, but you should poll throughout the campaign even if it’s once or twice a month. This is because over a 9+ month long campaign national and local news can change what people are concerned about, and it gives you a 10,000-foot view of the race&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other major thing you will have to do is target voter, which you can read more here: &lt;a href=&quot;../Targeting-Voters/&quot;&gt;How to Target Voters for a Political Campaign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grassroots&quot;&gt;Grassroots&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;They had a lot of their own thoughts on what went wrong … Mook had pinched pennies and failed to put organizers on the ground
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;b&gt;Shattered: Inside Hillary Clinton’s Doomed Campaign&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grassroots efforts are often the best strategy because it is considered the best form of voter contact, but it is also the most resource intensive for this reason unless you have 20+ hours volunteers, which for a local campaign is mostly friends, family, and yourself, a week you won’t be able to reach enough voters to justify the cost and time of the program. If you do have the manpower to pull it off though it should be the first thing that you start when you launch your campaign, and the earlier you start the more effective it will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Article&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;../voter-contact-math/&quot;&gt;Grassroots Volunteer Math&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mailers&quot;&gt;Mailers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mail-based strategy is one of the oldest political and issues campaign strategy, but it’s one of the most effective. This is because while digital might seem like a better option for local campaigns your audience is going to be older, and they still use and check their mail unlike those under 40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you design a mailer campaign, there are some things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bigger is better: You want to make sure that is can be seen through all the junk mail.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep the copy simple: the voter should be able to understand the candidate’s message and read between the mailbox and their front door.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Target your message: mailers are great at getting different messages to different people so make good use of this by sending targeted messages to voters, but not ones that contradict each other.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;digital&quot;&gt;Digital&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital outreach efforts fall into 2 groups the first is paid digital ads. These are the ads you have seen on social media and at the top and bottom of the search engines. The other king of Digital effort is influencers and organic. Both of which can take the time that political campaigns don’t have so political campaigns focus on paid digital efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;search&quot;&gt;Search&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using search for your digital campaign effort is the most underrated aspects in political campaigns because it is one of the hardest to understand. Unlike social media ads, search ads are based on what the user searches Google and to a lesser extent Bing and Yahoo. So when you start a search campaign you don’t want to target keywords like election 2018 or candidate Smith. What you have to do is figure out what the people you are trying to reach are searching for. An example is when I was working in Colorado on the no side of Amendment 66, which was a property tax issue, we went out and work on trying to figure out what our target voters were searching the Denver suburbs and what we found was that they were searching for was they were looking for car and home care. So rather than out keywords being about taxes when target lawn care and auto care searches so our ads were placed in front of them. While there isn’t a one size fit all solution for running a search as there are a few points to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Conduct strong and thorough keyword research.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure you keep your ads and landing pages relevant to the keywords.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use negative broad and exact match search to help better target and keep cost down.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;social&quot;&gt;Social&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paid social outreach is both easier and more effective with Facebook is the platform you should use for your political campaign. This is because it allows you to better target voters based off lists and interests, allowing you to better reach the voters your political or issue campaign is trying to reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, Twitter and Snapchat collect less information on its users making targeting must less effective because who people follow is less productive than what people give Facebook, and while Linkedin can be useful it is much more expensive than Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tv&quot;&gt;TV&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While television is often the most common way to reach voters for federal races it is one of the worse ways to reach voters at the local level. This is for 3 main reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Too broad an area: TV media markets can be much larger than the area you are trying to target, and in some instances cross state lines. A great example is any local races in New Jersey. Because the 2 markets are the New York and Philadelphia markets so if you were to run an ad for county commissioner you would end up not only having your ad run in other countries but other states.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cost is higher than alternatives: TV ads can be expensive and can vary depending on your markets, but overall digital and mailers will be cheaper because there is higher inventory (IE. places on Facebook and Google for ads to show) or you don’t have to worry about there being any inventory issues.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Can’t measure results well: With the rise of digital the information that you can get from your ad buys has grown greatly. Not only can you tell how many people saw your ad, but what they did when they interacted with the ad, but also are able to retarget them if the campaign was targeting them for a specific action (. I donate or sign-up).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other&quot;&gt;Other&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are other things a campaign can do.IE bumper stickers, yard signs, sign waving, billboards, and print ads. I would skip most of them because they don’t have any real effect and in the case of yard signs, despite neighborhoods being flooded with them come the election, they are a logistical nightmare and a waste of money compared to the other strategies above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related article&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;../problem-with-yard-signs/&quot;&gt;My Problem With Yard Signs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only exception to this list that I still consider is using print ads, but there are some rules you should follow. One stick with local papers and the best time to use print ads are in an off cycle (not even number year) elections for down-ballot races where the voters are older and the area doesn’t have a narrow or a cheap media market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;going-negative&quot;&gt;Going Negative&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it seems most candidates go negative, it happens less often than you think. This is because outside competitive Federal races there is just no reason to spend money raising you oppositions name ID. A great example of going negative gone wrong is the 2014 Republican primary in Virginia 7th Congressional District between House Majority Leader Eric Cantor and David Brat, and while it was a major upset most of the damage was done by Eric Cantor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For Cantor and his advisers, taking the election “seriously” meant brutally defining Brat (through lots of television ads) before the “liberal college professor” could ever hope to define himself.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/what-we-can-learn-from-eric-cantors-defeat/&quot;&gt;Five Thirty Eight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By spending money to raise his opponent name ID he was helping him more than hurting him because he was making Rep. Brat looks like a serious threat rather than a passing thought. Eric Cantor’s campaign also helped raise awareness of his opponent to people who might have been dissatisfied with his performance but didn’t know there was a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule a thumb is to always spend time introducing your self to the voters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;media-attention&quot;&gt;Media Attention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem that I have heard and experienced from local races is that they aren’t being covered by the media enough. The problem for all local candidates is that unless you say or do something controversial. This is just a fact of life for a local campaign, but one of the things that have always helped is having a contact at local newspapers and blogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you reach out to local newspapers make sure that you understand 3 major things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They are doing you a favor don’t go into your outreach thinking what’s good for you is good for them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure you reach out to them before you need them. This is basic PR 101, they shouldn’t just be hearing from you right as you need them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The media are never your friend make sure that you keep them at arm’s length, and not to trust them with anything that you aren’t ok with being public.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bring-it-all-together&quot;&gt;Bring it all Together&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a bootstrap political and issue campaign, it is best to stick with mailers and digital, with any volunteer you can get done phone banking. For local campaigns, you are going to have less time than you think with about 5 to 9 months till the election. So the best thing you can do is to use your time introducing your self to voters by running target digital ads to those under 45 and target mailers to those over 45, and to get volunteer, you need to start early by going to political groups especially the less established ones if you are challenging an incumbent in your primary. As your campaign grows your ability to expand your efforts will too, and that’s when you can incorporate a more aggressive grassroots or tv ads into your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/political-campaign-strategy/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/political-campaign-strategy/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fundraising Email: Digital Fundraising (3 of 3)</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;../building-a-campaign-list-digital-fundraising-part-1&quot; rel=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;Digital Fundraising Part 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;../finding-influencer-digital-fundraising-part-2&quot; rel=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;Digital Fundraising Part 2&lt;/a&gt; we went over how to build an email list for a fundraising campaign in Digital Fundraising part 3 we will be going through the basics of Fundraising with Email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fundraising-email-basics&quot;&gt;Fundraising Email Basics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundraising with Emails is still the go-to fundraising strategy for political and issue campaigns. However, the issue is that they have to take two actions to actualize donate. The first is having them open the email and click through to the donation page, and the second is having them respond to your message. Do it right and you can expect a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emailmonday.com/dma-national-client-email-report-2015&quot;&gt;return on investment by as much as 3800%&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic design for all emails is quite simple, it should be able to be used on mobile devices, and be readable from arm’s length and able to navigate with one eye and a thumb. An easy way to look at this is that the user should be able to scroll through and understand your email even if they are hiding their phone under a desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-group-donors-based-off-interests-segment-audience&quot;&gt;1. Group Donors Based off Interests (Segment Audience)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t reaching the right people, then your fundraising campaign will suffer, and while your email list is full of people who have expressed interest in your political or issue campaign each person was brought to our efforts for different reasons and has different needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why the first tip to having a successful email campaign is to segment your list. Here are a few basic groups you can create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Desired communication frequency&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Program interests&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Demographics (age, gender, location)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Giving status (donor, prospective donor, lapsed donor, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Role in your organization (donor, volunteer, board member, staff)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Higher response rates are a direct result of segmentation. In fact, some marketers have found that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/guides/email-marketing-new-rules/&quot;&gt;segmented emails campaigns increase revenue&lt;/a&gt; by as much as 760%!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-email-matches-to--donation-page&quot;&gt;2. Email Matches to  Donation Page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you match the design, visual and messaging elements of your email to your actual donation pages. But don’t stop there. If you’re being intelligent about your campaigns and sending custom asks for supporters based on their previous donation history, you need to direct them to a donation page that has that same ask amount as one of the values on the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-optimize-with-ab-testing&quot;&gt;3. Optimize with A/B testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boost your donation chances by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kissmetrics.com/ab-testing-email-campaigns/&quot;&gt;A/B testing&lt;/a&gt; to see how one email performs against another. Don’t be put off by the acronym, it’s actually a simple concept that involves creating different versions of an email and testing them to see which performs best—A or B!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, you might be wondering, “Will more people open an email with the subject ‘Please donate now’ than ‘Help us reach our goal?’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A/B testing makes it a snap to find the answer. Just fire off two different versions each to 5-10% of your email recipients, then send the better-performing version to the remaining 80-90% of your list. You can test a variety of variables such as your call to action, use of images, different donation pages, even the time and date that you send your emails. For examples, do emails sent on a Friday afternoon perform better than those sent on a Monday morning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust us, no one gets it right the first time. Be prepared to track and iterate. Track open rates, click-throughs, donations, unsubscribes and other statistics. Don’t wait until your campaign is over—measure right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-copy-best-practices&quot;&gt;4. Copy Best Practices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;1-make-it-personal&quot;&gt;1. Make It Personal&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;People are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aberdeen.com/research/7635/ra-social-media-marketing/content.aspx&quot;&gt;has a very strong impact&lt;/a&gt;, and can help your donation rate by up to 10%. Most mass email programs have this option and it is one that you should take advantage of, and A/B test different levels of formality and the use of just their first or last name.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;First name only- Dear John…&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;First and last name- Dear John Smith…&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Formal- Dear Mr. Smith…Dear Mr. John Smith…&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Informal- Hi John… Hey, John…&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;2-nail-the-subject-line&quot;&gt;2. Nail the Subject line&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hubspot.com/sales/subject-line-stats-open-rates-slideshare#sm.0016i5xrc1ckjdi6wc31mj851d5fd&quot;&gt;33% of email recipients&lt;/a&gt; decide whether they’re going to open an email based on the subject line. And, if they don’t like what they see, your audience won’t read about why they should donate.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep it Short&lt;/strong&gt; - under 15 characters&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create Urgency&lt;/strong&gt; -  Give them a reason to donate now by using words like “urgent”, “now” and “important”. Obama’s campaign found that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/story/2012/05/15-best-obama-email-subject-lines-076857&quot;&gt;“Hey”&lt;/a&gt; worked well for fundraising emails.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;3-make-the-call-to-action-clear&quot;&gt;3. Make the Call to Action Clear&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fundraising emails require a call to action so the reader knows how to give and get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While asking for money is the most important, you should also reach out to social media and volunteers, and while asking for donations both above the fold and at the end is ok to try to avoid overwhelming them for donation and ask for other things.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&quot;wrong-way&quot;&gt;Wrong Way&lt;/h5&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Donation-Email-DCCC.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of DCCC fundraising email&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&quot;right-way&quot;&gt;Right Way&lt;/h5&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Hillary-donation-vol-email.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of HRC campaign email asking for money and volunteers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/email-fundraising-basics-for-digital-fundraising-part-3/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/email-fundraising-basics-for-digital-fundraising-part-3/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Target Voters for a Political Campaign</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every political campaign strategy is built around targeting voters through different stages of voter contact, and while there is a range of ways to do the voter contact they all follow the similar voter targeting strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stages-of-a-political-campaign-targeting&quot;&gt;Stages of a Political Campaign Targeting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ID&lt;/strong&gt; : This can be as simple as using party registration or as complex as running a grassroots effort where you survey voter at the door and on the phone. This will allow you to create voter universes, so you can focus more on undecided voters, and supporters&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persuade&lt;/strong&gt; : This part is often skipped, but it allows the political campaign to better refine its voter universes and allows political campaign to reduce the overall size of the undecided voter universe&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOTV&lt;/strong&gt; : This is the last part of any political campaign, and it was the campaign tries to contact their support universes as many times as they can before the polls close.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started-with-voter-targeting&quot;&gt;Getting Started with Voter Targeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The First thing you will need to start voter targeting is a voter registration list for this article I will be using a DC voter registration list from 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ajschumacher/dc_voter_reg/archive/master.zip&quot;&gt;Download DC Voter Registration Data&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Warning Large &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.csv&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;overview-of-voter-list&quot;&gt;Overview of Voter List&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we talk about targeting voter with a voter registration list we should go over the basic of every voter registration list that includes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;personal-information&quot;&gt;Personal Information&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/voter-contact/voter-info-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Personal Information from Voter Registration list&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you will notice is that you are given personal information, and in some state, it can include phone numbers and email address. &lt;strong&gt;Thing to keep in mind&lt;/strong&gt; the information might not be current for voters (ie. moved or new number), and can have more people at each address then there are because of this. While it is a safe bet that a voter with an A, which means active, in status information is current inactive voter noted with an I will have to be followed up on and fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way you do this is by contacting and updating political campaign list through voter contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;voting-information&quot;&gt;Voting Information&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/voter-contact/voter-info-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Voter and Election Information From Voter Registration list&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part of the list can change based on the state you are in, but there are some common elements about each list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important part of this section is how often they have voted. This is because research has shown that people who vote are more likely to vote again. The best voter is the 3 of 4 and 4 of 4 because they will likely vote without much voter contact need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing that will be listed is their party registration (shown with personal information). In a state that doesn’t have party registration you are given information on which primaries, they have voted in(ie. democrat or republican). Then you can make a 5 point partisan scale, or you just mark them down as republican, democrat, and crossover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;data-brokers&quot;&gt;Data Brokers&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final thing you can do to target voter is to buy voter data from a vendor, but the major thing to keep in mind is that the voter data is most likely 3rd hand data (.ie magazine subscriptions and email lists) while these can give you some information about a voter you don’t know how old the data is and could include people who don’t live there&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running surveys through canvassing and phone banking is the only way you can make sure the information is correct, which makes 2nd hand data (.ie Facebook and LinkedIn) give you better results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;acquiring-the-list&quot;&gt;Acquiring the List&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each state has their own laws on how much and who can have access to it, and what kind of data will be on it. Below is a state by state list of costs and different restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rwd-table&quot;&gt;
&lt;table id=&quot;rwd-table&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th colspan=&quot;7&quot;&gt;Who Can Use&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;State&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;The Public&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;State Residents&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Registered Voters&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Non-Profits&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Researchers&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Political Committees&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Candidates&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Price Estimate&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Additional Data&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Website&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Alabama &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;1 cent per voter or about $30,000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.alabamavotes.gov/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Alaska&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$20&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;https://www.elections.alaska.gov/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Arizona&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;1 cent per voter or about $32,500&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Permanent Absentee List; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.azsos.gov/elections&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Arkansas&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$2.50&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.arkansas.gov/elections/Pages/default.aspx&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;California&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$30&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.ca.gov/elections/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Colorado&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$50 (One Month Extract)/$500 (One Year of Monthly Extracts) $1,000 (Annual Subscription to Live Database)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.state.co.us/pubs/elections/main.html&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Connecticut&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$300&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.ct.gov/sots/site/default.asp&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Delaware&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Not Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Not Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Permanent Absentee List; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://elections.delaware.gov/index.shtml&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Florida&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$5&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://dos.myflorida.com/elections/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Georgia&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$5,000 for records ($500 for CD-ROM)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History (Free)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://sos.ga.gov/index.php/?section=elections&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Hawaii&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$500&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Requested; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://elections.hawaii.gov/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Idaho&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$20&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.idaho.gov/elect/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Illinois&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$500&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;https://www.elections.il.gov/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Indiana&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$5,000 (Annual Subscription)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Voter Data; Vote History for Previous Ten Elections&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.in.gov/sos/elections/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Iowa&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$1,950 (Annual Subscription)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://sos.iowa.gov/elections/otherinfo.html&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Kansas&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$200&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.kssos.org/elections/elections.html&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Kentucky &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$450&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://elect.ky.gov/Pages/default.aspx&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Louisiana&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$5,000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.la.gov/ElectionsAndVoting/GetElectionInformation/Pages/default.aspx&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Maine&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$2,200&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.maine.gov/sos/cec/elec/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Maryland&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$125&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.elections.state.md.us/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Massachusetts&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Free for those who Qualify&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Information is Available via the Municipalities; Vote History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sec.state.ma.us/ele/eleifv/howreg.htm&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Michigan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$22.50&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;None&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.michigan.gov/sos/0,1607,7-127-1633---,00.html&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Minnesota&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$51&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.state.mn.us/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Mississippi&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$2,100&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Voter Data; Vote History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.ms.gov/elections-voting/Pages/default.aspx&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Missouri&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$100&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://s1.sos.mo.gov/elections&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Montana&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$5,000 (Annual Subscription)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://sos.mt.gov/elections/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Nebraska &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$500&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.ne.gov/elec/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Nevada&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$500 (Per Month Subscription)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://nvsos.gov/index.aspx?page=3&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;New Hampshire&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$8,200&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee (Separate List); Previous 2 Years Vote History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://voterlist.electproject.org/states/new-jersey&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;New Jersey&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes*&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes*&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes*&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes*&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes*&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes*&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes*&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$2.55&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data (separate list); Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.nj.gov/state/elections/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;New Mexico&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$4,800&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.state.nm.us/Elections_Data/#&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;New York&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Free&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.elections.ny.gov/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;North Carolina&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$25&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History (via FTP)These data are also freely available at http://dl.ncsbe.gov/The voter registration and vote history data are in the /data sub-directory and the absentee ballot data is available in the /ENRS sub-directory&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.ncsbe.gov/ncsbe/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;North Dakota&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$5,000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;https://vip.sos.nd.gov/PortalList.aspx&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Ohio&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Free (via HTTP directory)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.state.oh.us/SOS/elections.aspx&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Oklahoma&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Free (must request access to online system)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.ok.gov/elections/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Oregon&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$500&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://sos.oregon.gov/voting-elections/Pages/default.aspx&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Pennsylvania&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$500&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;AbsenteeData; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.dos.pa.gov/VotingElections/Pages/default.aspx&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Rhode Island &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$700&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.elections.state.ri.us/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;South Carolina &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$75 for printed list and $160 for CD's&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.scvotes.org/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;South Dakota &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$2,500&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://sdsos.gov/elections-voting/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Tennessee &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Political Purposes (Not Incl. Research)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$2,500&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://sos.tn.gov/elections&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Texas &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$1,250&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.state.tx.us/elections/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Utah&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$1,050&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://elections.utah.gov/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Vermont &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Free&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee can be Requested from Towns; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;https://www.sec.state.vt.us/elections.aspx&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Virginia &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Election Purposes (Incl. GOTV &amp;amp; Voter Reg)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$5,000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://elections.virginia.gov/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Washington &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Free &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;https://www.sos.wa.gov/elections/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;West Virginia &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$6,000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;None&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.sos.wv.gov/elections/pages/default.aspx&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Wisconsin &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$12,500&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Permanent Absentee List; Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://www.gab.wi.gov/elections-voting&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Wyoming&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Cannot Use&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Free&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;http://soswy.state.wy.us/elections/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Washington DC&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Non-Commercial Purposes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$2.00&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Absentee Data; Voter History&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;https://www.dcboee.org/&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/Targeting-Voters/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/Targeting-Voters/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volunteer Voter Contact Formula</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;voter-contact-formula&quot;&gt;Voter Contact Formula&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following formulas for voter contact are averages and assume all volunteer labor. The numbers in bold are for budgeting purposes; the actual number may vary depending on a number of factors you should adjust your own budgeting accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Door to Door Canvassing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Door-to-door canvassing assuming every door is knocked or a very dense walk list: average
25 doors per hour; 6 contacts(5 8 contacts) per hour&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Door-to-door canvassing assuming a walk list or more suburban district with less density: average 15 doors per hour; 4 contacts (3 6 contacts) per hour
Phone canvassing&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-Predictive Dialing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Phone IDs straight ID, no persuasion: average 35 dials per hour; 10 contacts (7 - 14 contacts) per hour depending on length of script (assuming non - predictive dialing)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Normal 3 hour calling shift to calculate number of lines needed&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Normal 5 days per week (unless other reasons)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Calling through the list 4x you can expect on average to reach about 45 - 50% of the people. One call you can expect about 15 - 25%.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;To calculate a number of dials for repeated calls through the list multiply the original list number by the following factors: 3x call though = 2.25 – 4x call through = 2.5 (e.g. to call through a 1,000 name list 3x = 2,250 dials, assuming bad numbers and contacts are removed after each dial through.)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Phone Persuasion — average 25 dials per hour; 7 contacts (5 - 11 contacts) per hour depending on length of script (assuming non - predictive dialing)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;GOTV calling — average 30 dials per hour; 10 contacts per hour, assuming no message.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phone canvassing – Predictive Dialing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Phone IDs — average 110 dials per hour; 45 contacts (assuming less than one minute script) per hour&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To calculate number of dials for repeated calls through the list multiply the original list number by the following factors: 3x call though = 2.25 – 4x call through = 2.5&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Phone Persuasion — average 90 dials per hour; 20 contacts (assuming an average 2.5 minute conversation) per hour&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;GOTV calling — average 100 dials per hour; 25 contacts per hour (assuming a 2-minute interactive conversation), assuming no message.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dropping Literature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dropping literature — average 50 houses (30 – 70 houses) per person/per hour shift, depending on turf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volunteer Recruitment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volunteer Recruitment calling — average 30 dials per hour; 10 contacts and 3 - 5 volunteers per hour depending on list and task (e.g. canvassing fewer, Persuasion calling fewer, ID calling more, GOTV calling more, dropping literature still more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;voter-contact-formulas---doing-the-math&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VOTER CONTACT FORMULAS - DOING THE MATH&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persuasion Phone Calls&lt;/strong&gt;: Assume that you are asked to make 5000 persuasion calls in 5 days. You will need 14 volunteers, each working a 3 - hour shift and 14 phone lines to call the list one time.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Assume you do not have a predictive dialer. For volunteer persuasion calls, assume you can make 25 Dials per hour/per phone line. Divide to figure out how many hours it will take to make the calls. 5000 attempted contacts ÷ 25 dials per hour = 200 hours&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Divide by 5 days (the number of days you have to call)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;= 40 calling hours per day&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;To figure out how many phone lines, determine how many hours per line you will be calling. If you assume you will have 3-hour shifts, then divide to determine how many lines per day you will need (and how many volunteers per day you will need).&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;40 calling hours per day ÷ 3 hours per shift = 13.3 shifts (14) per day. You will, therefore, need 14 phone lines and 14 volunteers per day to make 5000 persuasion calls in 5 days.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;To figure out how many actual contacts you will make, assume a 25% contact rate (based on calling through the list one time). You can expect at the end of five days to have made &lt;strong&gt;1,250 actual contacts&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;To figure out how many names and volunteers you would need to make 5000 contacts do the reverse.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;5000 contacts ÷ 50% contact rate (based on calling the list through 4 times) = 10,000 names/numbers to start with&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;10,000 x 2.5 (the factor for the number of dials to call though 4x) = 25,000 dials.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;25,000 ÷ 25 = 1000 hours&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;= 200 calling hours per day&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;= 67 shifts and volunteers&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;To figure out how long it would take to call one time through the list of 5,000 names using a predictive dialer.
5000 attempted contacts ÷ 90 dials per hour = 56 hours
= 11 calling hours per day
= 4 stations and volunteer shifts&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;To figure out how to make 5,000 contacts using a predictive dialer.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;5000 contacts ÷ 20 contacts per hour = 250 calling hours
= 50 hours per day
= 14 shifts per day&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Door - to - Door Canvassing&lt;/strong&gt; Assume that you are asked to knock 3600 households of targeted voters in a dense urban district (although not every house will be knocked). You want to know how many volunteers you will need to knock it in ten days. To knock this number of houses in 10 days you will need 5 volunteers per day for 10 days, each person working a 3-hour shift. You will make approximately 864 contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Start with 3600 households. To calculate how many hours it will take:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;3600 HH ÷ 25 doors knocked per hour = 144 hours&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;To calculate the number of volunteers you need to determine how long a shift will be:&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;144 hours ÷ 3 hour shifts = 48 shifts (or volunteers)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;48 shifts (volunteers) ÷ 10 days = 4.8 (5) shifts (volunteers) per day&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To calculate the number of contacts:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;144 hours x 6 contacts per hour = 864 contacts&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOTV Calling&lt;/strong&gt;.Assume that you are asked to make 3000 GOTV calls on Monday as part of a GOTV effort. You will need 9 lines and 34 volunteers calling in 3-hour shifts over 12 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For calculation purposes, assume that you will contact all 3000 with a message or direct contact (since they have already been contacted in some way).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3000 GOTV calls ÷ 30 calls per hour = 100 hours calling hours&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assume that you will be calling Monday 9 am - 9 pm = 12 hours. To determine how many phone lines are needed, divide the total number of calling hours needed to complete the calls by the total number of hours available to make the calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100 hours calling hours needed ÷ 12 hours total to call = 8.5 (9) lines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To determine the number of volunteers needed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100 calling hours ÷ 3 hours shifts = 33.3 (34) volunteer shifts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that not every phone line has to be filled at every moment, but that a full 33 shifts need to be filled over the 12 hour day&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/voter-contact-math/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/voter-contact-math/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
