<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Roots Blog</title>
    <description>Engaging activities and voter through cutting edge digital and grassroots strategies. That deliver the hardest fought elections</description>
    <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 10:12:19 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 10:12:19 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Tips for better User Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-for-slower-connection-speed&quot;&gt;1. Design for Slower Connection Speed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Design for slow web connections such as 3G&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: In the United States at least eighty-nine percent (89%) of users have high speed access, but currently fourty-two percent (42%) of internet usage in the USA is used on phones and tablets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/usa-internt-usage-graph.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Graph of internet Usage in USA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-not-display-unsolicited-windows-or-graphics&quot;&gt;2. Do Not Display Unsolicited Windows or Graphics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Do not have unsolicited windows or graphics ‘pop-up’ to users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: Users have commented that unsolicited windows or graphics that ‘pop up’ are annoying, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2016/08/helping-users-easily-access-content-on.html&quot;&gt;Google has started to penalize sites&lt;/a&gt; that use these ‘pop-ups’å&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;limit-homepage-length&quot;&gt;3. Limit Homepage Length&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Limit the homepage to one screenful of information, if at all possible. If you have a longer homepage keep important information above the fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: Any element on the homepage that must immediately attract the attention of users should be placed ’above the fold.’ Information that cannot be seen in the first screenful may be missed altogether—this can negatively impact the effectiveness of the Web site. If users conclude that what they see on the visible portion of the page is not of interest, they may not bother scrolling to see the rest of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some users take a long time to scroll down ’below the fold,’ indicating a reluctance to move from the first screenful to subsequent information. Older users and novices are more likely to miss information that is placed below the fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/ted-cruz-desktop-site.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ted Cruz's Desktop Website&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/ted-cruz-mobile-site.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ted Cruz's Mobile Website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;avoid-scroll-stoppers&quot;&gt;5. Avoid Scroll Stoppers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensure that the location of headings and other page elements does not create the illusion that users have reached the top or bottom of a page when they have not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;:In one study, three headings were positioned in the center of a page below a section of introductory text—the headings were located about one inch below the navigation tabs. When users scrolled up the page from the bottom and encountered these headings, they tended to stop, thinking the headings indicated the top of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, users have been found to not scroll to the true bottom of a page to find a link because they encountered a block of text in a very small font size. This small type led users to believe that they were at the true bottom of the page. Other elements that may stop users’ scrolling include horizontal lines, inappropriate placement of ’widgets,’ and cessation of background color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/example-scroll-stoppers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Examples of scroll stoppers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;set-appropriate-page-lengths&quot;&gt;6. Set Appropriate Page Lengths&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Make page-length decisions that support the primary use of the Web page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: In general, use shorter pages for homepages and navigation pages, and pages that need to be quickly browsed and/or read online. Use longer pages to (1) facilitate uninterrupted reading, especially on content pages;
(2) match the structure of a paper counterpart; (3) simplify page maintenance (fewer Web page files to maintain); and, (4) make pages more convenient to download and print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/appropriate-page-lengths.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Examples of appropriate page length&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;place-primary-navigation-menus-in-the-left-panel&quot;&gt;7. Place Primary Navigation Menus in the Left Panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Place the primary navigation menus in the left panel, and the secondary and tertiary menus together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: [One study]((http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/154193120404801309) found that navigation times were faster when the primary menu was located in the left panel. Also, navigation performance was best when the secondary and tertiary menus were placed together. Placing a navigation menu in the right panel was supported as a viable design option by both performance and preference measures. Users preferred having the primary menu in the left panel, and grouping secondary and tertiary menus together, or grouping all three menu levels together. The best performance and preference was achieved when all three menus were placed in the left panel (placing them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;eliminate-horizontal-scrolling&quot;&gt;8. Eliminate Horizontal scrolling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Use an appropriate page layout to eliminate the need for users to scroll horizontally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/webmasters/mobile-sites/mobile-seo/common-mistakes&quot;&gt;Google has stated&lt;/a&gt; that horizontal scrolling hurts mobile SEO. Also horizontal scrolling is a slow and tedious way to view an entire screen. Common page layouts including fluid and left-justified may require some users to scroll horizontally if their monitor resolution or size is smaller than that used by designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/horizontal-scrolling.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Examples of Horizontal Scrolling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-headings-in-the-appropriate-html-order&quot;&gt;9. Use Headings in the Appropriate HTML Order&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Use headings in the appropriate HTML order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: Using the appropriate HTML heading order helps users get a sense of the hierarchy of information on the page. The appropriate use of H1-H3 heading tags also allows users of assistive technologies to understand the hierarchy of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/Heading-order.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Example of proper heading order&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;avoid-misleading-cues-to-click&quot;&gt;10. Avoid Misleading Cues to Click&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensure that items that are not clickable do not have characteristics that suggest that they are clickable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: Symbols usually must be combined with at least one other cue that suggests clickability. In one study, users were observed to click on a major heading with some link characteristics, but the heading was not actually a link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, to some users bullets and arrows may suggest clickability, even when they contain no other clickability cues (underlining, blue coloration, etc.). This slows users as they debate whether the items are links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/10-tip-ux/misleading-cues-to-click.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Example of misleading cues to click&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/10-tips-for-a-better-user-experince/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/10-tips-for-a-better-user-experince/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting a Political Action Committee</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A Political Action Committee (PAC) is often the best way to make a difference in politics. In this post we will go over the key differences between the two most common PACs, and an overview of the steps you will need to take to start and terminate a Nonconnected PAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;separate-segregated-funds&quot;&gt;Separate Segregated Funds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Corporations and labor organizations can’t contribute to federal candidates. They can establish and administer a special kind of political committee: the separate segregated fund (SSF).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An SSF can raise funds to make contributions to candidates — including expenditures that are coordinated with candidates — within the applicable contribution limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who can set up an SSF?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Corporations (including those without capital stock)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Labor organizations&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Incorporated membership organizations (including trade associations)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;National banks&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Incorporated cooperatives&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sponsoring corporation or labor organization is called the SSF’s “connected organization.” The connected organization can use its own money to solicit contributions to the SSF and to pay the costs of establishing and operating the SSF, for example staff salaries and office space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSFs may solicit contributions only from a limited group of people, including the connected organization’s executive or administrative personnel, its stockholders (if the connected organization is a corporation), or its members (if the connected organization is a labor organization or a membership organization).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nonconnected-comittees&quot;&gt;Nonconnected Comittees&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to set up a Political Action Committee (PAC) — and your PAC is not a political party committee, a candidate’s authorized committee or a separate segregated fund (SSF) established by a corporation or labor organization — you can set up a “nonconnected” committee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of congress and other political leaders often establish nonconnected committees, usually called Leadership PACs. Leadership PACs usually support candidates for various federal or nonfederal offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Super PACs and Hybrid PACs are another type of nonconnected committee. These committees must register and report all of their receipts and disbursements. If you are setting up a Super PAC or a Hybrid PAC, find more information on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/ans/answers_pac.shtml#super_hybrid&quot;&gt;FEC.gov quick answers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;essentials-for-nonconnected-committees&quot;&gt;Essentials for nonconnected committees&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;registration&quot;&gt;Registration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;getting-a-tax-id-and-bank-account&quot;&gt;Getting a tax ID and bank account&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Political committees must establish a bank account. This is required for many reasons, including helping keep committee funds separate from personal funds. You’ll use this account to deposit receipts and make disbursements. The account must be at one of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;National bank&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;State bank&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;FDIC- or NCUA-insured institution&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ll list the name and address of the bank on the authorized committee’s Statement of Organization (Form 1).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Banks require you to have a taxpayer identification number to open an account. Get your “Employer Identification Number” online or by completing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/fss4.pdf?portlet=3&quot;&gt;IRS Form SS-4&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions about obtaining a taxpayer identification number, call the Internal Revenue Service, 1-800-829-3676.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;getting-a-treasurer&quot;&gt;Getting a treasurer&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Every political committee must designate a treasurer before it can accept contributions or make expenditures. Designate your treasurer on your Statement of Organization (Form 1).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Treasurers must ensure committee reports and statements are complete, accurate and timely. This is a significant responsibility— if there’s an enforcement action against a committee, the treasurer is usually named as a respondent. Treasurers can be found officially (or, in some circumstances, personally) liable for the actions they take.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Treasurer responsibilities:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Sign and file all committee reports and statements.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Deposit receipts in the committee’s designated bank within 10 days of receipt.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Authorize expenditures or appoint someone else (orally or in writing) to authorize expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Monitor contributions, ensuring they comply with legal limits and prohibitions.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Keep records of receipts and disbursements for three years from the filing date of the report to which they relate.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A candidate can choose to act as his or her own committee treasurer.
Assistant treasurer&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A committee can’t raise or spend money unless it has a treasurer. For that reason, the FEC urges every committee to designate an assistant treasurer on its Statement of Organization. If the treasurer resigns or is unavailable, the assistant treasurer can perform any of the duties listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The assistant treasurer should be aware of all filing requirements and have access to the committee’s electronic filing password, if the committee files electronically.
Changing treasurers&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Committees must report a change in treasurer within 10 days of the change. Most do this by filing an amended Statement of Organization. This amended form designates (and is signed by) the new treasurer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Treasurers can also resign by informing the FEC directly by letter or — in the case of electronic filers — by Form 99.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;registering-a-nonconnected-committee&quot;&gt;Registering a nonconnected committee&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You must register your nonconnected committee within 10 days of raising or spending more than $1,000 in contributions or expenditures during a calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Register by filing a Statement of Organization (Form 1) with the FEC. The Statement of Organization collects some basic information, including the full name of your nonconnected committee, your address and your treasurer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If the information you disclosed on your Statement of Organization ever changes, you must report that change within 10 days. Do this by filing an amended Statement of Organization. If your nonconnected committee isn’t an electronic filer, you may update your Statement of Organization by letter.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Statement of Organization is available in the following options:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://webforms.fec.gov/webforms/form1/index.htm&quot;&gt;Web form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pdf/forms/fecfrm1.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pdf/forms/fecfrm1sf.pdf&quot;&gt;Screen-fillable PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pdf/forms/fecfrm1auth.pdf&quot;&gt;Screen-fillable PDF with audio instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read Form 1 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pdf/forms/fecfrm1i.pdf&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-file&quot;&gt;How to File&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some committees are required to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/elecfil/ef_overview.shtml&quot;&gt;file electronically&lt;/a&gt;. All other committees can choose whether to file electronically or by paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/elecfil/ef_overview.shtml&quot;&gt;Electronic filing&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/elecfil/software.shtml&quot;&gt;Filing Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper Filing&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;When filing by paper, your committee can use first-class mail, hand delivery or overnight mail options.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Always retain proof of mailing and delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First-class mail or hand delivery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;If you use first-class mail or hand delivery, your reports must be received by close of business on the filing deadline. If the filing deadline falls on a weekend or federal holiday, your report must be received by the close of business on the last business day before the filing deadline.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overnight mail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“Overnight mail” means registered mail, certified mail, Priority or Priority Express mail (with delivery confirmation) or overnight delivery service (with online tracking)— if you use one of these methods, your reports must be postmarked by 11:59 p.m. Eastern Time on the filing deadline, unless the report is a pre-primary or a pre-general report.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-primary and pre-general reports&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Pre-primary and pre-general reports must be received by close of business on the filing deadline if sent by first-class mail or hand delivery. They must be postmarked by 11:59 p.m. Eastern Time three days before the filing deadline if sent by one of the “overnight mail” options.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Postal deliveries to the FEC:&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Federal Election Commission&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;999 E Street, NW&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Washington, DC 20463&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;regular-filing&quot;&gt;Regular Filing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;know-your-filing-requirements&quot;&gt;Know your filing requirements&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After registration, your nonconnected committee must file regular reports with the FEC until you request to terminate and that request is approved by the FEC.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nonconnected committee filing requirements differ in election and non-election years. Election years are even-numbered years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As you review required documents, you may notice that some forms are offered as both a web form and a PDF. With the exception of mandatory electronic filers, nonconnected committees can choose whether to file electronically or by paper.  If a committee voluntarily files electronically, it must continue to do so for the remainder of the calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;election-years&quot;&gt;Election years&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In election years, your nonconnected committee can choose to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/info/filing.shtml&quot;&gt;file either quarterly or monthly&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to switch your committee’s filing frequency, you can do this only once per calendar year, and your treasurer must notify the FEC. Send the notification along with a report filed under your current filing schedule, on paper or electronically, whichever is your regular method of filing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Independent expenditures&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In some circumstances, your nonconnected committee may need to file specific and separate reports of independent expenditures. These are called 24- and 48-Hour Reports.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about Independent Expenditure reporting follow this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pages/brochures/indexp.shtml&quot;&gt;link to the FEC.gov section&lt;/a&gt; on Coordinated Communications and Independent Expenditures&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;non-election-years&quot;&gt;Non-election years&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your nonconnected committee &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/info/filing.shtml&quot;&gt;files quarterly&lt;/a&gt; in election years, you’ll automatically switch to semi-annual reporting in non-election years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your committee &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/info/filing.shtml&quot;&gt;files monthly&lt;/a&gt; in election years, you’ll keep filing monthly in non-election years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you want to switch filing frequency from monthly to quarterly or vice versa, you can do this only once per calendar year, and your treasurer must notify the FEC. Send the notification along with a report filed under your current filing schedule, on paper or electronically, whichever is your regular method of filing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Other filing requirements may also apply if your committee is active in a special election.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;terminating-a-committee&quot;&gt;Terminating a committee&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you decide to close down your committee operations, you must file a termination report.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You can file a termination report when your committee meets all of these criteria:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;You no longer receive (or intend to receive) contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;You no longer make (or intend to make) expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use your regular campaign finance disclosure form to file the termination report (Form 3, 3X or 3P). Check the “Termination Report” box on line 4 of that form’s cover page.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For example, you can combine your termination report with an already scheduled filing by checking the “Termination Report” box on your May monthly report. However, your termination report must include the following information:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;All receipts and disbursements not previously reported. This includes your accounting of any debt retirement.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;How you will use any remaining committee funds and assets.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your committee is involved in an FEC enforcement action, audit or litigation, you cannot terminate your committee. You must file regularly until that matter is resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once the FEC notifies you that it has accepted your termination report, you can stop filing regular campaign finance disclosure reports with the FEC.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t stop filing just because you checked the “Termination Report” box on your regular campaign finance disclosure form. You must file regularly scheduled reports until the Commission notifies you in writing that it has granted your request to terminate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;troubleshooting&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;missed-deadline&quot;&gt;Missed deadline&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The FEC doesn’t have the authority to give deadline extensions. If you miss a filing deadline, you may be referred to their Administrative Fine Program. File your report as soon as you realize you’ve missed a deadline. Contact the FEC with questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;responding-to-a-request-for-additional-information-rfaihttpwwwfecgovradfederalelectioncommission-rad-respondingtorfaisshtml&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/rad/FederalElectionCommission-RAD-RespondingtoRFAIs.shtml&quot;&gt;Responding to a Request for Additional Information (RFAI)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;administrative-fine-program-httpwwwfecgovafafshtml&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/af/af.shtml&quot;&gt;Administrative Fine Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;contact-the-fechttpwwwfecgovpagescontactshtml&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fec.gov/pages/contact.shtml&quot;&gt;Contact the FEC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/intro-to-poltical-action-committes/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/intro-to-poltical-action-committes/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Get Involved with Your Local Political Party</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the November election long past and midterms still over 18 months away a lot of people I know have asked me how to get involved with local politics. While there are may ways to seem involved the new way in social media rarely will lead to making the kind of difference you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-to-meeting&quot;&gt;Go To Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do if you want to get involved is join a local group that is affiliated with the party. The best place to find out when they have meeting is to go to a county party site or an affiliated group site. If you do have a problem finding the event calendar or if it is blank look for an email address and ask them about getting involved. The reason why I would avoid the state party is because they are less responsive compared to the local parties and groups, and it’s often the local parties role to organize during none election years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;volunteer-at-head-quarters&quot;&gt;Volunteer at Head Quarters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your state you can volunteer at the Head Quarters. This is a great opportunity because even though you start out with stuffing envelopes and answering phones it will give you an opportunity to meet a lot of the people who make the local and state parties run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-for-a-campaign&quot;&gt;Work For A Campaign&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reach out to a campaign they are always looking for volunteers, and would be happy for you to join them. The thing to keep in mind you will be spending your first couple of weeks doing voter contact before you get to do more, but everyone has had to do this, and most people who work on campaigns still go out knock doors and make phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-others-involved&quot;&gt;Get Others Involved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have spent some time campaigning try to get others involved. Start with your friends and family, and then move on to more difficult places like online and from public club meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;start-a-state-or-local-group&quot;&gt;Start a State or Local Group&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have been involved with the local party look at start a group that will help them reach out to the community, and have it sanctioned by the state party. One thing to keep in mind is that &lt;a href=&quot;../fundraising-plan-1&quot;&gt;fundraising&lt;/a&gt; is a critical part of any group, along with volunteer mobilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;run-for-precinct-chair&quot;&gt;Run For Precinct Chair&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Precinct Chairs are the lowest level of elected official, and are elected in party primaries. Precinct Chairs have varying power depending on county and state party rules, but it is by far the best place to start if you want to be in party leadership. This is because in most counties I have worked in the Chairs are the ones who elect the local party official, and can be the ones who determine what kind of primary you have (.ie caucus, convention, or primary).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;run-for-office&quot;&gt;Run For Office&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing you can do to get involved is run for office. If you have gotten involved and are known in the local party it is relatively easy because you will have the party support to get through the primary and general election.  If you aren’t known in the local political party, you can still win with a &lt;a href=&quot;../Campaign-Plan&quot;&gt;strong campaign plan&lt;/a&gt;, and start with a smaller office. Running for Office is like baseball you have to start in the minors to be able to make it in the majors. So when you look at election to run in realizing that by starting local you will be able to win larger races in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/how-to-get-inovlved-with-local-politics/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/how-to-get-inovlved-with-local-politics/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fundraising Plan (2 of 2)</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;../fundraising-plan-1/&quot; rel=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;Fundraising Plan part 1&lt;/a&gt; we looked at how to lay the ground work for you political campaign fundraising. In part 2 we will look at the 6 components every political and advocacy fundraising plan needs to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-6-components-of-a-successful-political-fundraising-plan&quot;&gt;The 6 Components of a Successful Political Fundraising Plan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience these are the 6 thing your political and advocacy Fundraising plan should focus on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;campaign-fundraising-goal&quot;&gt;1. Campaign Fundraising Goal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have stated in part 1 your campaign fundraising goals are driven by your campaign strategy. You will need to know what it will take to win your election before you can raise enough to carry out that strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your political fundraising plan should set clearly defined overall fundraising goals that lays out how much your campaign will need to raise not just for the campaign overall, but at each major milestone - Candidate ID, Voter ID, Persuasion, and GOTV. Because each one of these steps will require some if not all new materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if your campaign is planning to print GOTV materials you have to make sure that the campaign fundraising plan has that laid out so you don’t end up underfunding a key campaign activity. Similarly, if you have stuff you will need to make sure that you have a consistent cash flow in order to make payroll. By having a clear campaign fundraising plan you will make sure that you don’t end up underfunding any campaign activity last minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assumptions&quot;&gt;2. Assumptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you will do once you lay out how much you will need is to make some assumptions when formulating the plan. Every campaign makes assumptions, list them out in your fundraising plan so everyone is on the same page. Some examples of possible assumptions include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Assuming that the campaign will receive endorsements from several trade groups or associations whose support comes with major donations&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Assuming that your candidate will be the “establishment candidate” and receive funding your political base&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Assuming that certain major fundraisers will line up to support your candidate&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;List your assumptions up front, and know that if one of the assumptions doesn’t bear out, you may need to rewrite part of the plan to map out a strategy for dealing with the new reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning DO NOT make payroll decisions on assumptions&lt;/strong&gt; this has happened to me early on in my career and it caused me to give leave a job I couldn’t get back. It’s better to be over worked then hire some you can’t keep on till the election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fundraising-infrastructure&quot;&gt;3. Fundraising Infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What infrastructure do you currently have in place for fundraising, and what infrastructure do you anticipate needing over the length of the campaign?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundraising infrastructure includes things like fundraising staff, a donor database, your fundraising, marketing materials, your &lt;a href=&quot;../website-platform/&quot;&gt;website’s fundraising capabilities&lt;/a&gt;, etc. – everything you use to fundraise. Map out what you will need in order to effectively raise money for your campaign. Be sure to include deadlines and responsibilities for implementation, as well as the cost for each item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fundraising-tactics&quot;&gt;4. Fundraising Tactics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the section where you lay out, in as much detail, all of the different ways you are going to raise money for your campaign. Each tactic should get its own subsection with action steps, deadlines and responsible persons. Common tactics include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Direct Mail
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Events&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Online Fundraising&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../fundraising-plan-1/index.html#First-Step-for-Political-Fundraising---Finance-committee&quot;&gt;Finance Committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Major Donors&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Telemarketing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;PAC Fundraising&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Personal Solicitation by the Candidate&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Affinity Groups and Fundraising Networks&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use this section to detail exactly how you will implement each of these tactics over the weeks and months of your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;donor-communications-plan-and-calendar&quot;&gt;5. Donor Communications Plan and Calendar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use this section of your political fundraising plan to create a strategy for staying in touch with your donors and prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, in order to be successful, you want your campaign donors to feel as much as possible like part of your team. That requires communicating with them on a regular basis – and not every communication should be an ask. (For political campaigns, I recommend that you send your donors at least 1-2 non-ask communications in between every ask).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great donor communication will lead to more and bigger gifts from your donors. There are lots of ways to stay in touch with your donors and prospects. They include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email and snail mail newsletters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Postcards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Telemarketing calls for low dollar donors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personal calls for mid-level and high dollar donors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non-ask events (cultivation or thank-you events)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volunteer opportunities and committees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Public relations / PR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, the easiest and most cost effective way to stay in touch with your donors on a regular basis is through e-mail newsletters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;action-step-timeline&quot;&gt;6. Action Step Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, as I mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;../fundraising-plan-1/&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;, I like to include a list of action steps in each of the sections of the plan that lists what needs to be done by which deadline in order for the plan to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your campaign action steps and fundraising milestones should be listed in chronological order. This will allow for anyone who reads it to get a good picture of where your campaign is at, where your campaign should, and what has to be done in both the short term and long term. Many campaigns I worked on have used weekly timelines for their fundraising staff meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, your fundraising plan is a living document and will change with the campaign, but it is important to write down your plan so you have a clear way to know if you are staying on the right path or need to reexamine your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/fundraising-plan-2/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/fundraising-plan-2/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fundraising Plan (1 of 2)</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this series, we will walk through how to write a successful fundraising plan for your next campaign. In Part 1, we’ll take a look at why you need a plan, where you start with fundraising, and cover the two most important parts. In &lt;a href=&quot;../fundraising-plan-2&quot; rel=&quot;next&quot;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; we will be going through the 6 components that are needed for a strong and achievable fundraising plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-your-campaign-needs-a-fundraising-plan&quot;&gt;Why Your Campaign Needs a Fundraising Plan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fundraising plan is vital to success of any modern campaign, even the most local, but too often candidates assume once they get their campaign off the ground the money will start rolling, and take care of itself. They could not be farther from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campaigns run on money and even in the best Public Financing system you will need to get contributions to fund the campaign’s activities, this is by far the hardest part of any campaign. A successful fundraising effort will require the campaign in general, and the candidate in particular to spend quality time planning and execution a fundraising plan. &lt;strong&gt;The Candidate should spend a minimum 50% of their time fundraising&lt;/strong&gt; no matter level you’re running for - local, state, or federal - from my fundraising experience will be the deciding factor because if you don’t have the funds you can’t run a competitive campaign. That is why I always suggest &lt;strong&gt;writing out your fundraising plan before you launch your campaign&lt;/strong&gt;, and remember that your plan is a living document and can change during the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-comes-first---fundraising-plan-or-campaign-strategy&quot;&gt;What Comes First - Fundraising Plan or Campaign Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While having a well developed fundraising plan is a key to a successful campaign I often am asked by candidates and campaign managers what comes first the campaign strategy or the fundraising plan. Another way of putting it is does a campaign figure out how much it can raise them build a plan around it, or do they figure a &lt;a href=&quot;../Campaign-Plan/&quot;&gt;winning campaign strategy&lt;/a&gt; and then figure out how to fund it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience it is the latter, &lt;strong&gt;your campaign should figure out what it will take to win&lt;/strong&gt; because if you need to raise $500,000 to win and you aren’t able to create a reasonable fundraising plan to match then I would suggest sitting out this cycle or looking at a different race. Also in past races I have been involved with large donors like to know how their money will be spent, and a campaign strategy is the only way to show that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-step-for-political-fundraising---finance-committee&quot;&gt;First Step for Political Fundraising - Finance committee&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name “Finance Committee” can be deceiving because the committee isn’t really responsible for executing the fundraising. That task is for the candidate, campaign manager, campaign staff, and in larger races Finance Director. The role of the Finance Committee is to provide contacts who can be solicited for donations, and provides a starting point for the campaign’s political fundraising network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key elements that each member of the Finance Committee are that they have a wide range of contacts they can solicit to support the candidate, which should go without saying the members should be some of your strongest supporters, and have already donated to the campaign. To keep the members accountable you should get commitments or pledges about how much they will raise. The committee can be cured from a large spectrum of people from local businessmen, professionals, socialites, and political contact among other. &lt;strong&gt;The only requirement is that they have supported the candidate financially and have a gold Rolodex with multiple people who can also donate&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;political-fundraising-network&quot;&gt;Political Fundraising Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to fundraising local candidates are unlikely to national money and PAC contributions, and for the handful of candidate that do they are few and far between. For a candidate to then be successful the candidate, staff, and finance committee must be ruthless when it comes to using their contacts. This means when the campaign goes through their contacts they have to be will go beyond close friends and family and reach out to everyone in their social circles from school alumni to PTA and acquaintances from church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your list the candidate has to make the call. This is because every donor like personal contact, which means that the candidate will get more “Yes” then a campaign staffer. That being said spouses and family members are a close second because &lt;strong&gt;the key is using personal contact to make “potential contributors” into “regular contributors”&lt;/strong&gt;, and the best way is to make them feel like they have access and a connection to the candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-keys-to-a-successful-political-fundraising-plan&quot;&gt;The keys to a Successful Political Fundraising Plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two most important things that political campaigns fail to put into their fundraising plans are &lt;strong&gt;deadlines and responsibilities&lt;/strong&gt;. Every fundraising plan needs to have a list of deadlines for the event followed by action that need to be taken on certain days, which then are assigned a person who will be responsible for carrying out the action so the political campaign can meet its deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example you might create a schedule that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Campaign Kick Off Fundraising Event - 7/2&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Form host committee - 5/15 - John&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Secure venue - 5/20 - Jane&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Send out invitations - 6/1 - John&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make follow up calls - 6/10 - Jane, John and Committee&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Finalize event details - 6/20 - Jane&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Final follow-up calls - 6/28 - Jane and John&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that you can fill in staffing areas with campaign staff or volunteers the key is to &lt;strong&gt;make sure that you have a concrete action plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will guide the person or persons that are in charge of the task.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/fundraising-plan-1/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/fundraising-plan-1/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Website Platforms for you Political and Advocacy Campaign</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are a lot of options for a website for your political and advocacy campaign keeping it simple with a static site or a Wordpress site is the best option. We will be looking at both options and the tools that can be used&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;low-cost-website&quot;&gt;Low-Cost Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;fundraising&quot;&gt;Fundraising&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two tools that are non-partisan that can be used by any political or issue campaign:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://politics.raisethemoney.com/&quot;&gt;Raise the Money&lt;/a&gt;
  The one of the advantages to this fundraising platform is that is embedded in your site, which makes it feel more professional, but it the most expensive at 4.9% + $.25 transaction fee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://transaxt.com/default.aspx&quot;&gt;Transaxt&lt;/a&gt;
  The advantage to Transaxt is that it the cheapest non-partisan platform, but it will require user to go to a Transaxt subdomain making it look less professional and moving off your website. The transition fee is less the Raise the Money with a 4.5% transition fee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also partisan platforms, and while I have only used Revv both APIs will work with static sites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partisan options
  * &lt;a href=&quot;https://revv.co/&quot;&gt;Revv&lt;/a&gt;
  This is a Republican and Conservative platform that allows you to embed the API on your site with 4% + $.30 transaction fee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.actblue.com/&quot;&gt;ActBlue&lt;/a&gt;
  This is a Democratic and Liberal platform that has the lowest transition fee at 3.95%, but the user will leave the site to make the donation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;blog&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintaining a blog for a static site use to be difficult, but over the last few years &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.staticgen.com/&quot;&gt;Static Site Generators&lt;/a&gt; have made maintain a blog relatively simple. The most popular is Jekyll, but it was built to be used with a Mac so if you are on Windows make sure you take a look at the alternatives because setting up Jekyll can be difficult. If you are looking to set up a Jekyll site you cab make make it act like a &lt;a href=&quot;../static-site-cms/&quot;&gt;CRM with a few simple steps&lt;/a&gt;, and should be placed in a subfolder ie. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/blog&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other option is to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; as your blog platform, which has a few advantages. The biggest benefit is that because it is built around a social media platform, so it has tools to help disseminate your content to the right people right away. The other one is that people don’t need any technology skills because it uses a What You See Is What You Get (WYSIWYG) editor. If you do go this route try to buy &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.blog&lt;/code&gt; of your domain because you will be unable to set-up the blog in a subfolder or subdomain, and can use the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.blog&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.medium.com/hc/en-us/articles/214110127-About-custom-domains&quot;&gt;domain for your Medium&lt;/a&gt; blog, and redirect visitor from your main page. The biggest downside is that you don’t have control over the blog layout or features so it is less customizable, and will be harder to raise money off or collect emails from an article .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;hosting&quot;&gt;Hosting&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many options for hosting a static Website from &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; which is free to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2424725,00.asp&quot;&gt;options&lt;/a&gt; that can cost between $1.00 a month for a basic shared hosting to $50 a month for a Virtual Private Server (VPS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;high-cost-website&quot;&gt;High-Cost Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;fundraising-1&quot;&gt;Fundraising&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WordPress can use any of the platform list for static site &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/&quot;&gt;plus thousands more&lt;/a&gt;, but WordPress has a popular Plug-in called WooCommerce that will cost less because it can use many payment gateway. Setting up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?num=50&amp;amp;q=setting+up+WooCommerce&amp;amp;spell=1&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi6-qi9tL3RAhWEORQKHdbGAtEQvwUIGSgA&amp;amp;biw=1182&amp;amp;bih=731&quot;&gt;WooCommerce in WordPress has be covered&lt;/a&gt; in-depth, and since all the themes that are available are built with WooComerce in mind the biggest decision is the payment gateway, which unlike static website tools can very greatly, but will cost less then the fundraising platforms above. While there are many the 2 I would recommend are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.authorize.net/&quot;&gt;Authorize.Net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;More than 400,000 merchants worldwide use Authorize.Net payment gateway – that accepts online payments through credit cards and electronic checks. You need to pay $49 as setup fees and $29 as monthly gateway fees.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/payflow-payment-gateway&quot;&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;It’s one of the most widely-used payment gateways that accepts both credit card or debit card payments. It’s free to use for buyers. However store owners will have to pay a simple transition fees of “3.4% + $0.30 USD”, when using PayPal for credit card payments. This payment gateway does not require any setup fees, gateway fees, or monthly fees.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This set-up biggest drawback is that you loss the reporting tools that come with the built for fundraising platforms, and while this might seem like a large issue there isn’t much you do with excel, practice, and time can’t overcome when it comes to campaign finance reporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;blog-1&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WordPress was built as a blogging platform so it comes with all the tools need to publish a blog post from a WYSIWYG editor in a way to easily add images and video’s. The only thing you need to keep in mind is to make sure that your blog is in a subfolder &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;example.com/blog&lt;/code&gt; not a subdomain &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;blog.example.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;hosting-1&quot;&gt;Hosting&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest hurdle for a WordPress site is hosting. Because it is a dynamic website, we can’t use the hosting options on the static site. While there are cheaper options out there the issues will arise right as your content goes viral this often will cause the site to become unusable so it is best to invest from the start so when you strike gold you can. This topic has been covered by most WordPress based sites below is further reading on the subject:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://yoast.com/wordpress-hosting/&quot;&gt;The best WordPress hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wpengine.com/blog/wordpress-optimized-hosting/&quot;&gt;The WordPress Optimized Hosting Difference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wpbeginner.com/wordpress-hosting/&quot;&gt;How to Choose the Best WordPress Hosting?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.stackexchange.com/questions/142649/is-there-a-real-benefit-in-using-wordpress-optimized-hosting&quot;&gt;Is there a real benefit in using wordpress optimized hosting?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools-and-services&quot;&gt;Tools and Services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the popularity of Wordpress when you choose a tool or services for you political or advocacy campaign it will always be available. So the tools and services are targeted for those who choose to use a static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;email&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchimp.com/&quot;&gt;MailChimp&lt;/a&gt; is the most common tool used by local campaign websites because it has the best free option compared to the other email deliver systems, but if you know you will be going to a pay tier early on then there are many option these two I have used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aweber.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/Aweber.png&quot; alt=&quot;Aweber Logo&quot; /&gt; AWeber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Starts at $19/mo for 0-500 Subscribers, but offers unlimited emails along with premium features that are left off other low-cost tiers like segmenting which can help with retargeting outreach to supporters or donors of the political or issue campaign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campaignmonitor.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/campaignMonitor.png&quot; alt=&quot;Campaign Monitor Logo&quot; /&gt; Campaign Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Starts at $9/mo for 0-500 Subscribers, but limits you to only 2,500 email a month. To have unlimited emails you have to go to the next tier at $29/mo and to get all the features of Aweber you will need their Premier at $149/mo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;form&quot;&gt;Form&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other crucial service you will need if you are launching a political or advocacy campaign website is a way for supporters to reach out to you, and while a community comment section can seem like a good idea it will only lead to harassment and trolling from the opposition even if you use Disqus or Facebook Community. That is why I have always used a form on our campaign websites so we can move the conversation to email or offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only one I have used is &lt;a href=&quot;https://formspree.io/&quot;&gt;formspree.io&lt;/a&gt;. Formspree will allow you to place a form on your campaign website and have the responses forwarded to an email account, but your campaign can only receive 1000 submissions per email each month. If you would like to have more submissions they have a Gold Plan for $10/mo that will also give you a dashboard to help manage the submissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;putting-it-all-together&quot;&gt;Putting It all Together&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the information laid out thought the article you should be able to get you advocacy or political campaign off the ground, but it is just the start &lt;strong&gt;you will need to set up an organization with your state or federal government&lt;/strong&gt; so you can legally fundraise for your campaign. But the one thing you have to understand about an organizing an advocacy campaign online is that tweets, shares, signup, and web traffic does not equal votes at the ballot or in the legislature. So you will need to create a &lt;a href=&quot;../Campaign-Plan/&quot;&gt;campaign plan&lt;/a&gt; to move from the internet to the ballot box.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/website-platform/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/website-platform/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The West Coast Effect</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The West Coast Effect is the term given to an election controversy that date back to the 1960’s when the national broadcast started. This controversy centers around early reporting on the east coast and the impact it has on west coast voters. While the commonly studied effect on west coast voter didn’t have an effect on 2016 early voting reports might have a similar effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first research into in the West Cost effect was done in the 1966 election (Fuchs, 1966; Mendelsohn, 1966; Lang &amp;amp; Lang, 1968), and found to be no evidence of the effect of early reporting, but it had a few problems. One of the issues was that all three studies assume that voter made a decision on election, which is known to only be a few. The voters in the studies only showed that pre-election polls would have caused the west coast voters to stay home, then only hear about a Goldwater upset because that would have changed the results. The other problem was that they ignore the central question of what the effect on the local level. And the biggest one was that the 1966 election was never close so the east coast vote total provided no new information to west coast voters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the three Lang &amp;amp; Lang’s book &lt;strong&gt;Voting and Nonvoting: Implications of Broadcasting Returns Before Polls Are Closed&lt;/strong&gt; (1968) was more far-reaching and was considered the definitive study for over a decade. The survey was limited to, Oakland county and the members surveyed (438) resulted large margin of error, and once the early voter were eliminated there slightly more the 100 making the study inconclusive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1980’s there was a second wave of research on the West Cost Effect, which included multiple studies. Of the studies three of the studies (Delli Carpini, 1984; Dubois, 1983; Epstein &amp;amp; Strom, 1981) used aggregate date rather than surveys to overcome the lack of a sufficient data pool, while (Jackson, 1983) used a much larger survey. While Epstein &amp;amp; Strom (1981), Dubois (1983), and Delli Carpini (1984) used aggregate data, they all chose different details from Epstein and Strom (1981) using regional turnout data (West Coast, Pacific Northwest, Rocky Mountain states, etc.), Dubois (1983) using state level turnout, and Delli Carpini (1984) using congressional districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Epstein &amp;amp; Strom determined that the results were inconclusive. Both Delli Carpini and Dubois found there to be an effect, but Dubois argued this was a unique effect of the 1980 election. Jackson (1983) was different from the other studies because it was able to address the issue of information access, which the other 3 ignored. Because Jackson used a survey from the University of Michigan’s Presidential Election Study and from the Vote Validation Study by the Center for Political Studies he was able to create a pool of 1814 persons who were interviewed both before and after the election. Jackson found that the combination of access to early election returns and hearing Carter’s concession speech reduced turnout between six and twelve percent. There was little evidence, however, that either party was disproportionately affected, but because of statistical errors and among other problems it decrease confidence in the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most recent study by Peterson (2004) looks to address voter access to information that past studies have ignored. He was able to show a direct effect of early reporting with the average turnout for the informed participants were 31.2%, while it was 71.5% of the uninformed participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/west-coast-effect/west-bar-graph-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;West Coast Effect Figure showing voter turnout between informed and uninformed participants&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study also found that among informed participants that turnout dropped by 19.1% based off of earlier reports, but favored the candidate that lost on the East Coast because those participants turnout dropped only 8.3%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/west-coast-effect/west-bar-graph-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;West Coast Effect Figure showing voter turnout between favorable news and unfavorable news&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part of Peterson (2004) study shows us that the West Coast effect occurs, and participants who had access to the early election returns were significantly and consistently more likely to stay home than uninformed participants. In the second part Peterson (2004) looked at the effect if one candidate always had the support of a majority of the potential voters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/west-coast-effect/west-bar-graph-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;West Coast Effect With one Candidate having support of a majority&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study found when the information supports the majority candidate that informed voters weren’t effective, but uninformed voter turnout decreased slightly from 65% to 59% for majority supporters and decreased from 37% to 25%. When information about the minority candidate show them winning or tiring on the east coast, then minority supports increase from 33% to 55%, while turnout from the supporters of the majority candidate plummeted from 42% to 13%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;effect-on-2016&quot;&gt;Effect on 2016&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the studies are inconclusive the effect on early reporting does have the possibility to affect the outcome of the race and given a headline during and right after early voting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/politics/la-na-pol-early-voting-20161027-story.html&quot;&gt;Millions of people have voted, and Democrats are showing strong signs in key states&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mcclatchydc.com/news/politics-government/election/voters-guide/article107655357.html&quot;&gt;Could Hillary Clinton win the election weeks before November 8?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on top of the early reporting the voter that did come out to vote were &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tampabay.com/news/politics/stateroundup/how-hillary-clinton-lost-florida-hint-it-happened-on-election-day/2305224&quot;&gt;Super Voters&lt;/a&gt; so when election day came around and everyone from Fox News to MSNBC said that Clinton was in a strong position to win the low prospect voters decided not to show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the election a lot has been said about how Donald Trump won, but when looking at what happened in Michigan and Wisconsin with voter turnout dropping 0.2% and 3.4%, respectively the effects of early reporting should be taken seriously even if the results are inconclusive. Moving forward surveys looking to study the West Coast Effect should move beyond early reporting on election day and examine the effects of early reporting from early voting and the effect it has on election day turnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delli Carpini, M. X. (1984). Scooping the voters?  The consequence of the networks’ early call of the 1980 presidential race. Journal of Politics, 46, 66-85.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dubois, P. L. (1983). Election night projections and voter turnout in the west. American Politics Quarterly, 11, 349-63.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epstein, L. K., &amp;amp; Strom, G. (1981). Election night projections and West Coast turnout. American Politics Quarterly, 9, 479-91&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuchs, D. A. (1966). Election-day radio-television and voter turnout. Public Opinion Quarterly, 30, 226-37.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lang, K., &amp;amp; Lang, G. E. (1968). Voting and Nonvoting: Implications of Broadcasting Returns Before Polls Are Closed. Waltham, MA: Blaisdell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jackson, J. E. (1983). Election night reporting and voter turnout. American Journal of Political Science, 27, 613-35.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peterson, G. D. (2004). Can A Voter In New York Make A Candidate Lose in California? An Experimental Test of the Release of Early Election Results On Voter Turnout. Lights, Camera, Campaign!: Media, Politics, and Political Advertising, 11, 73.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/west-coast-effect/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/west-coast-effect/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting a Digital Activist Group</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best places to start an activist group is online because it allows for you to start organizing with low fixed costs. In this article we will talk about the basic to start an online political or issues based campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;starting-the-campaign&quot;&gt;Starting the Campaign&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start any political or issue campaign you have to choose a scoop, and while most people what to start and organize nationwide the problem comes down to scale because while a national organization saying they have 750,000 members might seem impressive, but they have no real influence because their support will be spread across 50 states, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_television_stations_in_North_America_by_media_market&quot;&gt;210 designated market areas&lt;/a&gt;, 435 congressional districts, which have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?num=50&amp;amp;q=average+number+of+voter+per+congressional+districts&amp;amp;oq=average+number+of+voter+per+congressional+districts&amp;amp;gs_l=serp.3...24138.29411.0.29511.28.28.0.0.0.0.105.2044.23j3.26.0....0...1.1.64.serp..3.9.662...0i7i30k1j0i8i7i30k1j0i8i30k1.kjDV6DeEVkk&quot;&gt;approximately 700,000 voters &lt;/a&gt; each, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.usgs.gov/faq/categories/9799/2971&quot;&gt;3,141 counties and county equivalents&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing that you will have to keep in mind is cost because the more you spend on basics (IE. website, lists, and services) the more you will have to raise before you can spend on advocacy. So it is best to start locally and grow from there, but no matter what the scale of the organization is you will first need is a Website to be your digital outreach base for your political or advocacy campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-up-and-running&quot;&gt;Getting Up and Running&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that you will need is a website to bass your digital campaign outreach from. The website doesn’t have to be complicated it can be a simple static website hosted for free by &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, but should &lt;strong&gt;include email sign up, donate, and a blog for your content&lt;/strong&gt;. It will also help if you familiarize yourself with a Spread Sheet program because this will be how you will organize your data (. IE volunteers, social media IDs, donor records) at the beginning of your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;thing-to-keep-in-mind&quot;&gt;Thing to Keep in Mind&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it may seem easier to use an all-in one system like NationBuilder the problem is that most of the tools are ad-ones, and the ones that aren’t have free equivalents like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meshfire.com/&quot;&gt;MeshFire&lt;/a&gt; for social media listening tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing to keep in mind is that pivot tables are a strong tool that are included in spreadsheet programs and can handle the volume of data you will have at the beginning. So make sure that you know the full cost before you start with an all-in one service because it can add unnecessary cost to you campaign in the early stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-one&quot;&gt;Step One&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very first thing you will need to do is obtain a &lt;a href=&quot;../domain-name/&quot;&gt;domain name&lt;/a&gt; the best place to start is &lt;a href=&quot;http://domains.google/&quot;&gt;Google Domain&lt;/a&gt; because places like GoDaddy will buy the domain name that you search for through their website forcing you to use them. &lt;strong&gt;Once you have the domain name make sure to claim it on every social media account&lt;/strong&gt; from Facebook to GitHub any anything else you can think of. This step is to make sure that people don’t assume your organization identity on a platform you don’t use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;website-basics&quot;&gt;Website Basics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic cost of a website depends on how much you are willing to do yourself. The cheapest option will be creating a static website for the landing page, and use a Static Site Generator like &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to maintain a blog. While this way is by far the cheapest you will need to know how to build a simple website, and be able to integrate some third party services. Another option is to use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; site. The biggest benefit of this solution is that you don’t need to know anything about a website. This is because every web host has 1 click WordPress set-up, and there is plenty of theme market place like &lt;a href=&quot;http://themeforest.net/&quot;&gt;Themeforest&lt;/a&gt; that have non-for profit and campaign web themes. The biggest problem is cost because while you can host a WordPress site for $5 per month it will crash the moment you go viral, and the only way to avoid the problem is to spend any where from $50 to $250 a month on hosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../website-platform/&quot;&gt;Read more about website option here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;digital-campaign-strategy-why-you-need-a-blog&quot;&gt;Digital Campaign Strategy (Why You Need a Blog)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until this point we have talked about having a blog, but haven’t really explained why. The reason why you need a blog is very simple it is the best platform for you to get your voice out, because while Facebook, Twitter, Reddit, Instagram, and SnapChat might have more users they limit your content too much and should be as platforms to promote your content from your blog. Great example of this is every digital facing issue advocacy group like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hrc&quot;&gt;Humans Rights Campaign&lt;/a&gt;. This type of blog based strategy is Content Marketing and is one of the main pillars of digital advocacy campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-create-content&quot;&gt;How to Create Content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/220587&quot;&gt;Content Is King&lt;/a&gt; is an often said mantra in digital marketing for good reason. &lt;strong&gt;Quality content will drive traffic&lt;/strong&gt;  and help you create a broader organization narrative beyond your mission statement and about page. For an Online Activist Group and Political and Issue Campaign there a 3 types of content that will help your effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Press Release: Should be short and act as announcements for the Organization, such as fundraising number or upcoming event. While a lot of people will copy the text into twitter it is better to link to it with a twitter card, and retweet it multiply time through the day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Technical: Are either research, or policy on your issue. While reporting on other research or policy initiatives is ok. It is better for you to do original work, which is often a key component to this type of content getting shared.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Narrative: This is a personal story that talks about the effects of not acting on your issue, and should try to create an emotional connection with an uplifting ending.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Consumer psychologist Dr Brent Coker from the University of Melbourne has identified four key elements present in viral videos, and revealed four common factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Shareability’ on social media. The video content must make the sharer look good to their peers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Viewers must be able to connect to the content. Activating memories via music and nostalgia are key to getting the audience to connect to the video.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Large emotional range. Clips that quickly take the viewer from an emotional low (sadness or unfairness) to an emotional high (joy, love or justice) are more likely to go viral.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;‘Frisson’ or primitive feeling of excitement or thrill. There is often a physical response to a viral video, hairs standing on the back of the neck and goosebumps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Source &lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/news/2016-03-recipe-video-viralresearch-key-ingredients.html&quot;&gt;phys.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the 4 points look at video the first can easily be applied to blogs and depending on what social media platforms you use videos are always an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-content-local&quot;&gt;Keep Content Local&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have decided to keep your effort locally then you will need to make sure that your content is local also. This means focusing less on national news and more about local councils. By writing local you are letting search engines know that your activist organization is for a local cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will help the most for what search engines view as local searches some examples of search treated as local are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Where to vote on election day&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When does early voting start&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Where to volunteer&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and while most people have seen Google answer these questions throughout the Presidential Election they still don’t cover municipal and special elections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;social-media&quot;&gt;Social media&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look at what social media platforms to use it is &lt;strong&gt;best to use Facebook plus one other&lt;/strong&gt; to start with, but don’t forget to register your name for every social media platform so no can take it. The major reason for using only 2 platforms to start with is because it is better to do Facebook and SnapChat well compared to be on Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, interest, SnapChat, YouTube, and LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main purpose for using &lt;strong&gt;social media is to engage with your supporters&lt;/strong&gt; and help your campaign disseminate content from your blog. The best way to do that is to reach out to influencers to share your content with their larger following with the hope they follow your account. The &lt;strong&gt;key goal is to drive traffic to your site&lt;/strong&gt; so the user completes an action like to donate or sign-up for a newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;warning-about-twitter&quot;&gt;Warning About Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter is one of the best platforms and might have more reach than Facebook given how content can go viral much quicker, and can spread outside of a group more easily. That being said, you are more likely to face trolls and bot driven harassment. When you choose a platform make sure that you have a well thought out &lt;a href=&quot;../social-media-policy/&quot;&gt;social media policy&lt;/a&gt; because on Twitter not knowing who to respond to and how to respond can lead you to causing your problems, and alienating support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;digital-fundraising&quot;&gt;Digital Fundraising&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you start fundraising make sure that you are following your state laws for issue and political organizations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main tool for digital fundraising will be your email list. While most people think it is social media that assumption is wrong. The ALS Association Ice Bucket Challenge went viral it was the exception most campaigns &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/alltechconsidered/2015/12/02/458008461/a-click-too-far-why-social-media-isnt-that-great-for-fundraising&quot;&gt;2% of their donation referrals&lt;/a&gt; from social media. The best online examples fundraising through emails are President Donald Trump and Senator Bernie Sanders shows how strong it can be. The key takeaway from both of their campaigns are that you should &lt;strong&gt;ask often and create a sense of urgency&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../digital-fundraising-part-1/&quot;&gt;Introduction to Digital Fundraising&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../intro-to-poltical-action-committes/&quot;&gt;Starting a Political Action Committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;putting-all-together&quot;&gt;Putting All Together&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With your campaign website and social media accounts up and running the last step you will have to do is put it all together. This means that you should start working on content to populate your advocacy site, and try to schedule a set number of post and tweets each week. You will also have to start with your social media outreach to influencers to help get your content to the right people to grow your following in a meaningful way. &lt;strong&gt;Make sure you set clear and achievable goal&lt;/strong&gt; so that you measure the success of each action so you know what works best for your advocacy organization.&lt;/p&gt;
 Seen First on href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/starting-activist-group/?utm_source=rss</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/starting-activist-group/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
