<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Roots</title>
    <description>Engaging activistes and voter through cutting endge digitial and grassroots stratiegies. That deliver the hard fought elections &lt;p&gt;seen first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://digitalroots.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 22:16:25 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 22:16:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Twitterbots and Campaigns</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With social media proving itself to be worth an investment and integration at the start of a campaign, there are still a lot of decisions that a campaign will have to make that go beyond a &lt;a href=&quot;../social-media-policy/&quot;&gt;social media policy and strategy&lt;/a&gt;. The decisions that go beyond strategy and policy include paid vs organic outreach and whether or not you are going to use a beats to help you with your online presence, which recent research has shown can have a meaningful effect even in some of the largest campaigns. Philip Howard, Professor of Internet Studies at the Oxford Internet Institute, comments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘We can’t say who was behind the highly automated pro-Trump accounts but they were purposeful, thoughtful and deliberate about when to release messages, what those messages should be, and what their targets were. We found similarities in the rhythm of the pro-Trump Twitter campaign and that successfully employed by the Leave campaign in the run up to the EU referendum in the UK.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A USC study has also shown the scale of these bots:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The researchers found that Twitter bot accounts produced 3.8 million tweets, or 19 percent of all election tweets for the study’s period. Social bots also accounted for 400,000 of the 2.8 million individual users tweeting about the election, or nearly 15 percent of the population under study.&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The USC study goes further than just the presence of bots and looks at the sentiment of each message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;on a scale ranging from minus 4 (maximum negativity) to plus 4 (maximum positivity), generated by both bot and human tweets during this time. Both human and bot tweets about Trump were almost uniformly positive when compared to those about Clinton, which were equally neutral and positive.&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though President-Elect Donald Trump was having a large amount of negative news in print and on television it seems that having a uniformly positive message on twitter. This helped balance the message that was being driven offline, and in contrast, Hillary Clinton had a twitter army that was a lot more balanced. The difference here can create a stark difference given bits are a large driver of online discussion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bots produce content automatically, and therefore at a very fast and continuous rate. That means they form consistent and pervasive parts of the online discussion throughout the campaign. As a result, they were able to build significant influence, collecting large numbers of followers and having their tweets retweeted by thousands of humans.&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The constant presence along with a large number of followers is what gives beats the ability to be empowered by the “illusory truth effect”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Psychological research, including my own, shows that repeated exposure to false information can change people’s beliefs that is it true. This phenomenon is called the “illusory truth effect.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This effect happens to us all – including people who know the truth. Our research suggests that even people who knew Pope Francis made no presidential endorsement would be susceptible to believing a “Pope endorses Trump” headline when they had seen it multiple times. &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While twitter bots have been attributed in having an effect on an election, there still isn’t much data to know if there is any real impact, but thanks to the Python Library &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/esdalmaijer/markovbot&quot;&gt;Markovbot&lt;/a&gt; it is possible to set-up and try for both local and state based races. The only things you keep in mind are:
1. What kind of bot will do(ie. retweet, post new content, respond other members)
2. what will be your keywords, target string an conversation depth
3. When will it start and stop&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you set the twitter bolt upright and make sure they have a positive and promoting message for the candidate or organization, then it will have the best opponent to have an impact on the election,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;http://phys.org/news/2016-12-pro-trump-bot-colonised-pro-clinton-twitter.html&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;http://news.usc.edu/110565/rigged-usc-study-finds-many-political-tweets-come-from-fake-accounts/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;http://phys.org/news/2016-11-twitter-bots-affected-presidential-campaign.html&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;http://phys.org/news/2016-12-unbelievable-news-true.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;seen first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/twitter-bot-campaign/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/twitter-bot-campaign/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volunteer Relations System</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Volunteers are the life blood or non-for profits, campaigns, and political parties, and while where and how you recruit them is important keeping motivated and involved not just through the campaign, but in between is important to making sure hat you have the support to make the calls and knock the doors to win. Here at Digitalroots has written about how to &lt;a href=&quot;../blog/recruit/&quot;&gt;identify and manage volunteer&lt;/a&gt;, but we have never talked about how to build a system that will help you retain first time volunteers and keep them through the winter and off cycle slumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-case-for-a-program&quot;&gt;The Case for a Program&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When maintaining volunteers there are a number of challenges that every organization faces:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reducing ‘churn’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engaging or growing current volunteering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increasing loyalty to the organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These issues are best faced with a loyalty program because there are a number of advantages over the average volunteers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stay active over a long period of time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More likely to suggest people volunteers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spend more time volunteering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-building-the-system&quot;&gt;How to Building the System&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While each system will be different in a number of key ways there are some rules of thumbs to make sure that the program is successful. The key parts are broken down into the key element of every loyalty program and the mechanics that make the program function on a day to day basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;loyalty-levers&quot;&gt;Loyalty Levers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;rewards&quot;&gt;Rewards&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rewards are the backbone of the system and can be the most difficult. The rewards can be done in a few ways, but they revolve around accumulating points so that you can receive an award. The points system can be a as simple as receiving the reward after you reach a certain number of points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of this is Duncan Donuts were once you acquire 200 points you are automatically issued a coupon for a free drink. Or as complicated as the ones most hotel use where you can exchange points like cash for food drinks and discount rooms. Unlike Duncan Donuts these systems allow for greater choice for the user, and create a more customized experience through the different services. The tradeoff for these systems is that changing the system can cause a friction point with your supporters making it harder to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;recognition&quot;&gt;Recognition&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognition is what keeps people engaged in the program this is because it allow the individual to feel like they are making progress by reaching new levels or gathering badges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognition though isn’t just a statics it also has to come with benefits that are more constant rather than one time. One of the most common examples is when loyalty program members get a preferred customer hotline. For some organization, it could be an extended early bird special for events and fundraisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;relevance&quot;&gt;Relevance&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relevance is what will help you get new members to join the program. This is by far one of the most important parts of the program because using the program can quickly become irrelevant if you can’t gain and active members that will use your loyalty program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest friction points are the forms to sign-up are too long and ask for for more information then need to start. The thing to remember is that you can always get more information from a member once they are active. The other fiction point of relevance is the rewards while it can be easy to avoid on simpler systems more complex ones will have to figure out what members what and what is relevant to the as their status and use of the program goes up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;different-kinds-of-loyalty&quot;&gt;Different Kinds of Loyalty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mercenary&lt;/strong&gt; - were they are only loyal because it is the best offer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inertia&lt;/strong&gt; - were they stay in the program because they have already invest money or time(IE. money on a loyalty card)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;True&lt;/strong&gt; - were they believe in the organization and don’t need to be incentivize to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most volunteers will get involved because they fall under true loyalty, but because there are often multiple organizations that advocate for similar issues we need to create inertia loyalty to try to get volunteers to prioritize our efforts over those of allied organizations, and give them a reason to stay on board after the first event (reduce churn).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;basic-part-to-a-program&quot;&gt;Basic Part to a Program&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 4 basic parts to every loyalty program, which are the currency, status, enrollment &amp;amp; activation, and partnerships. While most organizations have national, local, and state chapters the ability to do partnerships are limited because of the risk of sharing a volunteer list and the different laws. That is why it is best for organization with multiple levels of organizations should run the program at the state level and allow local branches to join the statewide program directly rather than working in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Currency (Points) - This is the most significant decision in creating a loyalty program, and is the major supporter of the loyalty lever Reward. The two parts that need to be addressed is the member and organization side:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Decisions that effect Members:&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;How can the currency be earned: It could be for social media activity or for canvassing and phone banking.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;How easy the process is to use them: Does the reward automatically trigger once reaching a certain value or does the person have to spend them.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;What is the value of the rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Decisions that effect Organization:&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Breakage: ‘points’ earned by volunteers but are never used, typically stated as a percentage of the total.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Administrative Cost: annual costs associated with maintaining, and growing the program.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Reward Cost: financial value of any program award that a consumer receives and uses&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Status - is especially important element of a loyalty program because it creates value beyond the points system and supports the loyalty lever Recognition:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Statues have to mean something: That means the there should a desirable benefit for these “special volunteers”, and should be a continuing benefit unlike currency benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Enrollment &amp;amp; Activation - All programs start with enrolling (acquiring) and activating (on-boarding) a new member done well it will support the loyalty lever Relevance. The key points are:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Make the process simple&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Minimize the information that is “required”&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Enable enrollment to happen across many channels.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tell them only what they need to get started&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tracking-key-performance-indicators-kpi&quot;&gt;Tracking Key Performance Indicators (KPI)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest difference between private business and non-for profits is the KPIs. In business it is based around how much more a member spends. For non-for profits they could use a program for donations, but it would be better at attracting retaining and mobilizing voters. So the KPIs should be based events, voter contact, and volunteer referred rather than a monetary value or social media engagement (IE. reviews and generated content).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting your KPIs to focus on volunteers will have a larger return because investing in a grassroots program can be a time consuming and labor intensive effort. With a loyalty system is is well built you can reduce voluntary churn between election, allowing you to start more aggressively and spend more time growing from last year progress rather than rebuilding last year team.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;seen first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/volunteer-system/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/volunteer-system/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quick Start SEO Checklist</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Search Engine Optimization(SEO) is a broad field with technical and creative part. This is a basic check list that should be used to make sure you have done the bare minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-pagetechnical&quot;&gt;On-Page/Technical&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On-Page and Technical side of SEO is the part that you can do right away, and can be broken down into code and keywords. The basic checklist for On-Page and Technical SEO are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;check your &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/SEO-Basics&quot;&gt;robots.txt&lt;/a&gt; it should be clear if it looks like this:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;user-agent: *&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Disallow: /&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;this tells search engines to ignore your site so the first thing to is remove, remove the backslash (/)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;make sure that you don’t have meat name=”robots” &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;content=&quot;noindex&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; [content value can be anything else] (/blog/robots) but &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;content=&quot;noindex&quot;&lt;/code&gt; tell search engines not to index just like robot.txt&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure that there is no 404 pages with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/webmasters/&quot;&gt;search console&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.screamingfrog.co.uk/seo-spider/&quot;&gt;Screaming Frog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Title tags should be structured (page title&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;brand name)&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;URLs should use hyphens( - ) over underscore( _ ) for spaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;markup-and-speed&quot;&gt;Markup and Speed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Page speed is one of the most important parts of a website because studies have shown that most users won’t wait more than 4 seconds. Markup also helps a site have a better social media precinct because of image cards on Facebook and Twitter, and you need schema mark-up for Google Snippets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hide-show-1&quot;&gt;Read More &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;hide-show-1&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;Markup_and_Structure_Data_0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Markup and Structure Data&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;go through &lt;a href=&quot;http://schema.org/&quot;&gt;scheme.org&lt;/a&gt;, and make sure that you are using proper tags&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seoskeptic.com/json-ld-big-day-at-google/&quot;&gt;Google seems to prefer JSON-LD&lt;/a&gt; ,but has said they won’t prioritize one over the other&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at APIs to see what you should use (IE. Pinterest need microdata if you have multiple objects on a page)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that there is an image on the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This makes sure that all posts and tweets are fat finger friendly and will stand out in the fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If available use tester to make sure that they are working properly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;Optimizing_for_Speed_14&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Optimizing for Speed&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that you use appropriate image size to reduce load time. There is also &lt;code&gt;scrset&lt;/code&gt; that allows for a better responsive images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use GZip to compress files&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This can be done in the .htaccess file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minify your files(IE. CSS, JS, HTML)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a Content Deliver System like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure if you use a platform like Wordpress you take the necessary steps to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wpbeginner.com/common-wordpress-errors-and-how-to-fix-them/&quot;&gt;avoid any problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ContentOffPage_28&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Content/Off-Page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;content should be above 300 words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is no hard rule for this, but content with 1700 to 3000 words seems to do the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post around 300 words also ranks well, but they are more time sensitive (IE. breaking news)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that you have outbound link. They act like citations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/Social-Media-Tracker&quot;&gt;content tools&lt;/a&gt; like &lt;a href=&quot;http://buzzsumo.com/&quot;&gt;Buzzsumo&lt;/a&gt; to see what content from a sit or on a subject is being shared and where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;Outreach_40&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Outreach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google use links and social media are a measure of popularity and there are a number of things you can do the focus on your social media platform and the links you have going to your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;Backlinks_44&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Backlinks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure if you are a chapter or branch of an organization that you have both outbound links (links going to them) and inbound links (links gong for you).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out to news site that have done articles for you and try to get backlinks from them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;seen first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/seo-checklist/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/seo-checklist/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maryland GOP | Site Audit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With 2016 over and 2018 being more crucial for Republicans in Maryland than ever I though it might be a good time to go through the Maryland GOP and Local GOP Clubs to see how their digital footprint looks. To start off I though I would take a look at the Maryland State Party Website. Each audit will limited, due to the lack of access to Google Analytics and Search Console, to the landing page and contain 5 parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accessibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Indexability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On-Page Ranking Factors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Off-Page Ranking Factors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Competitive Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;maryland-republican-party---seo-audit&quot;&gt;Maryland Republican Party - SEO Audit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;accessibility&quot;&gt;Accessibility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mdgop.org/&quot;&gt;Maryland Republican Party&lt;/a&gt; has done the worst possible thing you can do for Search Engine Optimization and the is having your &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/robots/&quot;&gt;robot.txt&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;User-Angent: *

Disallow: /
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is telling all crawlers that they are not allowed on the site which keep Search Engines from indexing any pages. In the case of mdgop.org they still index for exact search words and phrases because of sites linking back to it, but it is for from ideal. Beyond that, things start to look better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site seems to be fine there are no Robots Meta Tags, but because of the robots.txt the site that is index is a 404 error page. Also, they seem to have XML Sitemap, but don’t have it at in the footer. This is something that should be added because Google recommends it. They do avoid using Flash and JavaScript Navigation, which help the Crawlability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site architecture and performance is another mix bag. While the site architecture is simple and allows for easy access the site take a little over 4 seconds to load which &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kissmetrics.com/loading-time/&quot;&gt;can cause problems&lt;/a&gt; they should enable compression, use browser caching, and minify files. On the mobile site they need to increase the size of social links so that they are fat finger friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;indexability&quot;&gt;Indexability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;site-and-page-search&quot;&gt;Site and Page search&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/robots/&quot;&gt;robots.txt&lt;/a&gt; mdgop.org does index and has a reported 169 pages indexed, and on mdgop.org page search it shows up in position number one, but no other page shows up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;brand-search&quot;&gt;Brand Search&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These searches seem to have had a major effect from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/robots/&quot;&gt;robots.txt&lt;/a&gt; because the only mdgop domain that showed when I searched Maryland Republican Party, Maryland GOP and mdgop was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mdgop.org/site/lookup.asp?c=9sILJXMCLdJ0H&amp;amp;b=5916197&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;mdgop.com&lt;/a&gt; which was in position 5, 8 and 1 respectively but both lead to a 404 pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/img/MDGOP-SERP-Maryland-Republican-Party.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of Google SERP for Maryland Republican Party&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, because of Google My Business the Maryland Republican Party does show up on the right in the knowledge panel, but only when you search Maryland Republican Party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-page-ranking-factors&quot;&gt;On-Page Ranking Factors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;urls&quot;&gt;URLs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mdgop.org&quot;&gt;Maryland Republican Party&lt;/a&gt; site has a good url that contains relevant keywords, are short and user friendly, and avoids the most common problems with urls, but should use hyphens( - ) instead of underscores( _ ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;Content&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Maryland Republican Party has regular post, but are lacking in length and have no keywords. Maryland GOP could try to use narrative post about what the party is currently doing in the community and have volunteers talk about how they got involved with the party. They could also answer questions “like where do I vote” and “how to run for office”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;keywords&quot;&gt;Keywords&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current Top 5 Keywords by traffic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Keyword&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Percent of Search Traffic&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1. republican convention&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;44.97%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2. maryland republican party&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;15.46%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3. maryland gop&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;5.75%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4. maryland republican primary&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;4.53%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5. maryland republican delegates&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;4.31%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They seem to only be getting traffic from republican subject queries this likely means that they are only drawing in republican voters though search and should try to answer election questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For ranking with keywords the most important measures are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drumbeatmarketing.net/marketing-blog/what-is-page-authority&quot;&gt;Page Authority(PA)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shoutmeloud.com/domain-authority.html&quot;&gt;Domain Authority(DA)&lt;/a&gt; mdgop.org is PA: 55/100 DA: 46/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOP: Volume 300k - 1.5m Difficulty 83 Opportunity 64 Potential 80&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top 3 sites PA was between 49 - 86 and DA were between 84 - 100 for GOP making it hard to make meaningful gains, and because Google views it as a national keyword trying to use local key-phrases isn’t possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where to vote: Volume 11.5k - 30.3l Difficulty 70 Opportunity 52 Potential 67&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top 3 sites PA was 60 -71 and DA 57 - 75, but Google treats this a a local search to some degree so while it may be hard to rank nationally if they continue down the local search path it will  be one of the easer key-phrases to rank with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where to vote in Maryland: Volume 101 - 200 Difficulty 38 Opportunity 46 Potential&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The  top 3 site are the same without Maryland added. With Google looking at their query as a local search more this key-phrase will help you with local SEO, and during midterms the election is more likely to drive local searches over nation ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Republican Beliefs : Volume 4.3k - 6.5k Difficulty 31 Opportunity 64 Potential 72&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top sites Page Authority was between 24 - 25 and Domain Authority was between 22 - 36 for Republican Beliefs and while it has much less volume the ability to rank well for this keyword. It also is a keyword that will fit in naturally with narrative content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;html-markuphttpwwwdigitalrootsioblogseo-basics&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io/blog/SEO-Basics&quot;&gt;HTML Markup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Maryland Republican Party’s HTML Markup is lacking in a number of areas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;title-tag&quot;&gt;Title Tag&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;The Maryland Republican Party’s site has a good title tag, and uses the proper format they might want to replace the dash (-) with a vertical bar (&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;).&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;meta-description&quot;&gt;Meta Description&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They are lacking any Meta Description on all of their pages. One thing that they can add is a general description of each page, and what can be found on it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;other-head-tags&quot;&gt;Other &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; Tags&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The rest of head&amp;gt; section seems to be in good shape with the exception of the social media tags. The Facebook tag doesn’t have a picture of the landing page and the description for Facebook is “Joe Cluster, Executive Director of the Maryland Republican Party, was recently appointed to the Maryland House of Delegates and is leaving the Party on December 31, 2016. The MDGOP is..” because the ‘og: description’ property should be explicitly provided. For twitter the description is blank causing a similar problem to Facebook and has no picture, which means that they are losing out on making their tweets more fat finger friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;image&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Images has no ALT text this is a huge problem. The best ALT text for the landing page image is “Maryland Republican Governor Larry Hogan Greets excited crowd “. Also try to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;scrset&lt;/code&gt; to help with load times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;other-body-tags&quot;&gt;Other Body Tags&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Join Governor Larry Hogan &amp;amp; the Maryland Republican Party to change Maryland for the better!” should be in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag.
Also they should remove the commit above the header due to Internet Explorer, along with removing the end tag &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/form&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; that has no open element, and the unclosed element &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;off-page-ranking-factors&quot;&gt;Off-Page Ranking Factors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the off-page factors are defiantly the strongest part of the website. It has high quality back links from newspapers and government sites, and lacks any spam quality links. The one suggestion I would give them is that try to reach out to influences both locally and nationally through social media. Also, they need to start to focus on Key Performance Indicators like email sign up or RSVP for an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;competitive-analysis-mddemsorg&quot;&gt;Competitive Analysis (mddems.org)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final peace of the Site Audit is to look at Maryland Republican Party main competitor Maryland Democratic Party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top 5 Keywords by traffic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Keyword&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Percent of Search Traffic&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1. maryland voter registration&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;15.42%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2. maryland democratic party&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;13.53%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3. md party&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;8.27%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4. democratic party website&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;5.10%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5. maryland democratic delegates&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3.93%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their keywords seem to be border, and 2 of the keywords are generic searches with Maryland voter registration being their best performing. This is a keyword that the MD GOP should target because it is a basic search for new voters that could be more persuadable. In terms of backlink opportunities there seems to not be any given they are earning them through affiliate organizations and news stories. That being said linking with other GOP groups is something that could benefit The Republicans site.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;seen first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/mdgop-seo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/mdgop-seo/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Campaign Social Media Strategy</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-social-media-strategy&quot;&gt;What is a Social Media Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Social Media Strategy is becoming a critical part of every political and non-for profits strategy, and unlike other digital strategies your social media strategy is built with a framework and general policy. The first part is the Strategy that will act like a framework that will lay out your key performance indicators (KPI) and the general direction that it will take (IE. platform and activities). The other part is policy and will be the guidelines that will help you adapt you strategy to changing environments on each platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;social-media-policy&quot;&gt;Social Media Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Social Media Policy is by far the most important part of your Social Media Plan because it will be what fills in the strategy, and gives you direction when the unexpected happens. There are three basic points to cover in your Social Media Policy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you respond to people on social media
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The most common way to handle this is to not respond to people on social media because they are most likely to be trolls.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you do respond to people on social media it is best to try to get them off of social media. To do this you can direct them to a press release or direct message them, but you should have guidelines that focus on how fast you respond to people on social media and what type of message do you respond to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How do you use social media (IE. Repost of campaign material or social media exclusive media). There are pros and cons of both of them, and each campaign will have to decide which one will achieve their goal&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How does you staff handle their own social media.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The one point you should always have is that staffers don’t talk about internal information (IE. voter contact number and canvassing location)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The other one that can be important is what they post about politics in general. The rule of thumb here is for staffers to only post what their boss post.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;social-media-strategy&quot;&gt;Social Media Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Media Strategy has 6 different angles in which you can use social media:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reach: Social media helps politicians more effectively reach large numbers of voters in a short amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Engagement: Unlike television, radio, and direct mailers, social media allows politicians to actively engage with their potential voters.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Share Ideas &amp;amp; Goals: Social media allows politicians to share their beliefs, goals, and accomplishments directly with voters, making them feel more directly involved with the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behind-the-Scenes: Social media allows politicians to give their supporters a behind-the-scenes view of their campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Turn Digital Followers into Votes: It is one thing to build a large, digital following. It is another to turn those followers into votes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Analytics: Social media allows political campaigns to more easily track engagement. “We now track every mention of a Senator, House Representative, or Governor,” said Zachary Green, CEO of 140Elect.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sample-social-media-policy--strategy&quot;&gt;Sample Social Media Policy / Strategy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;social-media-policy-1&quot;&gt;Social Media Policy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address the fast-changing landscape of the Internet and the way voters communicate and obtain information online. &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; departments my consider using social media tools to reach a broader audience. The &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; encourages the use of social media to increase our out reach to communities, where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; has an overriding interest and expectation in deciding what is “spoken” on behalf of the organization on media sites. This policy establishes guidelines the use of personal social media accounts, and official accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; social media related accounts will be subject to approval by office of the communications director&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; website (example.com, example.org, etc.) will remain the organizations primary and predominate internet presences&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The best, most appropriate &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; use of social media fall into two categories:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;As a way to disseminate time-sensitive information as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;As a way to promote an event and encourage followers and supporters engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wherever possible, content posted to &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; social media accounts will also be available on the main website of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wherever possible, content posted on social media should link back to the  &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; main website for in-depth information, forms, or documents.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quality question that are asked through social media will be respond to with in 24 hours through on or off line channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A Quality question is a question that’s about up coming events like time and place, or are about clarifying a statement or position.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Poor quality question are accusatory and inflammatory, and will often look to attack your views and start a argument.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All new social media tools proposed for &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; use will be approved by the office of the Technology/Digital Director and the appropriate department’s public information authority.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; will whenever necessary will replace any removed content with an explanation of why it was removed and step that have been taken to avoid similar events.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; reserves the right to restrict or remove any content that is deemed in violation of this social media policy from staff accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Case studies
  There is no privacy on the Web.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Imagine, if you will, an NPR legal correspondent named Sue Zemencourt. She’s a huge fan of Enormous University’s basketball team and loves to chat online about EU. She posts comments on blogs under the screen name “enormous1.” One day, an equally rabid fan of Gigormous State (“gigormous1”) posts obnoxious comments about EU.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Sue snaps. Expletives and insults fly from her fingers on to the webpage. They’re so out-of-line that the blog blocks her from submitting any more comments — and discovers that her i.p. address leads back to NPR. The blog’s host posts that “someone at NPR is using language that the FCC definitely would not approve of” and describes what was said. Things go viral.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The basically good person that she is, Sue publicly acknowledges and apologizes for her mistake. But that doesn’t stop The Daily Show from  satirizing about the “NPRNormous Explosion.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Damage done.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Be circumspect about your behavior, even when the exchange feels private or anonymous. Even an email to a trusted recipient can be made public, with or without the recipient’s knowledge or consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Staff should avoid posting partisan political material. They shouldn’t just spread information they should be careful and skeptical.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Staff shouldn’t comment on issues that &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; are involved in, and any questions about &lt;strong&gt;[ORGANIZATION]&lt;/strong&gt; should be directed to the communication department or website.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Self-protection is part of being accountable online. Make sure that you use two stage authentication and strong passwords with all social media accounts&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;social-media-strategy-1&quot;&gt;Social Media Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Media Strategy will be used to target 18-35 year olds thought multiple social platforms. When ever possible create and maintain a open community, and to disseminate information as quickly as possible. The primary goal is to help organize supporters and reach out to hard to reach groups through fan pages, hashtags, and sub reddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platforms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reddit: have an on going AMA(Ask Me Anything) to direct question on other platform, and have schedule time for both staff and politician. Allow for volunteer to form a community, and to create and give input about blitz days and other campaign events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter: use Twitter as a new rss feed for new site content and press release. Try to get any interaction to the Website or Reddit whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook: use it as a portal for the website, but keep it up to date with pictures unique to the site and recent events and a current event list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tactics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create 2 blog post a week that talk about what the campaign has been up to (IE. events, press mentions, endorsements, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create infographic once a month on issues that are most important to online audience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use listening tools to monitor keywords and content sediment(negative, neutral, or positive)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;create hashtags for major event like Blitz Days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Performance Indicators (KPI)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main KPI: Will be sign-ups to email list to stay up to date on volunteer, and campaign events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondary KIP:
- Share and Upvotes(5+ will create a backlink)
- Increase of inbound traffic to main site&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one KPI that you should never use is number of users this is because followers have no value if they don’t engage with the campaign through sharing commenting or signing-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;influencers&quot;&gt;Influencers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An influencer is is a member of a community that can help you spread your brand and gain you meaningful followers that will help your KPIs. There are several tools to help you find them and they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://buzzsumo.com&quot;&gt;Buzzsumo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://keyhole.co/&quot;&gt;Keyhole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://meshfire.com&quot;&gt;Meshfire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALL&lt;/strong&gt; Have a free unlimited option that is some what limited, but are some of the best options out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Media Strategies aren’t like any other strategy you will have for your campaign because of the flex able nature of social media platforms. That is why you should always have a clear list of rules and ethics that will guide you through every situation while making sure that you have clear, measurable, and meaningful goals for your social media strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;seen first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/social-media-policy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/social-media-policy/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Complete Robot Tag Guide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Meta robots tags have been around for a while. During that time thought Search engines not only have slowly been adding features to them, but they have also expanded beyond the meta tag and robots.txt. This page lists an overview of all the different values you can use in your tag. The official syntax of the meta robot tag:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;value1, value2&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;which-search-engine-support-which-meat-tags-values&quot;&gt;Which Search Engine Support Which Meat Tags Values&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While robots is the most common because it targets all the search engines you can also target each one individually &lt;strong&gt;Warning They Will Not Override Robots Value&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Search&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Robots&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;:——–:&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;:———:&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Google&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;GOOGLEBOT&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yahoo!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SLURP&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MSN/Live&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MSNBOT&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ask&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TEOMA&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;list-of-all-the-robots-meta-values&quot;&gt;List of All the Robots Meta Values&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Robots value&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yahoo!&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;MSN / Live&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Ask&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;index&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;noindex&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;none&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Doubt&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Doubt&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;follow&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Doubt&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Doubt&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;nofollow&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;noarchive&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;nocache&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;nosnippet&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;noodp&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;noydir&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No use&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No use&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No use&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;notranslate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;noimageindex&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;unavailable_after: [RFC-850 date/time]&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-each-meta-robots-meta-value-do&quot;&gt;What each Meta Robots Meta Value do&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are no restrictions for indexing or serving. Note: this directive is the default value and has no effect if explicitly listed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow search engines robots to index the page, you don’t have to add this to your pages, as it’s the default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;noindex&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not show this page in search results and do not show a “Cached” link in search results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;follow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tells the search engines robots to follow the links on the page, whether it can index it or not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nofollow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not follow the links on this page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Equivalent to noindex, nofollow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;noarchive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not show a “Cached” link in search results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nocache&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Same as noarchive, but only used by MSN/Live.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nosnippet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not show a snippet in the search results for this page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;noodp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not use metadata from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://dmoz.org/&quot;&gt;Open Directory project&lt;/a&gt; for titles or snippets shown for this page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;notranslate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not offer translation of this page in search results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;noimageindex&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not index images on this page, but id the image is linked to directly from elsewhere Google will still index them, so using an X-Robot-Tag HTTP header is better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;unavailable_after: [RFC-850 date/time]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not show this page in search results after the specified date/time. The date/time must be specified in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc0850.txt&quot;&gt;RFC 850 format&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;complete-list-of-google-bots&quot;&gt;Complete List of Google Bots&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Crawler&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Robot Value&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;————————————————————————————————-&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;—————————————————&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Googlebot (Google Web search)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Googlebot&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Googlebot News&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Googlebot-News,(Googlebot)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Googlebot Images&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Googlebot-Image,(Googlebot)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Googlebot Video&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Googlebot-Video,(Googlebot)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Google Smartphone&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Googlebot&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Google Mobile AdSense&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mediapartners-Google,Mediapartners,(Googlebot)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Google AdSense&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mediapartners-Google,Mediapartners,(Googlebot)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Google AdsBot landing page quality check&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AdsBot-Google&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Google app crawler,(Used to fetch resources for mobile apps, obeys AdsBot-Google robots rules.)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AdsBot-Google-Mobile-Apps&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.com/2007/03/using-robots-meta-tag.html&quot;&gt;Google did a blogpost on the Google Webmaster Central Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bing.com/webmaster/help/which-robots-metatags-does-bing-support-5198d240&quot;&gt;Bing has a webmaster help page for it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://help.yandex.com/webmaster/controlling-robot/html.xml&quot;&gt;Yandex has a help page for HTML meta tags.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;seen first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/robots/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/robots/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SEO Crash Course for Beginners</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-seo&quot;&gt;What Is SEO&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how Google decides which websites show up at the top of the Search Engine Results Page (SERP) well it is based on of a number of algorithms based off of rank, and optimizing a website is what Search Engine Optimizing (SEO) does through strategies, tactics and techniques. While it might sound simple &lt;strong&gt;Google has over 400 updates a year&lt;/strong&gt; and research and testing are the only ways to stay on top of these updates. There is also the need to understand user intent, though keywords so you can have your content reach your audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To but it simply the SERP is like an iTunes chart of the internet, websites rank higher on the search engines dependent on how ‘good they are’ and SEO is the practice of making them get up there. So when some one searches for “volunteering in my area” the most popular site will be first. SEO tries to get your content above the fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making sure the right people find you&lt;/strong&gt; at the right time is what SEO is really all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reason-why-you-need-seo&quot;&gt;Reason Why You Need SEO&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imforza.com/blog/8-seo-stats-that-are-hard-to-ignore/&quot;&gt;93% of all online experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; start with search engines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mediapost.com/publications/article/233459/organic-search-drives-51-of-traffic-paid-search.html&quot;&gt;51% of traffic to business&lt;/a&gt; websites comes from organic search results. Paid search ads only accounted for 10% of traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SEO outranks PPC ads, social media marketing and email marketing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/steveolenski/2014/03/26/7-reasons-why-your-business-should-invest-in-seo/#196117661337&quot;&gt;when it comes to ROI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The top organic search result gets &lt;a href=&quot;https://chitika.com/google-positioning-value&quot;&gt;33% of organic traffic&lt;/a&gt;, while only 10% of users make it past the first page of Google.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So search optimization is really important reaching your audience, and getting them to your site. More importantly though it is what the top site on the internet are doing, and something that will give you an edge and another channel to reach your audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started-with-seo&quot;&gt;Getting Started With SEO&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you should do is google your site to make sure all the pages are indexed. To do this &lt;strong&gt;search site:yoursite.com&lt;/strong&gt; and it will show which pages are indexed. Depending on your results there are some simple steps to make sure that every page get indexed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;make-sure-that-google-analytics-ga-and-search-console-are-set-up&quot;&gt;1. Make sure that Google Analytics (GA) and Search Console are set up&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Analytics and Search Console on its own will not help you index your site, but a number of things that we will be using the console and you should always be &lt;strong&gt;tracking users on your website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;look-at-the-robottxt-file&quot;&gt;2. Look at the robot.txt file&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;most common mistake&lt;/strong&gt; that can be made here is having
  &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
  User-agnet: *
  Disallow: /
 &lt;/code&gt;
  This tells the Search Engine to not crawl your site because &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; means root directory. So by getting rid of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; and using Nonstandard extension &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;allowed:&lt;/code&gt; you will make sure that the search engines will crawl your site.
  &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
  User-agent: *
  Allow: /
  Disallow:
 &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;sitemap&quot;&gt;3. Sitemap&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The first thing that you should do is make sure you have a sitemap in both &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sitemap.html&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sitemap.xml&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sitemap.html&lt;/code&gt; will be added to the footer of each page, while the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sitemap.xml&lt;/code&gt; will be upload in to google search console.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Second, you will upload your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sitemap.html&lt;/code&gt; into &lt;strong&gt;Search Console&lt;/strong&gt; by going to the left hand menu &lt;strong&gt;Crawl &amp;gt; Sitemaps&lt;/strong&gt; in the upper right side there will be a &lt;strong&gt;ADD/TEST Sitemap&lt;/strong&gt; add the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sitemap.xml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;local-indexing&quot;&gt;4. Local Indexing&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This can only be done if you have a physical location&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure that you claim your &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/business/&quot;&gt;Google Business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once you set it up all you need to do is include the following:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add a long, unique description that’s formatted correctly and includes links.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Choose the correct categories for your business.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Upload as many photos as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add a local phone number to your listing.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add your business address that’s consistent with that on your website and local directories.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Upload a high-resolution profile image and cover photo.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add your opening times/days (if relevant)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Include NAP (Name, Address, Phone Number)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Make sure that you have your full NAP across your whole website and it has the same details/format.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;You will also need Local SEO factors that that help with targeting, and will be discussed in &lt;a href=&quot;/#Technical-SEO&quot;&gt;Technical SEO&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/#On-Page-SEO&quot;&gt;On-Page SEO&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there has been a lot to do to just get your website ready for SEO Digital Roots has the experience that will make sure that your content will not have any road blocks on it’s way to your audience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keyword-research&quot;&gt;Keyword Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While getting your website index requires &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;code&lt;/code&gt; make sure it targets your audience is all about content and the keywords that you use. Google is very good at understanding how different word is related thanks to
Latent Semantic Indexing (LSI), which means Google knows flat and apartment are interchangeable. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/6-seo-myths-debunked/&quot;&gt;Despite rumors to the contrary&lt;/a&gt;, keywords are still very much relevant to SEO and picking the right keywords to optimize your site around is a critical part of SEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most common mistakes&lt;/strong&gt; for Digital Marketing also apply to SEO keyword research:
  - Only doing SEO keyword research once
  - Not updating and expand their SEO keyword Lists
  - Only going for the competitive SEO Keywords leaving gains in other areas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing to remember is that Keyword research is an ongoing process, and you have to stay up to date on the best practices for SEO Keyword Research and content strategies. To get started with research start with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://adwords.google.com/KeywordPlanner&quot;&gt;AdWord’s Keyword Planner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; while it will give you traffic only ranges which are: 1-100, 100-1k, 1k-10k, 10k-100k, 100k-1M. This gives you an ok idea of what might be worth targeting, but make sure you look at the competition to see if there is any possibility for you to rank in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have a better chance of ranking and reaching your target audience, we use &lt;strong&gt;Long-Tail Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;. A long-tail keyword are more target because they are aiming to answer more specific questions. To start SEO Long-tail Keyword Research we look at the search funnel meaning we see what the &lt;strong&gt;scope of the search results&lt;/strong&gt; ie. Local, State, National. The best tool that I have come across for long-tail keyword research is &lt;a href=&quot;http://keywordtool.io/&quot;&gt;Keyword Tool&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keywordspy.com/&quot;&gt;Keyword Spy&lt;/a&gt;, but there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.woorank.com/en/blog/free-keyword-research-tools&quot;&gt;several options&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;links-1st-or-2nd-most-important-ranking-factor&quot;&gt;Links (1st or 2nd most important ranking factor)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;outbound-links&quot;&gt;Outbound Links&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outbound Links can help you rank better because they work like citations, but make sure you &lt;strong&gt;only have 1-3 outbound links&lt;/strong&gt; because it can seem like a spam quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;inbound-links&quot;&gt;Inbound Links&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inbound Links are the most important&lt;/strong&gt; because they are viewed as a measure of how trustworthy and popular your website is. It also helps with determining what type of website you are and for &lt;strong&gt;Local SEO your location&lt;/strong&gt;. The key is to get likes to point to your website and there are a number of to achieve this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;link-building-techniques&quot;&gt;5 Link Building Techniques&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Micro-sites
    - They are fun and great ways to attract links some time they will even link back to your main site. Even for the ones that don’t it will give you at least one moderate to high quality link in a relatively short time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RSS Feed
    - If you have a blog or press releases, then a blog is a great way to get links. Make sure you burn it at Feedburner.com. For linking build it’s simple sites will scrape your content (stealing). When they do make sure you get a back link by including links in the content back to your site.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social media
    - Both Reddit and LinkedIn give back links. With Reddit they will give a backlink to any link that has 5 upvotes, and LinkedIn will do the same based off an unknown number of leaks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy Existing/Abandoned/Expiring Domains
    - Older domains still have authority and can be a quick way to create a few link assets in a short time. by going to archive.org and repopulating it with some of the old content that got the most links. Also buying an existing website is more expensive, but it also has the most current value.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organizations
    - There are a number of organizations that will give quality back links, and while most of them will cost you some money. So the examples are your local Chamber of Commerce and Local Civics Leagues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;content-1st-or-2nd-most-important-ranking-factor&quot;&gt;Content (1st or 2nd most important ranking factor)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often you will here Content is King for SEO, and that is true to a point. The key to good content is that it &lt;strong&gt;answers the users question&lt;/strong&gt;, and can be done through telling a story or by presenting a report. Make sure you use your keywords and &lt;strong&gt;Local SEO will want to have the location used as often and naturally as possible&lt;/strong&gt; The thing to remember is that there are 2 key parts to content for SEO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;quality&quot;&gt;Quality&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;major question&lt;/strong&gt; you should ask your self when you are writing content is there real value, something that is useful, that is unique, and of substance to visitors. The other things that you should consider are: make sure it is optimized  and is your content linkable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of ways you can &lt;strong&gt;build link-worthiness&lt;/strong&gt; into content planning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;original research/data;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;expert opinions/quotes;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;collaboration; and&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;unique imagery/video.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;strong&gt;optimizing your content&lt;/strong&gt; there are some basic rules that you should obey:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Include your keywords where they feel natural never stuff keywords because there is no optimal key word destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep your post above 250 words and ideally at least 350 because if you don’t have that much then you probably don’t have a page. Consider combining pages because content under 250 can cause significant issues.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Also make sure that you use the word associated with your keywords. If you have a page on “A complete history of Maryland” then Google would expect you to write about Annapolis and Baltimore.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;freshness&quot;&gt;Freshness&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fresh content is often preferred by google and and can be done by publishing new content or up dating old content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Freshness score will initially be based off of its &lt;strong&gt;inception date, which decays or time&lt;/strong&gt;. This means initially content might rank high, but over time it will decrease. An example of this breaking news or events that are ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The amount you &lt;strong&gt;up date your content&lt;/strong&gt; can also influence freshness. When you do update your make sure it is a major update because Google may choose to ignore small changes, and care the most about core content. Less important content includes:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Comments&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Advertisements&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Navigation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Boilerplate material&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Date/time tags&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Best Practices&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Create new content regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;When updating, focus on core content, and not unimportant boilerplate material.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that small changes may be ignored. If you’re going to update a link, you may consider updating all the text around the link.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Steady link growth is almost always better than spiky, inconsistent link growth.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;All other things being equal, links from fresher pages likely pass more value than links from stale pages.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Engagement metrics are your friend. Work to increase clicks and user satisfaction.
  If you change the topic of a page too much, older links to the page may lose value.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updating older content can work amazingly well when you earn fresh links to the content, and updates authoritative content. And the goal shouldn’t be to update your site for the sake of updating isn’t going give the results. A good rule of thumb is that you should only update content if you do it in a timely manner that benefits users, with an aim to increase user engagement and help get fresh links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Technical SEO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Technical SEO isn’t a main ranking fact it will help with metrics such as bounce back and load time. The best time to implement these is before the launch of the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;page-speed&quot;&gt;Page Speed&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While page speed isn’t a ranking factor, it has a large effect on usability. The best example is the often talked about &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.gigaspaces.com/amazon-found-every-100ms-of-latency-cost-them-1-in-sales/&quot;&gt;Amazon Study where they found out that for every 100ms they lost 1%&lt;/a&gt;, put into simple term no user will wait 3 seconds or more and user won’t much longer for mobile sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Images add the most to file size and will often be the most important thing that you will have to change to optimize speed. The &lt;strong&gt;easiest way&lt;/strong&gt; to do this is by trying to reduce the file size as much as possible without reducing quality. The &lt;strong&gt;best way&lt;/strong&gt; to optimizing images is to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;srcset&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Content Delivery Network (CDN) is another way to speed up your sites load time. The way CDN works is to minimize the distance between the visitors and your website’s server, a CDN store a cached version of its content in multiple geographical locations (a.k.a., points of presence, or PoPs). Each PoP contains a number of caching servers responsible for content delivery to visitors within its proximity. &lt;strong&gt;Word of Warning&lt;/strong&gt; CDN take more effort and attention if you use a Content Management Systems because of Caching&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;on-page-factors&quot;&gt;On-Page Factors&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you search “on-page SEO” into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=on+page+seo&amp;amp;oq=on+&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.0.69i59j69i60l5.1214j0j4&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8#q=on+page+seo&amp;amp;start=0&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, Moz will tell you—through a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.searchenginejournal.com/7-ways-to-improve-your-chances-for-featured-snippets/166128/&quot;&gt;featured snippet—it&lt;/a&gt; is “the practice of optimizing individual web pages to rank higher and earn more relevant traffic in search engines. On-page refers to both the content and HTML source code of a page that can be optimized, as opposed to off-page SEO which refers to links and other external signals.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Title Tags&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Title Tags are the most seen on page element because it will show up in the SERP as the blue link, in the tab of the web browser, and is a place for keyword placement. The most common layout is **page title&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;brand** with a  character limit of 70 characters before showing ellipses.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meta Descriptions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are one of the most important on page factor, but not for SEO. The reason why it is so important is because goo copy can help reduce you bounce back rate because they know what to expect when they click through. For desktop, users will see up to 200 characters, while on mobile they’ll be shown up to 172 characters. To appeal to users on both devices, keep your description between 165 and 175 characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/google-search-meta-tittle-tag.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image with meta and tittle tag highlighted&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading Tags&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your landing page or blog should include multiple heading tags, from the h1 down to a potential h6. The most important is the h1. You should never have more than one h1 tag on any page. Include multiple h2’s or h3’s as users scroll down the page. These are used as subheadings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the headings to represent the different sections of the page. You’ll notice the impact from both an SEO standpoint and a usability standpoint&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;schema&quot;&gt;Schema&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schema  Defined by Schema.org:  Schema.org is a collaborative, community activity with a mission to create, maintain, and promote schemas for structured data on the Internet, on web pages, in email messages, and beyond.
Schema.org vocabulary can be used with many different encodings, including RDFa, Microdata and JSON-LD. These vocabularies cover entities, relationships between entities and actions, and can easily be extended through a well-documented extension model. Over 10 million sites use Schema.org to markup their web pages and email messages. Many applications from Google, Microsoft, Pinterest, Yandex and others already use these vocabularies to power rich, extensible experiences. Schema.org is sponsored by Google, Microsoft, Yahoo and Yandex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means is Schema allows the 4 major search engines to better understand what content you have on your web site and in some case will show items (ranting and snippets) in the SERP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Local Search&lt;/strong&gt; you will need Schema to add NAP, hours, and rating so that they can show up in the SERP. Keep in mind the order of NAP doesn’t matter as long as it is the same throughout the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;mobile-friendliness&quot;&gt;Mobile Friendliness&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2016/11/mobile-first-indexing.html&quot;&gt;Google is moving to Mobile First Indexing&lt;/a&gt; this means that your website should follow a mobile first approach. &lt;strong&gt;The key items&lt;/strong&gt; that you should be focusing on:
- Make sure that the website is fat finger Friendly
  - This means that you should be able to clearly use navigation elements and avoid missing clicks.
- Make sure your content (images, videos, and tables)
  - There are a number of ways to do this for each item. For images make sure that you use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;srcset&lt;/code&gt; and for video sure that the screen and navigation both resize:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are a number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/30-amazing-jquery-tables/&quot;&gt;jQuery libraries&lt;/a&gt; that will take care of it for you&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;data-hint&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; in CSS and HTML method&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEO is a major pillar of your digital foot print&lt;/strong&gt; and take time to produce strong results, but will have a longer lasting effect unlike PPC campaigns when they’re done the benefits go with them. That’s why at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt; make sure we are using the best tactics at the beginning of our development so our customers don’t lose any ground.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;seen first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/SEO-Basics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/SEO-Basics/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Check List for Yard Signs</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How many yard signs will be necessary to blanket your district?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will you use large wooden signs, small signs, a combination of both?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you do choose to use smaller signs look at using cardboard they are a little more expensive but are the easiest to put together.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Will you put up signs in the primary (whether or not you have a primary opponent)?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When will you put up your signs during the primary and general election?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is a trickier question than one might at first think.  4x4 wooden signs driven into the ground by metal stakes should probably go up as early as possible in the campaign which is about 45 days out. However, the smaller paper signs are not durable enough usually to last 45 days of weather and in addition, they get stolen by kids and opponents more frequently depending on where you live.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What information is absolutely necessary to put on your yard sign?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too often, candidates try to put too much information on their yard signs. Generally, people only look at yard signs for a split second as they are driving and don’t have time to see much more than the name. Unfortunately, I have known many starting candidates who believed that the yard sign was the appropriate place to educate voters as to first name, middle initial, last name, nickname, office being sought. District number, party affiliation and who knows what else. The key is to have your last name as big as possible, use upper and lower case letters and keep other information to a minimum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How are you going to develop your yard sign lists?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This can be done in several ways. First, contact all your friends and relatives that live in your district or near your district on main roads. Second, check with other candidates in the area for their yard sign lists. Third, distribute volunteer cards at all your events, and Republican events to gain yard sign locations. Fourth, do a mailing with a volunteer card, to all Republicans that voted in the ‘90 election, or the last school board election.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;seen first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/yard-sign-list/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/yard-sign-list/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List of htaccess Snippets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.htaccess&lt;/code&gt; files are for people that do not have rights to edit the main server configuration file. They are intrinsically slower and more complicated than using the main config. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://httpd.apache.org/docs/current/howto/htaccess.html&quot;&gt;how to in the httpd documentation&lt;/a&gt; for further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: While dropping the snippet into an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.htaccess&lt;/code&gt; file is most of the time sufficient, there are cases when certain modifications might be required. Use at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT&lt;/strong&gt;: Apache 2.4 introduces a few breaking changes, most notably in access control configuration. For more information, check the &lt;a href=&quot;https://httpd.apache.org/docs/2.4/upgrading.html&quot;&gt;upgrading document&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phanan/htaccess/issues/2&quot;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we are doing here is mostly collecting useful snippets from all over the interwebs (for example, a good chunk is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/h5bp/server-configs-apache&quot;&gt;Apache Server Configs&lt;/a&gt;) into one place. While we’ve been trying to credit where due, things might be missing. If you believe anything here is your work and credits should be given, let us know, or just send a PR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#rewrite-and-redirection&quot;&gt;Rewrite and Redirection&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#force-www&quot;&gt;Force www&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#force-www-in-a-generic-way&quot;&gt;Force www in a Generic Way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#force-non-www&quot;&gt;Force non-www&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#force-non-www-in-a-generic-way&quot;&gt;Force non-www in a Generic Way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#force-https&quot;&gt;Force HTTPS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#force-https-behind-a-proxy&quot;&gt;Force HTTPS Behind a Proxy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#force-trailing-slash&quot;&gt;Force Trailing Slash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#remove-trailing-slash&quot;&gt;Remove Trailing Slash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#redirect-a-single-page&quot;&gt;Redirect a Single Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#redirect-using-redirectmatch&quot;&gt;Redirect Using RedirectMatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#alias-a-single-directory&quot;&gt;Alias a Single Directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#alias-paths-to-script&quot;&gt;Alias Paths to Script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#redirect-an-entire-site&quot;&gt;Redirect an Entire Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#alias-clean-urls&quot;&gt;Alias “Clean” URLs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#deny-all-access&quot;&gt;Deny All Access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#deny-all-access-except-yours&quot;&gt;Deny All Access Except Yours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#allow-all-access-except-spammers&quot;&gt;Allow All Access Except Spammers’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#deny-access-to-hidden-files-and-directories&quot;&gt;Deny Access to Hidden Files and Directories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#deny-access-to-backup-and-source-files&quot;&gt;Deny Access to Backup and Source Files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#disable-directory-browsing&quot;&gt;Disable Directory Browsing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#disable-image-hotlinking&quot;&gt;Disable Image Hotlinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#disable-image-hotlinking-for-specific-domains&quot;&gt;Disable Image Hotlinking for Specific Domains&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#password-protect-a-directory&quot;&gt;Password Protect a Directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#password-protect-a-file-or-several-files&quot;&gt;Password Protect a File or Several Files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#block-visitors-by-referrer&quot;&gt;Block Visitors by Referrer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#prevent-framing-the-site&quot;&gt;Prevent Framing the Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#performance&quot;&gt;Performance&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#compress-text-files&quot;&gt;Compress Text Files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#set-expires-headers&quot;&gt;Set Expires Headers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#turn-etags-off&quot;&gt;Turn eTags Off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#miscellaneous&quot;&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#set-php-variables&quot;&gt;Set PHP Variables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#custom-error-pages&quot;&gt;Custom Error Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#force-downloading&quot;&gt;Force Downloading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#prevent-downloading&quot;&gt;Prevent Downloading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#allow-cross-domain-fonts&quot;&gt;Allow Cross-Domain Fonts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#auto-utf-8-encode&quot;&gt;Auto UTF-8 Encode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#switch-to-another-php-version&quot;&gt;Switch to Another PHP Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#disable-internet-explorer-compatibility-view&quot;&gt;Disable Internet Explorer Compatibility View&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#serve-webp-images&quot;&gt;Serve WebP Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rewrite-and-redirection&quot;&gt;Rewrite and Redirection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: It is assumed that you have &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mod_rewrite&lt;/code&gt; installed and enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;force-www&quot;&gt;Force www&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;RewriteEngine on
RewriteCond %{HTTP_HOST} ^example\.com [NC]
RewriteRule ^(.*)$ http://www.example.com/$1 [L,R=301,NC]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;force-www-in-a-generic-way&quot;&gt;Force www in a Generic Way&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;RewriteCond %{HTTP_HOST} !^$
RewriteCond %{HTTP_HOST} !^www\. [NC]
RewriteCond %{HTTPS}s ^on(s)|
RewriteRule ^ http%1://www.%{HTTP_HOST}%{REQUEST_URI} [R=301,L]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works for &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; domain. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/4916222/htaccess-how-to-force-www-in-a-generic-way&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;force-non-www&quot;&gt;Force non-www&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/domain-www-or-no-www/&quot;&gt;still&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/apex-domains&quot;&gt;open&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://yes-www.org/&quot;&gt;for&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://no-www.org/&quot;&gt;debate&lt;/a&gt; whether www or non-www is the way to go, so if you happen to be a fan of bare domains, here you go:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apacheconf
RewriteEngine on
RewriteCond %{HTTP_HOST} ^www\.example\.com [NC]
RewriteRule ^(.*)$ http://example.com/$1 [L,R=301]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;force-non-www-in-a-generic-way&quot;&gt;Force non-www in a Generic Way&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;RewriteEngine on
RewriteCond %{HTTP_HOST} ^www\.
RewriteCond %{HTTPS}s ^on(s)|off
RewriteCond http%1://%{HTTP_HOST} ^(https?://)(www\.)?(.+)$
RewriteRule ^ %1%3%{REQUEST_URI} [R=301,L]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;force-https&quot;&gt;Force HTTPS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;RewriteEngine on
RewriteCond %{HTTPS} !on
RewriteRule (.*) https://%{HTTP_HOST}%{REQUEST_URI}

# Note: It’s also recommended to enable HTTP Strict Transport Security (HSTS)
# on your HTTPS website to help prevent man-in-the-middle attacks.
# See https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/HTTP_strict_transport_security
&amp;lt;IfModule mod_headers.c&amp;gt;
    Header always set Strict-Transport-Security &quot;max-age=31536000; includeSubDomains&quot;
&amp;lt;/IfModule&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;force-https-behind-a-proxy&quot;&gt;Force HTTPS Behind a Proxy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Useful if you have a proxy in front of your server performing TLS termination.
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apacheconf
RewriteCond %{HTTP:X-Forwarded-Proto} !https
RewriteRule (.*) https://%{HTTP_HOST}%{REQUEST_URI}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;force-trailing-slash&quot;&gt;Force Trailing Slash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;RewriteCond %{REQUEST_URI} /+[^\.]+$
RewriteRule ^(.+[^/])$ %{REQUEST_URI}/ [R=301,L]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remove-trailing-slash&quot;&gt;Remove Trailing Slash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This snippet will redirect paths ending in slashes to their non-slash-terminated counterparts (except for actual directories), e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http://www.example.com/blog/&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http://www.example.com/blog&lt;/code&gt;. This is important for SEO, since it’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://overit.com/blog/canonical-urls&quot;&gt;recommended&lt;/a&gt; to have a canonical URL for every page.
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apacheconf
RewriteCond %{REQUEST_FILENAME} !-d
RewriteCond %{REQUEST_URI} (.+)/$
RewriteRule ^ %1 [R=301,L]
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/21417263/htaccess-add-remove-trailing-slash-from-url#27264788&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;redirect-a-single-page&quot;&gt;Redirect a Single Page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;Redirect 301 /oldpage.html http://www.example.com/newpage.html
Redirect 301 /oldpage2.html http://www.example.com/folder/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://css-tricks.com/snippets/htaccess/301-redirects/&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;redirect-using-redirectmatch&quot;&gt;Redirect Using RedirectMatch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;RedirectMatch 301 /subdirectory(.*) http://www.newsite.com/newfolder/$1
RedirectMatch 301 ^/(.*).htm$ /$1.html
RedirectMatch 301 ^/200([0-9])/([^01])(.*)$ /$2$3
RedirectMatch 301 ^/category/(.*)$ /$1
RedirectMatch 301 ^/(.*)/htaccesselite-ultimate-htaccess-article.html(.*) /htaccess/htaccess.html
RedirectMatch 301 ^/(.*).html/1/(.*) /$1.html$2
RedirectMatch 301 ^/manual/(.*)$ http://www.php.net/manual/$1
RedirectMatch 301 ^/dreamweaver/(.*)$ /tools/$1
RedirectMatch 301 ^/z/(.*)$ http://static.askapache.com/$1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.askapache.com/htaccess/301-redirect-with-mod_rewrite-or-redirectmatch.html#301_Redirects_RedirectMatch&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alias-a-single-directory&quot;&gt;Alias a Single Directory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;RewriteEngine On
RewriteRule ^source-directory/(.*) /target-directory/$1 [R=301,L]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alias-paths-to-script&quot;&gt;Alias Paths To Script&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;FallbackResource /index.fcgi
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example has an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;index.fcgi&lt;/code&gt; file in some directory, and any requests within that directory that fail to resolve a filename/directory will be sent to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;index.fcgi&lt;/code&gt; script. It’s good if you want &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;baz.foo/some/cool/path&lt;/code&gt; to be handled by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;baz.foo/index.fcgi&lt;/code&gt; (which also supports requests to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;baz.foo&lt;/code&gt;) while maintaining &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;baz.foo/css/style.css&lt;/code&gt; and the like. Get access to the original path from the PATH_INFO environment variable, as exposed to your scripting environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;RewriteEngine On
RewriteRule ^$ index.fcgi/ [QSA,L]
RewriteCond %{REQUEST_FILENAME} !-f
RewriteCond %{REQUEST_FILENAME} !-d
RewriteRule ^(.*)$ index.fcgi/$1 [QSA,L]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a less efficient version of the FallbackResource directive (because using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mod_rewrite&lt;/code&gt; is more complex than just handling the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FallbackResource&lt;/code&gt; directive), but it’s also more flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;redirect-an-entire-site&quot;&gt;Redirect an Entire Site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;Redirect 301 / http://newsite.com/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way does it with links intact. That is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;www.oldsite.com/some/crazy/link.html&lt;/code&gt; will become &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;www.newsite.com/some/crazy/link.html&lt;/code&gt;. This is extremely helpful when you are just “moving” a site to a new domain. &lt;a href=&quot;http://css-tricks.com/snippets/htaccess/301-redirects/&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alias-clean-urls&quot;&gt;Alias “Clean” URLs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This snippet lets you use “clean” URLs – those without a PHP extension, e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;example.com/users&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;example.com/users.php&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apacheconf
RewriteEngine On
RewriteCond %{SCRIPT_FILENAME} !-d
RewriteRule ^([^.]+)$ $1.php [NC,L]
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abeautifulsite.net/access-pages-without-the-php-extension-using-htaccess/&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### Deny All Access
``` apacheconf
## Apache 2.2
Deny from all&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apache-24&quot;&gt;Apache 2.4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Require all denied
```&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait, this will lock you out from your content as well! Thus introducing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deny-all-access-except-yours&quot;&gt;Deny All Access Except Yours&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;## Apache 2.2
Order deny,allow
Deny from all
Allow from xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx

## Apache 2.4
# Require all denied
# Require ip xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx&lt;/code&gt; is your IP. If you replace the last three digits with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0/12&lt;/code&gt; for example, this will specify a range of IPs within the same network, thus saving you the trouble to list all allowed IPs separately. &lt;a href=&quot;http://speckyboy.com/2013/01/08/useful-htaccess-snippets-and-hacks/&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now of course there’s a reversed version:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;allow-all-access-except-spammers&quot;&gt;Allow All Access Except Spammers’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;## Apache 2.2
Order deny,allow
Deny from xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx
Deny from xxx.xxx.xxx.xxy

## Apache 2.4
# Require all granted
# Require not ip xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx
# Require not ip xxx.xxx.xxx.xxy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deny-access-to-hidden-files-and-directories&quot;&gt;Deny Access to Hidden Files and Directories&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hidden files and directories (those whose names start with a dot &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.&lt;/code&gt;) should most, if not all, of the time be secured. For example: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.htaccess&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.htpasswd&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.git&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.hg&lt;/code&gt;…
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apacheconf
RewriteCond %{SCRIPT_FILENAME} -d [OR]
RewriteCond %{SCRIPT_FILENAME} -f
RewriteRule &quot;(^|/)\.&quot; - [F]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can just raise a “Not Found” error, giving the attacker no clue:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apacheconf
RedirectMatch 404 /\..*$
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deny-access-to-backup-and-source-files&quot;&gt;Deny Access to Backup and Source Files&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These files may be left by some text/HTML editors (like Vi/Vim) and pose a great security danger if exposed to public.
``` apacheconf
&amp;lt;FilesMatch “(.(bak|config|dist|fla|inc|ini|log|psd|sh|sql|swp)|~)$”&amp;gt;
    ## Apache 2.2
    Order allow,deny
    Deny from all
    Satisfy All&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Apache 2.4
# Require all denied
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;/FilesMatch&amp;gt;
```
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/h5bp/server-configs-apache&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disable-directory-browsing&quot;&gt;Disable Directory Browsing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;Options All -Indexes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disable-image-hotlinking&quot;&gt;Disable Image Hotlinking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;RewriteEngine on
# Remove the following line if you want to block blank referrer too
RewriteCond %{HTTP_REFERER} !^$

RewriteCond %{HTTP_REFERER} !^https?://(.+\.)?example.com [NC]
RewriteRule \.(jpe?g|png|gif|bmp)$ - [NC,F,L]

# If you want to display a “blocked” banner in place of the hotlinked image,
# replace the above rule with:
# RewriteRule \.(jpe?g|png|gif|bmp) http://example.com/blocked.png [R,L]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disable-image-hotlinking-for-specific-domains&quot;&gt;Disable Image Hotlinking for Specific Domains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you want to disable image hotlinking from some bad guys only.
``` apacheconf
RewriteEngine on
RewriteCond %{HTTP_REFERER} ^https?://(.+.)?badsite.com [NC,OR]
RewriteCond %{HTTP_REFERER} ^https?://(.+.)?badsite2.com [NC,OR]
RewriteRule .(jpe?g|png|gif|bmp)$ - [NC,F,L]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;if-you-want-to-display-a-blocked-banner-in-place-of-the-hotlinked-image&quot;&gt;If you want to display a “blocked” banner in place of the hotlinked image,&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# replace the above rule with:
# RewriteRule .(jpe?g|png|gif|bmp) http://example.com/blocked.png [R,L]
```&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;password-protect-a-directory&quot;&gt;Password Protect a Directory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you need to create a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.htpasswd&lt;/code&gt; file somewhere in the system:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bash
htpasswd -c /home/fellowship/.htpasswd boromir
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you can use it for authentication:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apacheconf
AuthType Basic
AuthName &quot;One does not simply&quot;
AuthUserFile /home/fellowship/.htpasswd
Require valid-user
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;password-protect-a-file-or-several-files&quot;&gt;Password Protect a File or Several Files&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;AuthName &quot;One still does not simply&quot;
AuthType Basic
AuthUserFile /home/fellowship/.htpasswd

&amp;lt;Files &quot;one-ring.o&quot;&amp;gt;
Require valid-user
&amp;lt;/Files&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;FilesMatch ^((one|two|three)-rings?\.o)$&amp;gt;
Require valid-user
&amp;lt;/FilesMatch&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;block-visitors-by-referrer&quot;&gt;Block Visitors by Referrer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This denies access for all users who are coming from (referred by) a specific domain.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.htaccess-guide.com/deny-visitors-by-referrer/&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apacheconf
RewriteEngine on
# Options +FollowSymlinks
RewriteCond %{HTTP_REFERER} somedomain\.com [NC,OR]
RewriteCond %{HTTP_REFERER} anotherdomain\.com
RewriteRule .* - [F]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prevent-framing-the-site&quot;&gt;Prevent Framing the Site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This prevents the website to be framed (i.e. put into an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iframe&lt;/code&gt; tag), when still allows framing for a specific URI.
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apacheconf
SetEnvIf Request_URI &quot;/starry-night&quot; allow_framing=true
Header set X-Frame-Options SAMEORIGIN env=!allow_framing
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;performance&quot;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### Compress Text Files
``` apacheconf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ifmodule mod_deflate.c=&quot;&quot;&gt;

    # Force compression for mangled headers.
    # https://developer.yahoo.com/blogs/ydn/pushing-beyond-gzipping-25601.html
    &lt;ifmodule mod_setenvif.c=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ifmodule mod_headers.c=&quot;&quot;&gt;
            SetEnvIfNoCase ^(Accept-EncodXng|X-cept-Encoding|X{15}|~{15}|-{15})$ ^((gzip|deflate)\s*,?\s*)+|[X~-]{4,13}$ HAVE_Accept-Encoding
            RequestHeader append Accept-Encoding &quot;gzip,deflate&quot; env=HAVE_Accept-Encoding
        &lt;/ifmodule&gt;
    &lt;/ifmodule&gt;

    # Compress all output labeled with one of the following MIME-types
    # (for Apache versions below 2.3.7, you don&#39;t need to enable `mod_filter`
    #  and can remove the `&lt;ifmodule mod_filter.c=&quot;&quot;&gt;` and `&lt;/ifmodule&gt;` lines
    #  as `AddOutputFilterByType` is still in the core directives).
    &lt;ifmodule mod_filter.c=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        AddOutputFilterByType DEFLATE application/atom+xml \
                                      application/javascript \
                                      application/json \
                                      application/rss+xml \
                                      application/vnd.ms-fontobject \
                                      application/x-font-ttf \
                                      application/x-web-app-manifest+json \
                                      application/xhtml+xml \
                                      application/xml \
                                      font/opentype \
                                      image/svg+xml \
                                      image/x-icon \
                                      text/css \
                                      text/html \
                                      text/plain \
                                      text/x-component \
                                      text/xml
    &lt;/ifmodule&gt;

&lt;/ifmodule&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[Source](https://github.com/h5bp/server-configs-apache)


### Set Expires Headers
_Expires headers_ tell the browser whether they should request a specific file from the server or just grab it from the cache. It is advisable to set static content&#39;s expires headers to something far in the future.

If you don’t control versioning with filename-based cache busting, consider lowering the cache time for resources like CSS and JS to something like 1 week. [Source](https://github.com/h5bp/server-configs-apache)
``` apacheconf
&amp;lt;IfModule mod_expires.c&amp;gt;
    ExpiresActive on
    ExpiresDefault                                      &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;

  # CSS
    ExpiresByType text/css                              &quot;access plus 1 year&quot;

  # Data interchange
    ExpiresByType application/json                      &quot;access plus 0 seconds&quot;
    ExpiresByType application/xml                       &quot;access plus 0 seconds&quot;
    ExpiresByType text/xml                              &quot;access plus 0 seconds&quot;

  # Favicon (cannot be renamed!)
    ExpiresByType image/x-icon                          &quot;access plus 1 week&quot;

  # HTML components (HTCs)
    ExpiresByType text/x-component                      &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;

  # HTML
    ExpiresByType text/html                             &quot;access plus 0 seconds&quot;

  # JavaScript
    ExpiresByType application/javascript                &quot;access plus 1 year&quot;

  # Manifest files
    ExpiresByType application/x-web-app-manifest+json   &quot;access plus 0 seconds&quot;
    ExpiresByType text/cache-manifest                   &quot;access plus 0 seconds&quot;

  # Media
    ExpiresByType audio/ogg                             &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
    ExpiresByType image/gif                             &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
    ExpiresByType image/jpeg                            &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
    ExpiresByType image/png                             &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
    ExpiresByType video/mp4                             &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
    ExpiresByType video/ogg                             &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
    ExpiresByType video/webm                            &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;

  # Web feeds
    ExpiresByType application/atom+xml                  &quot;access plus 1 hour&quot;
    ExpiresByType application/rss+xml                   &quot;access plus 1 hour&quot;

  # Web fonts
    ExpiresByType application/font-woff2                &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
    ExpiresByType application/font-woff                 &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
    ExpiresByType application/vnd.ms-fontobject         &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
    ExpiresByType application/x-font-ttf                &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
    ExpiresByType font/opentype                         &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
    ExpiresByType image/svg+xml                         &quot;access plus 1 month&quot;
&amp;lt;/IfModule&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;turn-etags-off&quot;&gt;Turn eTags Off&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By removing the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ETag&lt;/code&gt; header, you disable caches and browsers from being able to validate files, so they are forced to rely on your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Cache-Control&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Expires&lt;/code&gt; header. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.askapache.com/htaccess/apache-speed-etags.html&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;
``` apacheconf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ifmodule mod_headers.c=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    Header unset ETag
&lt;/ifmodule&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FileETag None
```&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;miscellaneous&quot;&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;set-php-variables&quot;&gt;Set PHP Variables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;php_value &amp;lt;key&amp;gt; &amp;lt;val&amp;gt;

# For example:
php_value upload_max_filesize 50M
php_value max_execution_time 240
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;custom-error-pages&quot;&gt;Custom Error Pages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;ErrorDocument 500 &quot;Houston, we have a problem.&quot;
ErrorDocument 401 http://error.example.com/mordor.html
ErrorDocument 404 /errors/halflife3.html
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;force-downloading&quot;&gt;Force Downloading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you want to force the browser to download some content instead of displaying it.
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apacheconf
&amp;lt;Files *.md&amp;gt;
    ForceType application/octet-stream
    Header set Content-Disposition attachment
&amp;lt;/Files&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there is a yang to this yin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prevent-downloading&quot;&gt;Prevent Downloading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you want to force the browser to display some content instead of downloading it.
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apacheconf
&amp;lt;FilesMatch &quot;\.(tex|log|aux)$&quot;&amp;gt;
    Header set Content-Type text/plain
&amp;lt;/FilesMatch&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;allow-cross-domain-fonts&quot;&gt;Allow Cross-Domain Fonts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CDN-served webfonts might not work in Firefox or IE due to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-origin_resource_sharing&quot;&gt;CORS&lt;/a&gt;. This snippet solves the problem.
``` apacheconf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ifmodule mod_headers.c=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &amp;lt;FilesMatch &quot;\.(eot|otf|ttc|ttf|woff|woff2)$&quot;&amp;gt;
        Header set Access-Control-Allow-Origin &quot;*&quot;
    
&lt;/ifmodule&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[Source](https://github.com/h5bp/server-configs-apache/issues/32)

### Auto UTF-8 Encode
Your text content should always be UTF-8 encoded, no?
``` apacheconf
# Use UTF-8 encoding for anything served text/plain or text/html
AddDefaultCharset utf-8

# Force UTF-8 for a number of file formats
AddCharset utf-8 .atom .css .js .json .rss .vtt .xml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/h5bp/server-configs-apache&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;switch-to-another-php-version&quot;&gt;Switch to Another PHP Version&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re on a shared host, chances are there are more than one version of PHP installed, and sometimes you want a specific version for your website. The following snippet should switch the PHP version for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;AddHandler application/x-httpd-php56 .php

# Alternatively, you can use AddType
AddType application/x-httpd-php56 .php
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disable-internet-explorer-compatibility-view&quot;&gt;Disable Internet Explorer Compatibility View&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compatibility View in IE may affect how some websites are displayed. The following snippet should force IE to use the Edge Rendering Engine and disable the Compatibility View.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;IfModule mod_headers.c&amp;gt;
    BrowserMatch MSIE is-msie
    Header set X-UA-Compatible IE=edge env=is-msie
&amp;lt;/IfModule&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;serve-webp-images&quot;&gt;Serve WebP Images&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/speed/webp/?csw=1&quot;&gt;WebP images&lt;/a&gt; are supported and an image with a .webp extension and the same name is found at the same place as the jpg/png image that is going to be served, then the WebP image is served instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apacheconf&quot;&gt;RewriteEngine On
RewriteCond %{HTTP_ACCEPT} image/webp
RewriteCond %{DOCUMENT_ROOT}/$1.webp -f
RewriteRule (.+)\.(jpe?g|png)$ $1.webp [T=image/webp,E=accept:1]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vincentorback/WebP-images-with-htaccess&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;seen first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/htaccess-snippets/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/htaccess-snippets/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Writing your Campaign Plan and Determining the Strategy</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-the-campaign-plan&quot;&gt;WRITING THE CAMPAIGN PLAN&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most difficult challenges for first time campaign manager was writing the campaign plan and trying to envision the big picture for what has to happen in a campaign. A campaign plan is critical because it helps you to formulate a strategy, decide where you will need, key people, create a timeline and, perhaps, most importantly, create a budget so you don’t spend your money too soon. One other benefit is that you are more likely to gain a contribution from a large giver if you sit down with them and give them a campaign plan that is well thought out. As an underdog, my campaign plan helped me raise about $6,000 from large givers and political action committees by showing them that I was a legitimate candidate.
One thing -that may help you in creating a campaign plan is to look at it as a series of questions. To help toward this end, I have written some questions and comments on the following pages. Even if you have already written a campaign plan, read through the questions and see if you are adequately prepared to tackle your upcoming campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;district-background&quot;&gt;DISTRICT BACKGROUND&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the voter registration numbers for your district?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How many Democrats, Republicans and independents vote in a Presidential election?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is the past voting history of your district?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t be able to get a voting history for legislative races very accurately since redistricting most probably means that your current district probably was part of two or more previous districts. However, you should know how high profile races (Presidential, U.S. Senator, Governor) and low profile races (State Treasurer, State Auditor) have done in your district&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the age demographics in your district?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing how many people are registered to vote in certain age categories will help you a great deal with strategy and issues. How many registered voters are 18-24 (environment, tuition), 25-44 (education, family issues, crime, tax increases) 45-55 (Property taxes. College tuition, retirement issues, welfare abuse), 60 + (Property taxes, property taxes property taxes and traditional values).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the social demographics of the respective precincts in your district?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should try and classify each precinct as a certain type of person. This can be a difficult thing to do with some precincts’, but is relatively easy with most. This, too, is very important for issue and strategy development. Think among some of these categories: rural/agricultural (property taxes, farm Issues), blue collar/working families (crime, property taxes, welfare abuse, little more pro-life, job creation), country club/business (income taxes, property taxes, economic development, little more pro-choice, education) middle class/ young families (education, crime, some environment and taxes), small town (health of small towns and its institutions, education, school consolidation)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opponent-background&quot;&gt;OPPONENT BACKGROUND&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is the background of your opponent (education, jobs, place of birth, places lived) ?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If incumbent, what are the committees served on?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If incumbent, what are the key votes cast?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The local group, how do they feel about the votes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the stands of your opponent on key issues?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is different than key votes since we don’t have clear votes on most of the key issues&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If incumbent, how high is the absentee rate for voting?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If incumbent, do they have a home in the District, or a home outside of it?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-background&quot;&gt;YOUR BACKGROUND&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are your political and personal strengths in light of the district and the upcoming election race?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a very good idea to list these and to know them so you can emphasize them throughout your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are your political and personal weaknesses in light of the district and the upcoming election race?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is sometimes an uncomfortable thing to do, but it is important to be honest with yourself and your close advisors. I guarantee that people will probably find out your weakness anyway from your opponent. If you deal with it early, you can prepare for any attacks, or if necessary, cast a favorable light on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is your background (include political campaigns, education, jobs, awards won, other recognition, memberships, etc)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;name-identification&quot;&gt;NAME IDENTIFICATION&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is your plan to raise name identification?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What mediums will you use to establish your name identification?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some mediums may be social media, paid digital, billboards, newspaper ads, radio ads, literature, etc*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;earned-media&quot;&gt;EARNED MEDIA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### (PRESS RELEASES, ETC.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the addresses, phone numbers, email and news contacts at your local newspaper, radio stations and television stations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What will you use each social media platform for&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How is a proper press release written?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The state party should be able to send you information on how to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the deadlines for your newspapers radio stations and television stations?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When is a press release adequate and when is a press conference necessary?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doorknocking&quot;&gt;DOORKNOCKING&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many households are there in your district?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I generally figure this by taking the number of registered voters (15,000) and
multiply it by .67 to get the number of actual doors that will have to be knocked to hit the home of each registered voter. Example: 15,000 x .67 = 10,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many doors can you knock in an hour?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This varies widely. Depending on what yon say to people, whether you survey them, etc. will impact how many doors you can hit in an hour. In addition, the time of day also has a major impact because if people aren’t hone, you can hit a great many more homes. This isn’t necessarily effective, but it will increase the number of homes you hit. You can generally figure around 15 to 25 homes per hour. If you hit less than 15, then you may be spending too much time with each household, if you are hitting more than 30 or 40, then you may not be knocking when enough people are home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How many hours a week can you realistically spend knocking on doors?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How many weeks is it going to take to knock on all the doors in your district?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure this by dividing the number of households in your district by the product of the number of doors knocked in an hour multiplied by the number of hours you can knock in a week. Example: 10,000 households divided by (20 homes/hr. x 12 hrs/week) - 42 weeks to knock every registered household in the district. Now, if you don’t have 42 weeks, then you will have to increase the number of homes per hour, the number of hours per week or both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are you going to do with each household that you knock so that they will remember you after you leave?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doorknocking is the most important aspect of campaigning, but it helps most if they remember what your name is after you’ve left. Frequently people don’t. Literature is fine to leave at each household, but it is generally thrown away within 24 hours of your visit. One very effective way to extend your name identification is to follow up your visit with a email/postcard thanking them for the visit. This requires keeping close track of the names you actually visit and constantly updating your voter walking list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you intend to use a registered voter-walking list -and-knock on only those homes with registered voters or forego a list and hit every home registering those people who are not currently registered?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the voter answers the door, do you plan to simply give your literature with a quick spiel about yourself or your issues, or do you plan to administer a survey when they answer the door?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What order are you going to door knock your district?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you should doorknock your precincts in a systematic, planned way meant to maximize voter impact. These decisions should be made through the use of voter information that can be provided to you. by the State Party or you can simply rank your precincts yourself through a prioritization system. If you would like to see the system that I used, please feel free to call me or write me. Generally, I believe that you should knock your most important precincts between September 15th and October 31st.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;important-dates&quot;&gt;IMPORTANT DATES&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you need to petition on. When are petitions available to get signatures for your candidacy?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When are signature petitions due for your candidacy?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When do you need to file a formation of candidacy form with the Campaign finance disclosure commission?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When are the primary and general elections?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When can yard signs go up for the primary and general?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When do yard signs have to be down after the primary and general?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When is your precinct caucus, county convention, district convention and the Republican State convention?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When are the parades and fairs in or near your district?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;campaign-organization&quot;&gt;CAMPAIGN ORGANIZATION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you plan to recruit volunteers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying starting an Internship program at your local college and high school, and try to reach out to both political an civil group to speak at a meeting
2.	What areas of the campaign do you need specific volunteers to fill?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should consider having people help with these positions: overall coordinator or manager, fundraising, Get-out-The-Vote, events coordinator, yard signs, mailing coordinator, absentee ballot coordinator, media (press release, conference) coordinator, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What type of people do you need at the top of your campaign as chairs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should try to find people who appeal to different constituencies, in my campaign, I have a leader from the only small town in the district, a leading ag person and a well respected elected official known county wide. For my fundraising chairs, I have the best known doctor in -the county and a leading lawyer who represents any big business clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will you have one person organize each precinct?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;campaign-budget&quot;&gt;CAMPAIGN BUDGET&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a budget that used all basic elements of a campaign&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description– Number        Cost:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct Mail Campaign- 6  $44,100&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campaign Palm Cards- 30,000  $3,200&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4x8 &amp;amp; 4x4 Signs-     100  $2,360&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T-Posts————-      300  $1,300&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yard Signs———-      600  $1,800&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campaign Banner—–     1  $100&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOTV Robocalls——     N/A  $2,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phone Banking——-    N/A  $500&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook Ads——–        $2,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital Ads (Google, etc.)      $2,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Website————        $150&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MailChimp———-        $300&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event Expenses—–       $3,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campaign Manager—       $14,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canvassing Software-       $5,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dues/Sponsorships -      $2,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOTAL&lt;/strong&gt; :         &lt;strong&gt;$83,810&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-out-the-vote-program-gotv&quot;&gt;GET OUT THE VOTE PROGRAM (GOTV)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who do intend to turn out on election day to vote for  you.?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my opinion that too many legislative campaigns turn out voters that are already intending to vote.  Let me explain.  We know that certain voters vote in every election.  Come rain or shine, they never miss.  So why   use your phone bank or postcard to remind these people to vote?  Clearly, these regular voters need a contact before the election explaining why they should support you and not a GOTV contact.  Take this for what it’s worth, but I would only concentrate on turning out those Republican voters, or identified supporters among independents, that have a history of missing elections. All states keeps records of who votes in what elections so it is easy to determine which voters are regular voters and which need a little reminder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What methods do you intend to use to turnout your target groups?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider using a first-class postcard, mailed on Saturday so that it arrives Monday. Also see that you have turnout phoning organized for Monday night before the election and that the local party has phone banks for election day. Another idea that we have used in Galveston is to rise early on election day and place a large “VOTE TODAY” sign on every 4x4 yard sign before people leave for work. Other mediums such as digital, radio, newspaper or T.V. work fine for part of your GOTV program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technology&quot;&gt;TECHNOLOGY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You will need to set up a Website and will have to deiced between a static or CMS&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you intent to use excel or a more advance system, and is the system going to be all in one or pieced together.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are working with less then 75,000-voter universe you can get away with using excel and programs like MailChimp. If you are trying to manage a bigger universe then you will need a more advance system like i360, rVote, and NationBuilder. While they all do similar things i360 and rVote are more targeted to just doing canvassing and voter modeling because it doesn’t have any digital tools, while Nationbuilder is more about managing a digital presence, due to being able to host a website and digital media tools, and can be expanded to do canvassing but no modeling. I prefer to use one that can do more voter out-reach and modeling because of the ease of finding consultants to do a better job at the other tasks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;media-mix&quot;&gt;MEDIA MIX&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Should you spend your money on digital, radio, T.V., direct mail, door-to-door, newspaper ads, etc.?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that candidates should use a mix of audio and visual mediums to establish name identification and to penetrate with a message. This is because some people have better memory recall from audio than visual and vice-versa. Visual would include: digital, direct mail, literature, newspaper ads, yard signs, billboards and television. Audio would include radio, television, speeches, phone banking and door-to-door.
I personally believe (and this view isn’t shared by everyone) that too many Legislative candidates concentrate on visual education and ignore audio education. Behavioral learning abilities dictate that they both be used if you actually want to penetrate to the voter.
The combination that you use depends on the mediums in your district, while digital will work in both rural and urban districts. Radio, newspaper and direct mail will probably be the best choices in a rural district. In an urban district cable television, local television news commercials, and local newspapers can also be added to the list to be bought for radio or television to penetrate,.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When will you run your ads, mail your literature and start you digital ad buys?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly you will want to be out with your name on yard signs and parades, etc., as early and as often as you can, however, when should you spend your money on paid mediums? Well consider some polling research?  Non party line voters can’t begin making up their minds who they are going to vote for until about ten to fourteen days out from the election. Breaking this out in age groups, many senior citizens make their mind up seven to ten days out while 18-24 year olds decide the day before the election or at the polls. All other are somewhere in between.
Therefore, if you are mailing your “lower the property tax” message to seniors, start about two weeks out, while you may want to save your pro-environment mailings to 18-24 year olds until three to five days out.
No matter what else, you will want to spend the great preponderance of your money when people are making up their minds, and that is close to the election. Think of it as holding your fire until you see the whites of their eyes. If you fire too early you’re wasting your ammunition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you, intend to design your media and your literature?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This takes a special talent to create great literature, or commercials, but let me make a couple of suggestions that might help you. First, collect examples from other successful candidates and try to emulate those.  Second, Don’t overburden your reader with too much information in literature or commercials.  Keep it simple and repeat your main point over and over.  Third, make sure you have your name in the literature or commercial repeatedly.  Fourth, use visuals and pictures liberally.  Fifth, don’t be afraid to be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you plan to target your message through your media?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that it requires six contacts with a voter to penetrate with a message. That’s why you hear the suggestion to use three or four issues and keep pounding away at them. With that in mind, there are some very easy ways to target your voter with your message. Using voter information from state voter registration files, you can target in three ways: party, precinct, age.  Clearly, you can tell a lot by whether a person is a Republican, Democrat or Independent.  I also know that the people in rural precincts are concerned about different things than those in my blue collar precincts. Other targeting information that night be helpful is demographic information available from radio stations about their target markets. The same information is available with television.
Example: What if I wanted to target a message to Republicans, in precinct DV12 over the age of 60 with a message about property taxes. Well, I would do three things. First I would pull the names off of my computer of everybody in my district that fits those three criteria. I would use this list for a mailing to these people. Second, I would buy time on the local radio station whose demographics most target that group of people.  Finally, I might put an ad on the digital (cost at most $5 CPM) that best targets this group like CNN or the financial news station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In writing your campaign plan, your strategy will depend heavily on the type of race you have If you are the only Republican in a heavily Republican open district, then your race is going to be significantly different than most challengers. Please keep in mind that 95% of incumbents get re-elected. Therefore, if you are a challenger that intends to be a part of the 5%, you must 1) be aggressive, 2) door knock every door (at least once), 3) start early, 4) raise a lot of money, 5) use “voting” issues to take voters away from your opponent, and 6) take some risks. Too many challengers are afraid to take risks. Challengers are frequently so afraid of offending anyone that they run bland campaigns that don’t make a case for kicking the incumbent out of office.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;seen first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalroots.io&quot;&gt;Digital Roots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://digitalroots.io/blog/Campaign-Plan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://digitalroots.io/blog/Campaign-Plan/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
